-DOCSTART- -X- O
Ukraine -X- _ B-Location
has -X- _ O
been -X- _ O
widening -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
breach -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
Russia -X- _ B-Location
's -X- _ I-Location
defences -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
the -X- _ B-Location
southern -X- _ I-Location
Zaporizhzhia -X- _ I-Location
region -X- _ I-Location
as -X- _ O
its -X- _ O
counter-offensive -X- _ O
continues -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
make -X- _ O
slow -X- _ O
progress -X- _ O
against -X- _ O
Moscow -X- _ B-Organisation
's -X- _ I-Organisation
forces -X- _ I-Organisation
. -X- _ O

Here -X- _ O
are -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
latest -X- _ O
developments -X- _ O
: -X- _ O
Ukraine -X- _ B-Location
has -X- _ O
brought -X- _ O
heavy -X- _ O
equipment -X- _ O
beyond -X- _ O
Russia -X- _ B-Location
's -X- _ I-Location
first -X- _ O
line -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
defences -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
the -X- _ B-Location
Zaporizhzhia -X- _ I-Location
region -X- _ I-Location
for -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
first -X- _ O
time -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
analysts -X- _ O
sayIt -X- _ O
has -X- _ O
also -X- _ O
made -X- _ O
advances -X- _ O
around -X- _ O
Bakhmut -X- _ B-Location
after -X- _ O
Russia -X- _ B-Location
moved -X- _ O
some -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
its -X- _ O
most -X- _ O
experienced -X- _ O
troops -X- _ B-MilitaryPlatform
from -X- _ O
the -X- _ B-Location
city -X- _ I-Location
to -X- _ I-Location
the -X- _ I-Location
Zaporizhzhia -X- _ I-Location
region -X- _ I-Location
Meanwhile -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
Russia -X- _ B-Location
has -X- _ O
maintained -X- _ O
drone -X- _ B-MilitaryPlatform
attacks -X- _ O
on -X- _ O
Ukraine -X- _ B-Location
's -X- _ I-Location
River -X- _ I-Location
Danube -X- _ I-Location
ports -X- _ I-Location
, -X- _ O
damaging -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
country -X- _ O
's -X- _ O
grain -X- _ O
export -X- _ O
infrastructure -X- _ O
Ukraine -X- _ B-Location
's -X- _ I-Location
armoured -X- _ B-MilitaryPlatform
vehicles -X- _ I-MilitaryPlatform
advance -X- _ O
Ukrainian -X- _ B-MilitaryPlatform
forces -X- _ I-MilitaryPlatform
have -X- _ O
been -X- _ O
widening -X- _ O
their -X- _ O
breach -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
Russian -X- _ O
defensive -X- _ O
lines -X- _ O
near -X- _ O
the -X- _ B-Location
village -X- _ I-Location
of -X- _ I-Location
Robotyne -X- _ I-Location
for -X- _ O
several -X- _ O
weeks -X- _ O
and -X- _ O
analysts -X- _ O
say -X- _ O
they -X- _ O
may -X- _ O
be -X- _ O
preparing -X- _ O
for -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
new -X- _ O
push -X- _ O
. -X- _ O

The -X- _ B-Location
tiny -X- _ I-Location
village -X- _ I-Location
, -X- _ O
some -X- _ O
56km -X- _ O
( -X- _ O
35 -X- _ O
miles -X- _ O
) -X- _ O
south-east -X- _ B-Location
of -X- _ I-Location
the -X- _ I-Location
city -X- _ I-Location
of -X- _ I-Location
Zaporizhzhia -X- _ I-Location
, -X- _ O
has -X- _ O
been -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
focal -X- _ O
point -X- _ O
since -X- _ O
Ukraine -X- _ B-Location
's -X- _ I-Location
counter-offensive -X- _ O
began -X- _ O
at -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
start -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
June -X- _ B-Temporal

Progress -X- _ O
has -X- _ O
been -X- _ O
slow -X- _ O
but -X- _ O
analysts -X- _ O
at -X- _ O
the -X- _ B-Organisation
US-based -X- _ I-Organisation
Institute -X- _ I-Organisation
for -X- _ I-Organisation
the -X- _ I-Organisation
Study -X- _ I-Organisation
of -X- _ I-Organisation
War -X- _ I-Organisation
( -X- _ I-Organisation
ISW -X- _ I-Organisation
) -X- _ I-Organisation
say -X- _ O
they -X- _ O
have -X- _ O
confirmed -X- _ O
that -X- _ O
Ukrainian -X- _ B-MilitaryPlatform
forces -X- _ I-MilitaryPlatform
are -X- _ O
operating -X- _ O
armoured -X- _ B-MilitaryPlatform
vehicles -X- _ I-MilitaryPlatform
beyond -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
Russian -X- _ B-MilitaryPlatform
anti-tank -X- _ I-MilitaryPlatform
ditch -X- _ O
and -X- _ O
dragon -X- _ O
's -X- _ O
teeth -X- _ O
obstacles -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
area -X- _ O
for -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
first -X- _ O
time -X- _ O
- -X- _ O
just -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
the -X- _ B-Location
west -X- _ I-Location
of -X- _ I-Location
nearby -X- _ I-Location
Verbove. -X- _ I-Location
War -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
maps -X- _ O
: -X- _ O
Ukraine -X- _ B-Location
widening -X- _ O
Russia -X- _ B-Location
defences -X- _ O
breach -X- _ O
The -X- _ B-Organisation
ISW -X- _ I-Organisation
describes -X- _ O
this -X- _ O
as -X- _ O
an -X- _ O
" -X- _ O
important -X- _ O
sign -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
progress -X- _ O
" -X- _ O
but -X- _ O
adds -X- _ O
it -X- _ O
is -X- _ O
not -X- _ O
prepared -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
say -X- _ O
that -X- _ O
Ukraine -X- _ B-Location
has -X- _ O
broken -X- _ O
through -X- _ O
as -X- _ O
its -X- _ O
forces -X- _ B-MilitaryPlatform
have -X- _ O
not -X- _ O
breached -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
last -X- _ O
visible -X- _ O
defensive -X- _ O
positions -X- _ O

BBC -X- _ B-Organisation
security -X- _ O
correspondent -X- _ O
Frank -X- _ B-Person
Gardner -X- _ I-Person
says -X- _ O
this -X- _ O
is -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
most -X- _ O
strategically -X- _ O
important -X- _ O
part -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
Ukrainian -X- _ O
counter-offensive -X- _ O
and -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
if -X- _ O
it -X- _ O
is -X- _ O
successful -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
could -X- _ O
cut -X- _ O
off -X- _ O
Russia -X- _ B-Location
's -X- _ I-Location
supply -X- _ I-Location
lines -X- _ I-Location
that -X- _ O
connect -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
Russian -X- _ O
city -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
Rostov-on-Don -X- _ B-Location
to -X- _ O
Crimea -X- _ B-Location
. -X- _ O

Doing -X- _ O
so -X- _ O
would -X- _ O
make -X- _ O
it -X- _ O
all -X- _ O
but -X- _ O
impossible -X- _ O
for -X- _ O
Russia -X- _ B-Location
to -X- _ O
maintain -X- _ O
its -X- _ O
huge -X- _ O
garrison -X- _ B-MilitaryPlatform
in -X- _ O
Crimea -X- _ B-Location
, -X- _ O
which -X- _ O
it -X- _ O
annexed -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
2014 -X- _ B-Temporal
, -X- _ O
he -X- _ O
adds -X- _ O
. -X- _ O

Has -X- _ O
Ukraine -X- _ B-Location
broken -X- _ O
through -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
dragon -X- _ O
's -X- _ O
teeth -X- _ O
? -X- _ O
However -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
advance -X- _ O
so -X- _ O
far -X- _ O
has -X- _ O
been -X- _ O
restricted -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
area -X- _ O
around -X- _ O
Robotyne -X- _ B-Location
and -X- _ O
Ukrainian -X- _ B-MilitaryPlatform
forces -X- _ I-MilitaryPlatform
have -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
long -X- _ O
way -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
go -X- _ O
if -X- _ O
they -X- _ O
are -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
achieve -X- _ O
this -X- _ O
aim -X- _ O
by -X- _ O
reaching -X- _ O
the -X- _ B-Location
Sea -X- _ I-Location
of -X- _ I-Location
Azov -X- _ I-Location
. -X- _ O

The -X- _ O
battle -X- _ O
for -X- _ O
Bakhmut -X- _ B-Location
As -X- _ O
Ukraine -X- _ B-Location
has -X- _ O
been -X- _ O
trying -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
widen -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
breach -X- _ O
near -X- _ O
Robotyne -X- _ B-Location
, -X- _ O
Russia -X- _ B-Location
has -X- _ O
been -X- _ O
bringing -X- _ O
reinforcements -X- _ O
into -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
region -X- _ O
- -X- _ O
including -X- _ O
some -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
its -X- _ O
best -X- _ O
trained -X- _ O
soldiers -X- _ B-MilitaryPlatform
that -X- _ O
had -X- _ O
previously -X- _ O
been -X- _ O
deployed -X- _ O
elsewhere -X- _ O
. -X- _ O

The -X- _ B-Person
UK -X- _ I-Person
Ministry -X- _ I-Person
of -X- _ I-Person
Defence -X- _ I-Person
says -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
redeployments -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
Russia -X- _ B-Location
's -X- _ I-Location
paratroop -X- _ O
formations -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
known -X- _ O
as -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
VDV -X- _ B-Organisation
, -X- _ O
have -X- _ O
probably -X- _ O
weakened -X- _ O
its -X- _ O
defences -X- _ O
around -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
city -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
Bakhmut -X- _ B-Location
in -X- _ I-Location
eastern -X- _ I-Location
Ukraine -X- _ I-Location
, -X- _ O
which -X- _ O
has -X- _ O
endured -X- _ O
some -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
heaviest -X- _ O
fighting -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
war -X- _ O
. -X- _ O

It -X- _ O
has -X- _ O
been -X- _ O
under -X- _ O
Russian -X- _ O
control -X- _ O
for -X- _ O
several -X- _ O
months -X- _ O
but -X- _ O
Ukraine -X- _ B-Location
has -X- _ O
gained -X- _ O
some -X- _ O
ground -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
surrounding -X- _ O
areas -X- _ O
and -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
MoD -X- _ O
says -X- _ O
Ukraine -X- _ B-Location
has -X- _ O
now -X- _ O
secured -X- _ O
the -X- _ B-Location
villages -X- _ I-Location
of -X- _ I-Location
Klishchiivka -X- _ I-Location
and -X- _ O
Andriivka -X- _ B-Location
, -X- _ O
about -X- _ O
8km -X- _ O
( -X- _ O
five -X- _ O
miles -X- _ O
) -X- _ O
south -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
city -X- _ O

Attacks -X- _ O
on -X- _ O
Crimea -X- _ B-Location
Ukraine -X- _ B-Location
has -X- _ O
also -X- _ O
stepped -X- _ O
up -X- _ O
attacks -X- _ O
on -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
Crimean -X- _ B-Location
peninsula -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
past -X- _ O
month -X- _ O
- -X- _ O
including -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
missile -X- _ B-Weapon
attack -X- _ O
on -X- _ O
the -X- _ B-Location
port -X- _ I-Location
of -X- _ I-Location
Sevastopol -X- _ I-Location
on -X- _ O
22 -X- _ B-Temporal
September -X- _ I-Temporal
which -X- _ O
it -X- _ O
says -X- _ O
killed -X- _ O
Russian -X- _ O
34 -X- _ O
officers -X- _ O
. -X- _ O

It -X- _ O
initially -X- _ O
claimed -X- _ O
they -X- _ O
included -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
commander -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
Russia -X- _ B-Location
's -X- _ I-Location
Black -X- _ I-Location
Sea -X- _ I-Location
Fleet -X- _ I-Location
, -X- _ O
but -X- _ O
Moscow -X- _ B-Location
later -X- _ O
released -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
video -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
Viktor -X- _ B-Person
Sokolov -X- _ I-Person
, -X- _ O
which -X- _ O
it -X- _ O
said -X- _ O
was -X- _ O
filmed -X- _ O
several -X- _ O
days -X- _ O
later. -X- _ O
That -X- _ O
attack -X- _ O
came -X- _ O
just -X- _ O
over -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
week -X- _ O
after -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
major -X- _ O
attack -X- _ O
on -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
same -X- _ O
city -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
which -X- _ O
is -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
headquarters -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
fleet -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
using -X- _ O
cruise -X- _ B-Weapon
missiles -X- _ I-Weapon
supplied -X- _ O
by -X- _ O
the -X- _ B-Location
UK -X- _ I-Location
and -X- _ O
France -X- _ B-Location
that -X- _ O
is -X- _ O
thought -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
have -X- _ O
destroyed -X- _ O
a -X- _ B-MilitaryPlatform
ship -X- _ I-MilitaryPlatform
and -X- _ O
a -X- _ B-MilitaryPlatform
submarine -X- _ I-MilitaryPlatform
. -X- _ O

It -X- _ O
also -X- _ O
caused -X- _ O
significant -X- _ O
damage -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
dry -X- _ O
docks -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
which -X- _ O
are -X- _ O
vital -X- _ O
for -X- _ O
maintenance -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
entire -X- _ O
Black -X- _ B-MilitaryPlatform
Sea -X- _ I-MilitaryPlatform
fleet -X- _ I-MilitaryPlatform
. -X- _ O

The -X- _ O
next -X- _ O
day -X- _ O
Ukraine -X- _ B-Location
said -X- _ O
it -X- _ O
had -X- _ O
succeeded -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
destroying -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
sophisticated -X- _ O
Russian -X- _ O
air -X- _ B-MilitaryPlatform
defence -X- _ I-MilitaryPlatform
system -X- _ I-MilitaryPlatform
- -X- _ O
the -X- _ B-MilitaryPlatform
S-400 -X- _ I-MilitaryPlatform
- -X- _ O
on -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
peninsular. -X- _ O
Attacks -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
late -X- _ B-Temporal
August -X- _ I-Temporal
destroyed -X- _ O
another -X- _ O
S-400 -X- _ B-MilitaryPlatform
and -X- _ O
others -X- _ O
knocked -X- _ O
out -X- _ O
Russian -X- _ O
radar -X- _ B-MilitaryPlatform
positions -X- _ O
on -X- _ O
offshore -X- _ O
gas -X- _ O
platforms -X- _ O
. -X- _ O

Russia -X- _ B-Location
's -X- _ I-Location
Black -X- _ B-MilitaryPlatform
Sea -X- _ I-MilitaryPlatform
fleet -X- _ I-MilitaryPlatform
is -X- _ O
an -X- _ O
important -X- _ O
target -X- _ O
for -X- _ O
Kyiv -X- _ B-Location
- -X- _ O
it -X- _ O
is -X- _ O
seen -X- _ O
as -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
flagship -X- _ O
unit -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
Russia -X- _ B-Organisation
's -X- _ I-Organisation
navy -X- _ I-Organisation
and -X- _ O
its -X- _ O
ships -X- _ O
have -X- _ O
launched -X- _ O
missiles -X- _ B-Weapon
at -X- _ O
Ukraine -X- _ B-Location
causing -X- _ O
devastating -X- _ O
damage -X- _ O
. -X- _ O

It -X- _ O
has -X- _ O
also -X- _ O
been -X- _ O
threatening -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
block -X- _ O
the -X- _ B-Location
Black -X- _ I-Location
Sea -X- _ I-Location
shipping -X- _ I-Location
routes -X- _ I-Location
that -X- _ O
Ukraine -X- _ B-Location
has -X- _ O
been -X- _ O
using -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
export -X- _ O
grain -X- _ O
- -X- _ O
which -X- _ O
is -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
particular -X- _ O
sticking -X- _ O
point -X- _ O
for -X- _ O
Kyiv -X- _ B-Location
currently -X- _ O
. -X- _ O

Moscow -X- _ B-Location
pulled -X- _ O
out -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
internationally -X- _ O
brokered -X- _ O
Black -X- _ B-Organisation
Sea -X- _ I-Organisation
Grain -X- _ I-Organisation
Initiative -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
mid-July -X- _ O
- -X- _ O
guaranteeing -X- _ O
safe -X- _ O
passage -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
non-military -X- _ O
vessels -X- _ O
- -X- _ O
arguing -X- _ O
that -X- _ O
Russia -X- _ B-Location
's -X- _ I-Location
own -X- _ O
agricultural -X- _ O
exporters -X- _ O
were -X- _ O
being -X- _ O
disadvantaged -X- _ O
. -X- _ O

Is -X- _ O
Ukraine -X- _ B-Location
trying -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
retake -X- _ O
Crimea -X- _ B-Location
? -X- _ O
Since -X- _ O
Russia -X- _ B-Location
pulled -X- _ O
out -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
only -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
handful -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
vessels -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
have -X- _ O
been -X- _ O
able -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
sail -X- _ O
from -X- _ O
Ukraine -X- _ B-Location
's -X- _ I-Location
Black -X- _ I-Location
Sea -X- _ I-Location
ports -X- _ I-Location
such -X- _ O
as -X- _ O
Odesa -X- _ B-Location
, -X- _ O
with -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
first -X- _ O
large -X- _ O
grain -X- _ O
shipment -X- _ O
leaving -X- _ O
Chornomorsk -X- _ B-Location
, -X- _ O
just -X- _ O
south -X- _ B-Location
of -X- _ I-Location
Odesa -X- _ I-Location
, -X- _ O
this -X- _ O
week -X- _ O
and -X- _ O
reaching -X- _ O
Turkey -X- _ B-Location
on -X- _ O
Friday -X- _ B-Temporal

Drone -X- _ B-MilitaryPlatform
attacks -X- _ O
on -X- _ O
Danube -X- _ B-Location
ports -X- _ I-Location
The -X- _ B-Organisation
UK -X- _ I-Organisation
's -X- _ I-Organisation
Agriculture -X- _ I-Organisation
and -X- _ I-Organisation
Horticulture -X- _ I-Organisation
Development -X- _ I-Organisation
Board -X- _ I-Organisation
( -X- _ I-Organisation
AHDB -X- _ I-Organisation
) -X- _ I-Organisation
says -X- _ O
65 -X- _ O
% -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
Ukraine -X- _ B-Location
's -X- _ I-Location
grain -X- _ O
exports -X- _ O
are -X- _ O
now -X- _ O
going -X- _ O
from -X- _ O
the -X- _ B-Location
ports -X- _ I-Location
of -X- _ I-Location
Izmail -X- _ I-Location
and -X- _ O
Reni -X- _ B-Location
, -X- _ O
on -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
Danube. -X- _ B-Location
The -X- _ O
grain -X- _ O
is -X- _ O
then -X- _ O
transported -X- _ O
by -X- _ O
river -X- _ O
and -X- _ O
canals -X- _ O
into -X- _ O
the -X- _ B-Location
Black -X- _ I-Location
Sea -X- _ I-Location
, -X- _ O
via -X- _ O
the -X- _ B-Location
Romanian -X- _ I-Location
seaports -X- _ I-Location
of -X- _ I-Location
Sulina -X- _ I-Location
and -X- _ O
Constanta -X- _ B-Location
. -X- _ O

In -X- _ O
theory -X- _ O
it -X- _ O
is -X- _ O
safer -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
go -X- _ O
this -X- _ O
way -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
as -X- _ O
vessels -X- _ O
entering -X- _ O
the -X- _ B-Location
Black -X- _ I-Location
Sea -X- _ I-Location
from -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
mouth -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
river -X- _ O
immediately -X- _ O
enter -X- _ O
Romanian -X- _ B-Location
territorial -X- _ I-Location
waters -X- _ I-Location
. -X- _ O

But -X- _ O
Russia -X- _ B-Location
has -X- _ O
also -X- _ O
been -X- _ O
attacking -X- _ O
Ukraine -X- _ B-Location
's -X- _ I-Location
Danube -X- _ I-Location
ports -X- _ I-Location
using -X- _ O
drones. -X- _ B-MilitaryPlatform
Since -X- _ O
the -X- _ B-Location
River -X- _ I-Location
Danube -X- _ I-Location
forms -X- _ O
part -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
Ukraine -X- _ B-Location
's -X- _ I-Location
border -X- _ I-Location
with -X- _ O
Nato -X- _ B-Organisation
, -X- _ O
Russia -X- _ B-Location
's -X- _ I-Location
attacks -X- _ O
have -X- _ O
an -X- _ O
added -X- _ O
geopolitical -X- _ O
dimension -X- _ O
- -X- _ O
at -X- _ O
least -X- _ O
one -X- _ O
Russian -X- _ O
drone -X- _ B-MilitaryPlatform
has -X- _ O
been -X- _ O
filmed -X- _ O
exploding -X- _ O
across -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
river -X- _ O
from -X- _ O
Izmail -X- _ B-Location
, -X- _ O
inside -X- _ O
Romania -X- _ B-Location
. -X- _ O

Russian -X- _ O
drones -X- _ B-Weapon
threaten -X- _ O
Ukraine -X- _ B-Location
's -X- _ I-Location
economic -X- _ O
lifeline -X- _ O
More -X- _ O
than -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
year -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
fighting -X- _ O
Russia -X- _ B-Location
's -X- _ I-Location
invasion -X- _ O
began -X- _ O
with -X- _ O
dozens -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
missile -X- _ B-Weapon
strikes -X- _ O
on -X- _ O
cities -X- _ O
all -X- _ O
over -X- _ O
Ukraine -X- _ B-Location
before -X- _ O
dawn -X- _ O
on -X- _ O
24 -X- _ B-Temporal
February -X- _ I-Temporal
2022 -X- _ I-Temporal
. -X- _ O

Russian -X- _ B-MilitaryPlatform
ground -X- _ I-MilitaryPlatform
troops -X- _ I-MilitaryPlatform
moved -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
quickly -X- _ O
and -X- _ O
within -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
few -X- _ O
weeks -X- _ O
were -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
control -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
large -X- _ O
areas -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
Ukraine -X- _ B-Location
and -X- _ O
had -X- _ O
advanced -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
the -X- _ B-Location
suburbs -X- _ I-Location
of -X- _ I-Location
Kyiv -X- _ I-Location
. -X- _ O

Russian -X- _ B-Organisation
forces -X- _ I-Organisation
were -X- _ O
bombarding -X- _ O
Kharkiv -X- _ B-Location
, -X- _ O
and -X- _ O
they -X- _ O
had -X- _ O
taken -X- _ O
territory -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
east -X- _ O
and -X- _ O
south -X- _ O
as -X- _ O
far -X- _ O
as -X- _ O
Kherson -X- _ B-Location
, -X- _ O
and -X- _ O
surrounded -X- _ O
the -X- _ B-Location
port -X- _ I-Location
city -X- _ I-Location
of -X- _ I-Location
Mariupol -X- _ I-Location
. -X- _ I-Location

But -X- _ O
they -X- _ O
hit -X- _ O
very -X- _ O
strong -X- _ O
Ukrainian -X- _ O
resistance -X- _ O
almost -X- _ O
everywhere -X- _ O
and -X- _ O
faced -X- _ O
serious -X- _ O
logistical -X- _ O
problems -X- _ O
with -X- _ O
poorly -X- _ O
motivated -X- _ O
Russian -X- _ B-MilitaryPlatform
troops -X- _ I-MilitaryPlatform
suffering -X- _ O
shortages -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
food -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
water -X- _ O
and -X- _ O
ammunition -X- _ O
. -X- _ O

Ukrainian -X- _ B-Organisation
forces -X- _ I-Organisation
were -X- _ O
also -X- _ O
quick -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
deploy -X- _ O
Western -X- _ O
supplied -X- _ O
arms -X- _ O
such -X- _ O
as -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
Nlaw -X- _ B-MilitaryPlatform
anti-tank -X- _ I-MilitaryPlatform
system -X- _ I-MilitaryPlatform
, -X- _ O
which -X- _ O
proved -X- _ O
highly -X- _ O
effective -X- _ O
against -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
Russian -X- _ O
advance -X- _ O
. -X- _ O

By -X- _ O
October -X- _ B-Temporal
the -X- _ O
picture -X- _ O
had -X- _ O
changed -X- _ O
dramatically -X- _ O
and -X- _ O
having -X- _ O
failed -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
take -X- _ O
Kyiv -X- _ B-Location
, -X- _ O
Russia -X- _ B-Location
withdrew -X- _ O
completely -X- _ O
from -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
north -X- _ O
. -X- _ O

More -X- _ O
than -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
year -X- _ O
since -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
invasion -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
Ukraine -X- _ B-Location
is -X- _ O
now -X- _ O
hoping -X- _ O
its -X- _ O
latest -X- _ O
counter-offensive -X- _ O
can -X- _ O
turn -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
war -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
its -X- _ O
favour -X- _ O
. -X- _ O

About -X- _ O
these -X- _ O
maps -X- _ O
To -X- _ O
indicate -X- _ O
which -X- _ O
parts -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
Ukraine -X- _ B-Location
are -X- _ O
under -X- _ O
control -X- _ O
by -X- _ O
Russian -X- _ B-Organisation
troops -X- _ I-Organisation
we -X- _ O
are -X- _ O
using -X- _ O
daily -X- _ B-Temporal
assessments -X- _ O
published -X- _ O
by -X- _ O
the -X- _ B-Organisation
Institute -X- _ I-Organisation
for -X- _ I-Organisation
the -X- _ I-Organisation
Study -X- _ I-Organisation
of -X- _ I-Organisation
War -X- _ I-Organisation
with -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
American -X- _ B-Organisation
Enterprise -X- _ I-Organisation
Institute -X- _ I-Organisation
's -X- _ I-Organisation
Critical -X- _ O
Threats -X- _ O
Project. -X- _ O
To -X- _ O
show -X- _ O
key -X- _ O
areas -X- _ O
where -X- _ O
advances -X- _ O
are -X- _ O
taking -X- _ O
place -X- _ O
we -X- _ O
are -X- _ O
also -X- _ O
using -X- _ O
updates -X- _ O
from -X- _ O
the -X- _ B-Organisation
UK -X- _ I-Organisation
Ministry -X- _ I-Organisation
of -X- _ I-Organisation
Defence -X- _ I-Organisation
and -X- _ O
BBC -X- _ B-Organisation
research -X- _ O
. -X- _ O

The -X- _ O
situation -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
Ukraine -X- _ B-Location
is -X- _ O
often -X- _ O
fast -X- _ O
moving -X- _ O
and -X- _ O
it -X- _ O
is -X- _ O
likely -X- _ O
there -X- _ O
will -X- _ O
be -X- _ O
times -X- _ O
when -X- _ O
there -X- _ O
have -X- _ O
been -X- _ O
changes -X- _ O
not -X- _ O
reflected -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
maps -X- _ O
. -X- _ O

Specialist -X- _ B-MilitaryPlatform
British -X- _ I-MilitaryPlatform
military -X- _ I-MilitaryPlatform
bomb -X- _ I-MilitaryPlatform
disposal -X- _ I-MilitaryPlatform
teams -X- _ I-MilitaryPlatform
are -X- _ O
training -X- _ O
Ukrainian -X- _ O
engineers -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
clear -X- _ O
Russian -X- _ B-Location
minefields. -X- _ I-Location
Ukraine -X- _ B-Location
is -X- _ O
now -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
most -X- _ O
heavily -X- _ O
mined -X- _ O
country -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
world -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
and -X- _ O
it -X- _ O
's -X- _ O
slowing -X- _ O
down -X- _ O
Ukrainian -X- _ B-MilitaryPlatform
military -X- _ I-MilitaryPlatform
advances. -X- _ I-MilitaryPlatform
The -X- _ O
training -X- _ O
by -X- _ O
British -X- _ B-MilitaryPlatform
Army -X- _ I-MilitaryPlatform
sappers -X- _ I-MilitaryPlatform
- -X- _ O
combat -X- _ O
engineers -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
some -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
whom -X- _ O
faced -X- _ O
similar -X- _ O
obstacles -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
Afghanistan -X- _ B-Location
- -X- _ O
was -X- _ O
specifically -X- _ O
requested -X- _ O
by -X- _ O
Ukraine -X- _ B-Location
. -X- _ O

The -X- _ B-Organisation
BBC -X- _ I-Organisation
is -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
first -X- _ O
news -X- _ O
organisation -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
visit -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
military -X- _ O
base -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
Poland -X- _ B-Location
where -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
training -X- _ O
has -X- _ O
been -X- _ O
taking -X- _ O
place -X- _ O
. -X- _ O

Most -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
Ukrainian -X- _ O
engineers -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
like -X- _ O
Denys -X- _ B-Person
, -X- _ O
are -X- _ O
already -X- _ O
battle-hardened -X- _ O
and -X- _ O
experienced. -X- _ O
He -X- _ O
volunteered -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
fight -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
day -X- _ O
after -X- _ O
Russia -X- _ B-Location
's -X- _ I-Location
full-scale -X- _ O
invasion -X- _ O
began -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
February -X- _ B-Temporal
2022. -X- _ I-Temporal
This -X- _ O
brief -X- _ O
visit -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
Poland -X- _ B-Location
is -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
first -X- _ O
time -X- _ O
he -X- _ O
's -X- _ O
left -X- _ O
Ukraine -X- _ B-Location
since -X- _ O
2021 -X- _ B-Temporal
, -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
first -X- _ O
time -X- _ O
he -X- _ O
's -X- _ O
seen -X- _ O
passenger -X- _ B-MilitaryPlatform
jets -X- _ I-MilitaryPlatform
flying -X- _ O
overhead -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
nearly -X- _ O
two -X- _ O
years -X- _ O
. -X- _ O

Denys -X- _ B-Person
calls -X- _ O
Explosive -X- _ B-Organisation
Ordnance -X- _ I-Organisation
Disposal -X- _ I-Organisation
( -X- _ I-Organisation
EOD -X- _ I-Organisation
) -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
most -X- _ O
dangerous -X- _ O
job -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
world. -X- _ O
" -X- _ O
We -X- _ O
need -X- _ O
more -X- _ O
sappers -X- _ B-MilitaryPlatform
, -X- _ O
" -X- _ O
he -X- _ O
says -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
" -X- _ O
we -X- _ O
do -X- _ O
n't -X- _ O
have -X- _ O
enough -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
them -X- _ O
" -X- _ O
. -X- _ O
I -X- _ O
ask -X- _ O
him -X- _ O
if -X- _ O
he -X- _ O
's -X- _ O
lost -X- _ O
friends -X- _ O
doing -X- _ O
this -X- _ O
dangerous -X- _ O
work. -X- _ O
His -X- _ O
eyes -X- _ O
well -X- _ O
with -X- _ O
tears -X- _ O
as -X- _ O
he -X- _ O
nods -X- _ O
. -X- _ O

He -X- _ O
says -X- _ O
he -X- _ O
appreciates -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
help -X- _ O
being -X- _ O
given -X- _ O
by -X- _ O
his -X- _ O
British -X- _ O
brothers -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
arms -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
but -X- _ O
says -X- _ O
Ukraine -X- _ B-Location
still -X- _ O
needs -X- _ O
more -X- _ O
Western -X- _ O
help -X- _ O
and -X- _ O
equipment -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
clear -X- _ O
the -X- _ B-MilitaryPlatform
Russian -X- _ I-MilitaryPlatform
minefields. -X- _ I-MilitaryPlatform
" -X- _ O
We -X- _ O
ca -X- _ O
n't -X- _ O
do -X- _ O
it -X- _ O
on -X- _ O
our -X- _ O
own -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
" -X- _ O
he -X- _ O
says -X- _ O

Denys -X- _ B-Person
says -X- _ O
that -X- _ O
even -X- _ O
if -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
war -X- _ O
ended -X- _ O
tomorrow -X- _ B-Temporal
, -X- _ O
it -X- _ O
would -X- _ O
still -X- _ O
take -X- _ O
hundreds -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
years -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
clear -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
mines -X- _ B-Weapon
that -X- _ O
have -X- _ O
now -X- _ O
been -X- _ O
laid. -X- _ O
Russia -X- _ B-Location
has -X- _ O
been -X- _ O
producing -X- _ O
and -X- _ O
laying -X- _ O
mines -X- _ B-Weapon
on -X- _ O
an -X- _ O
industrial -X- _ O
scale -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
Ukraine. -X- _ B-Location
They -X- _ O
're -X- _ O
now -X- _ O
scattered -X- _ O
over -X- _ O
an -X- _ O
area -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
size -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
Florida -X- _ B-Location
; -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
minefields -X- _ B-MilitaryPlatform
can -X- _ O
be -X- _ O
up -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
10km -X- _ O
( -X- _ O
6.2 -X- _ O
miles -X- _ O
) -X- _ O
deep. -X- _ O
Just -X- _ O
one -X- _ O
square -X- _ O
metre -X- _ O
can -X- _ O
contain -X- _ O
as -X- _ O
many -X- _ O
as -X- _ O
five -X- _ O
explosives -X- _ B-Weapon
. -X- _ O

Image -X- _ O
caption -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
Ukrainian -X- _ O
engineers -X- _ O
are -X- _ O
being -X- _ O
shown -X- _ O
how -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
safely -X- _ O
clear -X- _ O
anti-tank -X- _ B-MilitaryPlatform
, -X- _ O
anti-personnel -X- _ B-MilitaryPlatform
, -X- _ O
and -X- _ O
bounding -X- _ B-MilitaryPlatform
minesAt -X- _ I-MilitaryPlatform
the -X- _ O
military -X- _ O
base -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
Poland -X- _ B-Location
, -X- _ O
more -X- _ O
than -X- _ O
20 -X- _ O
dummy -X- _ O
devices -X- _ O
have -X- _ O
been -X- _ O
buried -X- _ O
and -X- _ O
booby-trapped -X- _ O
by -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
small -X- _ O
UK -X- _ B-MilitaryPlatform
training -X- _ I-MilitaryPlatform
team -X- _ I-MilitaryPlatform
in -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
field. -X- _ O
The -X- _ B-Organisation
British -X- _ I-Organisation
EOD -X- _ I-Organisation
experts -X- _ I-Organisation
, -X- _ O
from -X- _ O
35 -X- _ B-Organisation
Engineer -X- _ I-Organisation
Regiment -X- _ I-Organisation
, -X- _ O
are -X- _ O
testing -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
Ukrainians -X- _ O
' -X- _ O
skills -X- _ O
as -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
course -X- _ O
nears -X- _ O
its -X- _ O
end -X- _ O

Among -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
devices -X- _ O
they -X- _ O
've -X- _ O
hidden -X- _ O
are -X- _ O
large -X- _ O
cylindrical -X- _ B-MilitaryPlatform
anti-tank -X- _ I-MilitaryPlatform
mines -X- _ I-MilitaryPlatform
; -X- _ O
smaller -X- _ O
anti-personnel -X- _ B-MilitaryPlatform
ones -X- _ O
; -X- _ O
bounding -X- _ B-MilitaryPlatform
mines -X- _ I-MilitaryPlatform
- -X- _ O
which -X- _ O
pop -X- _ O
out -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
ground -X- _ O
and -X- _ O
spread -X- _ O
shrapnel -X- _ O
over -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
wide -X- _ O
area -X- _ O
- -X- _ O
and -X- _ O
grenades -X- _ B-MilitaryPlatform
fitted -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
trip -X- _ O
wire -X- _ O
. -X- _ O

Those -X- _ O
not -X- _ O
on -X- _ O
display -X- _ O
include -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
small -X- _ O
butterfly -X- _ B-MilitaryPlatform
mines -X- _ I-MilitaryPlatform
designed -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
maim -X- _ O
; -X- _ O
others -X- _ O
triggered -X- _ O
by -X- _ O
vibration -X- _ O
rather -X- _ O
than -X- _ O
direct -X- _ O
contact -X- _ O
; -X- _ O
and -X- _ O
mines -X- _ B-Weapon
which -X- _ O
can -X- _ O
turn -X- _ O
themselves -X- _ O
on -X- _ O
and -X- _ O
off -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
avoid -X- _ O
detection. -X- _ O
Russia -X- _ B-Location
has -X- _ O
had -X- _ O
decades -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
plan -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
produce -X- _ O
and -X- _ O
prepare -X- _ O
these -X- _ O
weapons -X- _ B-MilitaryPlatform
- -X- _ O
now -X- _ O
one -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
major -X- _ O
causes -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
Ukrainian -X- _ O
casualties -X- _ O
and -X- _ O
injuries -X- _ O
. -X- _ O

Ihor -X- _ B-Person
, -X- _ O
who -X- _ O
has -X- _ O
been -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
sapper -X- _ B-MilitaryPlatform
for -X- _ O
four -X- _ O
years -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
says -X- _ O
he -X- _ O
has -X- _ O
already -X- _ O
lost -X- _ O
more -X- _ O
than -X- _ O
10 -X- _ O
members -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
his -X- _ O
team. -X- _ O
He -X- _ O
says -X- _ O
one -X- _ O
team -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
sappers -X- _ B-MilitaryPlatform
may -X- _ O
have -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
deal -X- _ O
with -X- _ O
more -X- _ O
than -X- _ O
100 -X- _ O
devices -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
day. -X- _ O
They -X- _ O
're -X- _ O
also -X- _ O
often -X- _ O
having -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
clear -X- _ O
areas -X- _ O
still -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
range -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
Russian -X- _ B-MilitaryPlatform
artillery -X- _ I-MilitaryPlatform
and -X- _ O
small -X- _ B-MilitaryPlatform
arms -X- _ I-MilitaryPlatform
fire -X- _ I-MilitaryPlatform

Image -X- _ O
caption -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
Staff -X- _ B-Person
Sgt -X- _ I-Person
Engstrom -X- _ I-Person
says -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
British -X- _ O
are -X- _ O
teaching -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
Ukrainians -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
gold -X- _ O
standard -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
mine -X- _ B-Weapon
clearanceThat -X- _ O
's -X- _ O
one -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
reasons -X- _ O
why -X- _ O
they -X- _ O
mostly -X- _ O
work -X- _ O
at -X- _ O
night. -X- _ O
Ukrainian -X- _ B-MilitaryPlatform
sappers -X- _ I-MilitaryPlatform
are -X- _ O
also -X- _ O
being -X- _ O
deliberately -X- _ O
targeted -X- _ O
by -X- _ O
Russian -X- _ B-Organisation
forces -X- _ I-Organisation
to -X- _ O
slow -X- _ O
down -X- _ O
their -X- _ O
advance. -X- _ O
" -X- _ O
When -X- _ O
we -X- _ O
advance -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
we -X- _ O
have -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
take -X- _ O
higher -X- _ O
risks. -X- _ O
We -X- _ O
do -X- _ O
n't -X- _ O
always -X- _ O
have -X- _ O
time -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
see -X- _ O
if -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
mines -X- _ B-Weapon
are -X- _ O
booby -X- _ O
trapped -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
" -X- _ O
says -X- _ O
Ihor. -X- _ B-Person
Staff -X- _ B-Person
Sgt -X- _ I-Person
Kevin -X- _ I-Person
Engstrom -X- _ I-Person
says -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
British -X- _ O
are -X- _ O
teaching -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
Ukrainians -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
gold -X- _ O
standard -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
mine -X- _ B-Weapon
clearance -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
which -X- _ O
involves -X- _ O
time -X- _ O
and -X- _ O
patience -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
but -X- _ O
adds -X- _ O
: -X- _ O
" -X- _ O
If -X- _ O
your -X- _ O
immediate -X- _ O
threat -X- _ O
is -X- _ O
gunfire -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
you -X- _ O
ca -X- _ O
n't -X- _ O
always -X- _ O
be -X- _ O
slow -X- _ O
and -X- _ O
methodical -X- _ O
. -X- _ O

" -X- _ O
As -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
Afghanistan -X- _ B-Location
, -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
threat -X- _ O
is -X- _ O
also -X- _ O
evolving -X- _ O
. -X- _ O

Denys -X- _ B-Person
says -X- _ O
it -X- _ O
's -X- _ O
now -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
norm -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
find -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
bodies -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
dead -X- _ O
Russian -X- _ O
soldiers -X- _ B-MilitaryPlatform
booby-trapped -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
liberated -X- _ O
territory. -X- _ O
Russia -X- _ B-Location
has -X- _ O
been -X- _ O
placing -X- _ O
anti-tank -X- _ B-Weapon
mines -X- _ I-Weapon
on -X- _ O
top -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
each -X- _ O
other -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
cause -X- _ O
larger -X- _ O
explosions -X- _ O
. -X- _ O

Smaller -X- _ O
anti-personnel -X- _ B-Weapon
mines -X- _ I-Weapon
are -X- _ O
also -X- _ O
being -X- _ O
placed -X- _ O
on -X- _ O
top -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
vehicle -X- _ B-Weapon
mines -X- _ I-Weapon
to -X- _ O
trigger -X- _ O
the -X- _ B-Weapon
larger -X- _ I-Weapon
bomb. -X- _ I-Weapon
Trip -X- _ B-Weapon
wires -X- _ I-Weapon
are -X- _ O
often -X- _ O
hidden -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
grass -X- _ O
. -X- _ O

The -X- _ O
Russians -X- _ O
also -X- _ O
now -X- _ O
hang -X- _ O
them -X- _ O
from -X- _ O
trees -X- _ O
with -X- _ O
hooks -X- _ O
attached -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
try -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
snag -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
uniforms -X- _ O
and -X- _ O
equipment -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
advancing -X- _ B-MilitaryPlatform
troops -X- _ I-MilitaryPlatform
. -X- _ O

Clearing -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
path -X- _ O
through -X- _ O
these -X- _ O
deadly -X- _ O
hidden -X- _ O
traps -X- _ O
can -X- _ O
be -X- _ O
slow -X- _ O
and -X- _ O
laborious. -X- _ O
The -X- _ B-MilitaryPlatform
Ukrainian -X- _ I-MilitaryPlatform
sappers -X- _ I-MilitaryPlatform
first -X- _ O
use -X- _ O
Vallons -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
which -X- _ O
look -X- _ O
like -X- _ O
metal -X- _ O
detectors -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
clear -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
path. -X- _ O
Britain -X- _ B-Location
has -X- _ O
already -X- _ O
provided -X- _ O
Ukraine -X- _ B-Location
with -X- _ O
1,500 -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
them. -X- _ O
When -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
Vallon -X- _ O
squawks -X- _ O
the -X- _ B-MilitaryPlatform
sappers -X- _ I-MilitaryPlatform
get -X- _ O
down -X- _ O
on -X- _ O
their -X- _ O
knees -X- _ O
and -X- _ O
stomachs -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
identify -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
threat. -X- _ O
It -X- _ O
can -X- _ O
be -X- _ O
painstaking -X- _ O
work -X- _ O
by -X- _ O
hand -X- _ O

Denys -X- _ B-Person
admires -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
ants -X- _ O
crawling -X- _ O
on -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
ground -X- _ O
before -X- _ O
spotting -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
trip -X- _ O
wire. -X- _ O
" -X- _ O
You -X- _ O
guys -X- _ O
make -X- _ O
it -X- _ O
hard -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
" -X- _ O
he -X- _ O
laughs -X- _ O
. -X- _ O

The -X- _ O
British -X- _ O
trainers -X- _ O
all -X- _ O
comment -X- _ O
on -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
speed -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
Ukrainians. -X- _ O
" -X- _ O
They -X- _ O
're -X- _ O
very -X- _ O
quick. -X- _ O
The -X- _ O
first -X- _ O
time -X- _ O
I -X- _ O
deployed -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
Afghanistan -X- _ B-Location
I -X- _ O
was -X- _ O
slow. -X- _ O
They -X- _ O
do -X- _ O
n't -X- _ O
miss -X- _ O
much -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
" -X- _ O
says -X- _ O
Staff -X- _ B-Person
Sgt -X- _ I-Person
Engstrom. -X- _ I-Person
Their -X- _ O
work -X- _ O
is -X- _ O
impressive -X- _ O
with -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
kit -X- _ O
they -X- _ O
've -X- _ O
been -X- _ O
given -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
he -X- _ O
adds -X- _ O

Image -X- _ O
caption -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
The -X- _ B-Organisation
UK -X- _ I-Organisation
has -X- _ O
provided -X- _ O
Ukraine -X- _ B-Location
with -X- _ O
1,500 -X- _ O
Vallons -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
which -X- _ O
are -X- _ O
used -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
clear -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
pathMaking -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
device -X- _ O
safe -X- _ O
is -X- _ O
not -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
biggest -X- _ O
challenge. -X- _ O
Ihor -X- _ B-Person
says -X- _ O
he -X- _ O
was -X- _ O
already -X- _ O
familiar -X- _ O
with -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
types -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
mines -X- _ B-Weapon
the -X- _ O
Russians -X- _ O
use -X- _ O
before -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
invasion. -X- _ O
" -X- _ O
It -X- _ O
's -X- _ O
quite -X- _ O
easy -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
disarm -X- _ O
mines -X- _ B-Weapon
, -X- _ O
but -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
Russians -X- _ O
are -X- _ O
making -X- _ O
it -X- _ O
more -X- _ O
difficult -X- _ O
" -X- _ O
. -X- _ O
The -X- _ O
British -X- _ B-Organisation
instructors -X- _ I-Organisation
liken -X- _ O
it -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
solving -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
puzzle -X- _ O
or -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
game -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
chess -X- _ O

The -X- _ O
real -X- _ O
challenge -X- _ O
is -X- _ O
trying -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
work -X- _ O
out -X- _ O
where -X- _ O
the -X- _ B-MilitaryPlatform
minefields -X- _ I-MilitaryPlatform
are -X- _ O
and -X- _ O
why -X- _ O
they -X- _ O
have -X- _ O
been -X- _ O
placed -X- _ O
there. -X- _ O
It -X- _ O
's -X- _ O
often -X- _ O
deliberate -X- _ O
- -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
draw -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
troops -X- _ B-MilitaryPlatform
who -X- _ O
can -X- _ O
then -X- _ O
be -X- _ O
targeted -X- _ O
by -X- _ O
artillery. -X- _ B-MilitaryPlatform
Mines -X- _ B-Weapon
are -X- _ O
often -X- _ O
booby -X- _ O
trapped. -X- _ O
Capt -X- _ B-Person
Chris -X- _ I-Person
Wilson -X- _ I-Person
, -X- _ O
who -X- _ O
leads -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
small -X- _ O
British -X- _ O
training -X- _ O
team -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
Poland -X- _ B-Location
, -X- _ O
says -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
character -X- _ O
traits -X- _ O
needed -X- _ O
for -X- _ O
Explosive -X- _ B-Organisation
Ordnance -X- _ I-Organisation
Disposal -X- _ I-Organisation
and -X- _ I-Organisation
Search -X- _ I-Organisation
" -X- _ O
is -X- _ O
someone -X- _ O
who -X- _ O
's -X- _ O
slow -X- _ O
and -X- _ O
methodical -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
who -X- _ O
can -X- _ O
think -X- _ O
and -X- _ O
understand -X- _ O
problem-solving -X- _ O
while -X- _ O
retaining -X- _ O
their -X- _ O
composure -X- _ O
" -X- _ O
. -X- _ O

This -X- _ O
training -X- _ O
only -X- _ O
started -X- _ O
last -X- _ O
November. -X- _ B-Temporal
Each -X- _ O
course -X- _ O
is -X- _ O
just -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
few -X- _ O
weeks -X- _ O
long -X- _ O
and -X- _ O
includes -X- _ O
just -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
few -X- _ O
dozen -X- _ O
experienced -X- _ O
Ukrainian -X- _ B-MilitaryPlatform
sappers. -X- _ I-MilitaryPlatform
That -X- _ O
tells -X- _ O
you -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
high -X- _ O
demand -X- _ O
for -X- _ O
them -X- _ O
back -X- _ O
on -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
front -X- _ O
line. -X- _ O
In -X- _ O
Southern -X- _ B-Location
Ukraine -X- _ I-Location
they -X- _ O
may -X- _ O
have -X- _ O
broken -X- _ O
through -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
first -X- _ O
lines -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
Russian -X- _ O
defences. -X- _ O
But -X- _ O
yet -X- _ O
more -X- _ O
Russian -X- _ B-MilitaryPlatform
minefields -X- _ I-MilitaryPlatform
, -X- _ O
dragons -X- _ O
' -X- _ O
teeth -X- _ O
and -X- _ O
trenches -X- _ B-MilitaryPlatform
stand -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
their -X- _ O
way. -X- _ O
Ihor -X- _ B-Person
and -X- _ O
his -X- _ O
team -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
sappers -X- _ B-MilitaryPlatform
know -X- _ O
they -X- _ O
still -X- _ O
have -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
huge -X- _ O
task -X- _ O
ahead. -X- _ O
But -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
he -X- _ O
says -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
they -X- _ O
have -X- _ O
no -X- _ O
choice -X- _ O
. -X- _ O

" -X- _ O
Unfortunately -X- _ O
we -X- _ O
will -X- _ O
lose -X- _ O
more -X- _ O
guys -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
process -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
but -X- _ O
we -X- _ O
have -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
do -X- _ O
it -X- _ O
. -X- _ O

" -X- _ O
At -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
very -X- _ O
least -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
British -X- _ O
instructors -X- _ O
hope -X- _ O
this -X- _ O
training -X- _ O
will -X- _ O
save -X- _ O
some -X- _ O
Ukrainian -X- _ O
lives -X- _ O
. -X- _ O

Ukraine -X- _ B-Person
's -X- _ I-Person
generals -X- _ I-Person
say -X- _ O
they -X- _ O
have -X- _ O
" -X- _ O
broken -X- _ O
through -X- _ O
" -X- _ O
Russia -X- _ B-Location
's -X- _ I-Location
first -X- _ O
line -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
defence -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
south. -X- _ O
We -X- _ O
've -X- _ O
assessed -X- _ O
how -X- _ O
far -X- _ O
Ukrainian -X- _ B-Organisation
forces -X- _ I-Organisation
have -X- _ O
really -X- _ O
progressed -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
and -X- _ O
what -X- _ O
signs -X- _ O
there -X- _ O
are -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
further -X- _ O
breakthroughs -X- _ O
along -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
frontline -X- _ O
. -X- _ O

Ukraine -X- _ B-Location
began -X- _ O
its -X- _ O
big -X- _ O
counter-offensive -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
early -X- _ O
June -X- _ B-Temporal
to -X- _ O
push -X- _ O
Russian -X- _ B-Organisation
forces -X- _ I-Organisation
back -X- _ O
from -X- _ O
land -X- _ O
they -X- _ O
seized. -X- _ O
It -X- _ O
attacked -X- _ O
at -X- _ O
three -X- _ O
points -X- _ O
along -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
600-mile-plus -X- _ O
( -X- _ O
965km -X- _ O
) -X- _ O
frontline. -X- _ O
The -X- _ O
area -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
the -X- _ B-Location
south-east -X- _ I-Location
of -X- _ I-Location
the -X- _ I-Location
city -X- _ I-Location
of -X- _ I-Location
Zaporizhzhia -X- _ I-Location
is -X- _ O
by -X- _ O
far -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
most -X- _ O
strategically -X- _ O
important -X- _ O
. -X- _ O

Striking -X- _ O
out -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
this -X- _ O
direction -X- _ O
towards -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
Sea -X- _ B-Location
of -X- _ I-Location
Azov -X- _ I-Location
, -X- _ O
if -X- _ O
successful -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
could -X- _ O
cut -X- _ O
off -X- _ O
Russia -X- _ B-Location
's -X- _ I-Location
supply -X- _ I-Location
lines -X- _ I-Location
that -X- _ O
connect -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
Russian -X- _ O
city -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
Rostov-on-Don -X- _ B-Location
to -X- _ O
Crimea -X- _ B-Location
. -X- _ O

There -X- _ O
has -X- _ O
n't -X- _ O
been -X- _ O
much -X- _ O
progress -X- _ O
on -X- _ O
this -X- _ O
front -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
except -X- _ O
for -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
area -X- _ O
around -X- _ O
the -X- _ B-Location
villages -X- _ I-Location
of -X- _ I-Location
Robotyne -X- _ I-Location
and -X- _ O
Verbove -X- _ B-Location
in -X- _ O
the -X- _ B-Location
Zaporizhzhia -X- _ I-Location
region -X- _ I-Location
, -X- _ O
as -X- _ O
seen -X- _ O
highlighted -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
purple -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
map -X- _ O
above -X- _ O
. -X- _ O

If -X- _ O
Ukraine -X- _ B-Location
can -X- _ O
sever -X- _ O
this -X- _ O
main -X- _ O
supply -X- _ O
route -X- _ O
then -X- _ O
Russia -X- _ B-Location
will -X- _ O
find -X- _ O
it -X- _ O
all -X- _ O
but -X- _ O
impossible -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
maintain -X- _ O
its -X- _ O
huge -X- _ O
garrison -X- _ B-MilitaryPlatform
in -X- _ O
Crimea -X- _ B-Location
which -X- _ O
it -X- _ O
annexed -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
2014 -X- _ B-Temporal
. -X- _ O

Despite -X- _ O
significant -X- _ O
obstacles -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
there -X- _ O
are -X- _ O
now -X- _ O
confirmed -X- _ O
sightings -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
Ukrainian -X- _ B-Organisation
troops -X- _ I-Organisation
breaching -X- _ O
Russia -X- _ B-Location
's -X- _ I-Location
defensive -X- _ O
structures -X- _ O
along -X- _ O
the -X- _ B-Location
southern -X- _ I-Location
front -X- _ I-Location
. -X- _ O

We -X- _ O
have -X- _ O
verified -X- _ O
nine -X- _ O
social -X- _ O
media -X- _ O
videos -X- _ O
along -X- _ O
the -X- _ B-Location
frontline -X- _ I-Location
near -X- _ I-Location
Verbove -X- _ I-Location
. -X- _ O

Four -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
videos -X- _ O
show -X- _ O
Ukrainian -X- _ B-Organisation
forces -X- _ I-Organisation
breaching -X- _ O
Russian -X- _ O
defences -X- _ O
north -X- _ B-Location
of -X- _ I-Location
Verbove -X- _ I-Location
. -X- _ O

However -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
these -X- _ O
show -X- _ O
incursions -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
not -X- _ O
that -X- _ O
Ukraine -X- _ B-Location
has -X- _ O
managed -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
take -X- _ O
control -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
area -X- _ O
. -X- _ O

So -X- _ O
far -X- _ O
it -X- _ O
has -X- _ O
only -X- _ O
been -X- _ O
Ukrainian -X- _ O
infantry -X- _ B-MilitaryPlatform
getting -X- _ O
through -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
and -X- _ O
we -X- _ O
're -X- _ O
not -X- _ O
seeing -X- _ O
Ukrainian -X- _ O
armoured -X- _ O
columns -X- _ O
pouring -X- _ O
through -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
exploiting -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
gap -X- _ O
and -X- _ O
holding -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
ground -X- _ O
taken. -X- _ O
What -X- _ O
is -X- _ O
stopping -X- _ O
Ukraine -X- _ B-Person
advancing -X- _ O
faster -X- _ O
? -X- _ O

Moscow -X- _ B-Location
saw -X- _ O
this -X- _ O
counter -X- _ O
attack -X- _ O
coming -X- _ O
long -X- _ O
ago -X- _ O
and -X- _ O
has -X- _ O
spent -X- _ O
months -X- _ O
building -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
world -X- _ O
's -X- _ O
most -X- _ O
formidable -X- _ O
layered -X- _ O
defences -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
depth. -X- _ O
This -X- _ O
is -X- _ O
what -X- _ O
they -X- _ O
look -X- _ O
like -X- _ O
from -X- _ O
space -X- _ O
- -X- _ O
lines -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
interlocking -X- _ O
obstacles -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
trenches -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
bunkers -X- _ B-Location
and -X- _ O
minefields -X- _ B-MilitaryPlatform
, -X- _ O
each -X- _ O
covered -X- _ O
by -X- _ O
artillery. -X- _ B-MilitaryPlatform
Its -X- _ O
so-called -X- _ O
dragon -X- _ O
's -X- _ O
teeth -X- _ O
are -X- _ O
concrete -X- _ O
anti-tank -X- _ B-MilitaryPlatform
barriers -X- _ I-MilitaryPlatform
. -X- _ O

Vast -X- _ O
minefields -X- _ B-MilitaryPlatform
have -X- _ O
slowed -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
Ukrainian -X- _ O
advance -X- _ O
. -X- _ O

These -X- _ O
minefields -X- _ B-MilitaryPlatform
are -X- _ O
intensely -X- _ O
packed -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
some -X- _ O
places -X- _ O
up -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
five -X- _ O
mines -X- _ B-Weapon
laid -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
square -X- _ O
metre -X- _ O
. -X- _ O

Ukraine -X- _ B-Location
's -X- _ I-Location
first -X- _ O
attempt -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
charge -X- _ O
through -X- _ O
them -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
June -X- _ B-Temporal
quickly -X- _ O
ended -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
failure -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
with -X- _ O
its -X- _ O
modern -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
Western-supplied -X- _ O
armour -X- _ O
crippled -X- _ O
and -X- _ O
burning. -X- _ O
Ukrainian -X- _ B-Organisation
infantry -X- _ I-Organisation
came -X- _ O
similarly -X- _ O
unstuck -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
taking -X- _ O
horrific -X- _ O
casualties -X- _ O
. -X- _ O

Kyiv -X- _ B-Location
has -X- _ O
since -X- _ O
had -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
resort -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
clearing -X- _ O
these -X- _ O
mines -X- _ B-Weapon
on -X- _ O
foot -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
often -X- _ O
at -X- _ O
night -X- _ O
and -X- _ O
sometimes -X- _ O
under -X- _ O
fire. -X- _ O
Hence -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
slow -X- _ O
progress -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
date -X- _ O
. -X- _ O

Ukraine -X- _ B-Location
's -X- _ I-Location
tanks -X- _ B-MilitaryPlatform
and -X- _ O
armoured -X- _ B-MilitaryPlatform
vehicles -X- _ I-MilitaryPlatform
are -X- _ O
vulnerable -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
Russia -X- _ B-Location
's -X- _ I-Location
mines -X- _ B-Weapon
, -X- _ O
drones -X- _ B-MilitaryPlatform
and -X- _ O
anti-tank -X- _ B-Weapon
missiles -X- _ I-Weapon
- -X- _ O
like -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
this -X- _ O
video -X- _ O
analysed -X- _ O
by -X- _ O
BBC -X- _ B-Organisation
Verify -X- _ O
which -X- _ O
shows -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
British-supplied -X- _ O
Challenger -X- _ B-MilitaryPlatform
2 -X- _ I-MilitaryPlatform
tank -X- _ I-MilitaryPlatform
that -X- _ O
got -X- _ O
hit -X- _ O
near -X- _ O
Robotyne -X- _ B-Location
. -X- _ O

These -X- _ O
will -X- _ O
only -X- _ O
be -X- _ O
able -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
push -X- _ O
forward -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
numbers -X- _ O
once -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
sufficiently -X- _ O
wide -X- _ O
path -X- _ O
has -X- _ O
been -X- _ O
cleared -X- _ O
through -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
minefields -X- _ B-MilitaryPlatform
and -X- _ O
when -X- _ O
Russian -X- _ O
artillery -X- _ B-MilitaryPlatform
there -X- _ O
has -X- _ O
been -X- _ O
subdued -X- _ O
. -X- _ O

What -X- _ O
next -X- _ O
for -X- _ O
Ukraine -X- _ B-Location
's -X- _ I-Location
counter-offensive -X- _ O
? -X- _ O

" -X- _ O
The -X- _ O
problem -X- _ O
that -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
Ukrainians -X- _ O
have -X- _ O
now -X- _ O
" -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
says -X- _ O
Dr -X- _ B-Person
Marina -X- _ I-Person
Miron -X- _ I-Person
at -X- _ O
King -X- _ B-Organisation
's -X- _ I-Organisation
College -X- _ I-Organisation
London -X- _ I-Organisation
War -X- _ I-Organisation
Studies -X- _ I-Organisation
Department -X- _ I-Organisation
, -X- _ O
" -X- _ O
is -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
get -X- _ O
an -X- _ O
opening -X- _ O
big -X- _ O
enough -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
get -X- _ O
more -X- _ O
troops -X- _ B-MilitaryPlatform
in -X- _ O
" -X- _ O
. -X- _ O

Meanwhile -X- _ O
Russia -X- _ B-Location
has -X- _ O
been -X- _ O
moving -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
reinforcements -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
and -X- _ O
this -X- _ O
battlefront -X- _ B-Location
is -X- _ O
dynamic -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
it -X- _ O
's -X- _ O
moving -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
and -X- _ O
Russia -X- _ B-Location
could -X- _ O
still -X- _ O
reverse -X- _ O
Ukraine -X- _ B-Location
's -X- _ I-Location
gains -X- _ O
. -X- _ O

We -X- _ O
've -X- _ O
geolocated -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
Russian -X- _ O
drone -X- _ B-MilitaryPlatform
video -X- _ O
which -X- _ O
backs -X- _ O
up -X- _ O
reports -X- _ O
that -X- _ O
its -X- _ O
elite -X- _ B-MilitaryPlatform
airborne -X- _ I-MilitaryPlatform
forces -X- _ I-MilitaryPlatform
, -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
VDV -X- _ B-Organisation
, -X- _ O
have -X- _ O
deployed -X- _ O
close -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
town -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
Verbove -X- _ B-Location
- -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
move -X- _ O
aimed -X- _ O
at -X- _ O
plugging -X- _ O
any -X- _ O
gaps -X- _ O
created -X- _ O
by -X- _ O
Ukraine -X- _ B-MilitaryPlatform
's -X- _ I-MilitaryPlatform
counter-offensive. -X- _ I-MilitaryPlatform
" -X- _ O
Ukrainian -X- _ B-Organisation
forces -X- _ I-Organisation
continue -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
face -X- _ O
resistance -X- _ O
from -X- _ O
Russian -X- _ B-Organisation
forces -X- _ I-Organisation
on -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
battlefield -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
" -X- _ O
says -X- _ O
Kateryna -X- _ B-Person
Stepanenko -X- _ I-Person
, -X- _ O
Russia -X- _ B-Location
analyst -X- _ O
at -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
US-based -X- _ B-Location
think -X- _ O
tank -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
Institute -X- _ B-Location
for -X- _ I-Location
the -X- _ I-Location
Study -X- _ I-Location
of -X- _ I-Location
War. -X- _ I-Location
" -X- _ O
Alongside -X- _ O
artillery -X- _ B-Weapon
fire -X- _ I-Weapon
, -X- _ O
drone -X- _ B-MilitaryPlatform
strikes -X- _ O
and -X- _ O
Russian -X- _ B-MilitaryPlatform
defensive -X- _ I-MilitaryPlatform
structures -X- _ I-MilitaryPlatform
- -X- _ O
Russian -X- _ B-Organisation
forces -X- _ I-Organisation
are -X- _ O
also -X- _ O
extensively -X- _ O
using -X- _ O
electronic -X- _ O
warfare -X- _ O
measures -X- _ O
that -X- _ O
aim -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
impede -X- _ O
Ukrainian -X- _ O
signals -X- _ O
and -X- _ O
drone -X- _ B-MilitaryPlatform
usage -X- _ O
. -X- _ O

" -X- _ O
Ukraine -X- _ B-Location
has -X- _ O
barely -X- _ O
progressed -X- _ O
more -X- _ O
than -X- _ O
10 -X- _ O
% -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
way -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
coast -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
but -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
reality -X- _ O
is -X- _ O
much -X- _ O
more -X- _ O
nuanced -X- _ O
than -X- _ O
that -X- _ O
. -X- _ O

Ukrainian -X- _ B-MilitaryPlatform
troops -X- _ I-MilitaryPlatform
near -X- _ O
the -X- _ B-Location
village -X- _ I-Location
of -X- _ I-Location
Robotyne -X- _ I-Location
on -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
southern -X- _ B-Location
frontline -X- _ I-Location
Russia -X- _ B-MilitaryPlatform
's -X- _ I-MilitaryPlatform
forces -X- _ I-MilitaryPlatform
are -X- _ O
exhausted -X- _ O
and -X- _ O
possibly -X- _ O
demoralised -X- _ O
after -X- _ O
sustaining -X- _ O
three -X- _ O
months -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
intensive -X- _ O
attacks -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
including -X- _ O
long-range -X- _ O
strikes -X- _ O
that -X- _ O
are -X- _ O
targeting -X- _ O
their -X- _ O
supply -X- _ O
lines -X- _ O
. -X- _ O

If -X- _ O
Ukraine -X- _ B-Location
can -X- _ O
break -X- _ O
through -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
remaining -X- _ O
Russian -X- _ O
defences -X- _ O
and -X- _ O
reach -X- _ O
as -X- _ O
far -X- _ O
as -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
town -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
Tokmak -X- _ B-Location
then -X- _ O
this -X- _ O
would -X- _ O
bring -X- _ O
Russia -X- _ B-Location
's -X- _ I-Location
rail -X- _ O
and -X- _ O
road -X- _ O
supply -X- _ O
routes -X- _ O
for -X- _ O
Crimea -X- _ B-Location
within -X- _ O
range -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
its -X- _ O
artillery -X- _ B-MilitaryPlatform
. -X- _ O

If -X- _ O
they -X- _ O
can -X- _ O
do -X- _ O
that -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
then -X- _ O
this -X- _ O
counter -X- _ O
offensive -X- _ O
can -X- _ O
be -X- _ O
judged -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
qualified -X- _ O
success -X- _ O
. -X- _ O

It -X- _ O
may -X- _ O
not -X- _ O
end -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
war -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
which -X- _ O
is -X- _ O
likely -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
drag -X- _ O
on -X- _ O
well -X- _ O
into -X- _ O
2024 -X- _ B-Temporal
and -X- _ O
perhaps -X- _ O
longer -X- _ O
- -X- _ O
but -X- _ O
it -X- _ O
would -X- _ O
seriously -X- _ O
undermine -X- _ O
Moscow -X- _ B-Location
's -X- _ I-Location
war -X- _ O
effort -X- _ O
and -X- _ O
put -X- _ O
Ukraine -X- _ B-Location
in -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
strong -X- _ O
position -X- _ O
for -X- _ O
when -X- _ O
peace -X- _ O
talks -X- _ O
eventually -X- _ O
begin. -X- _ O
But -X- _ O
for -X- _ O
Kyiv -X- _ B-Location
, -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
clock -X- _ O
is -X- _ O
ticking. -X- _ O
The -X- _ O
rainy -X- _ O
season -X- _ O
will -X- _ O
arrive -X- _ O
within -X- _ O
weeks -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
turning -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
roads -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
mud -X- _ O
and -X- _ O
hindering -X- _ O
further -X- _ O
advances. -X- _ O
Beyond -X- _ O
that -X- _ O
lies -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
uncertainty -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
US -X- _ B-Organisation
presidential -X- _ O
elections -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
where -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
Republican -X- _ O
victory -X- _ O
could -X- _ O
see -X- _ O
US -X- _ B-Organisation
military -X- _ I-Organisation
support -X- _ O
for -X- _ O
Ukraine -X- _ B-Location
dramatically -X- _ O
slashed. -X- _ O
President -X- _ B-Person
Putin -X- _ I-Person
knows -X- _ O
he -X- _ O
needs -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
tough -X- _ O
it -X- _ O
out -X- _ O
until -X- _ O
then. -X- _ O
The -X- _ O
Ukrainians -X- _ O
know -X- _ O
they -X- _ O
have -X- _ O
got -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
make -X- _ O
this -X- _ O
counter-offensive -X- _ O
succeed -X- _ O
. -X- _ O

Ukraine -X- _ B-Location
cyber-operators -X- _ O
are -X- _ O
being -X- _ O
deployed -X- _ O
on -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
front -X- _ O
lines -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
war -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
duelling -X- _ O
close-up -X- _ O
with -X- _ O
their -X- _ O
Russian -X- _ O
counterparts -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
new -X- _ O
kind -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
high-tech -X- _ O
battle. -X- _ O
" -X- _ O
We -X- _ O
have -X- _ O
people -X- _ O
who -X- _ O
are -X- _ O
directly -X- _ O
involved -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
combat -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
" -X- _ O
says -X- _ O
Illia -X- _ B-Person
Vitiuk -X- _ I-Person
, -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
head -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
the -X- _ B-Organisation
Ukrainian -X- _ I-Organisation
Security -X- _ I-Organisation
Service -X- _ I-Organisation
's -X- _ I-Organisation
( -X- _ I-Organisation
SBU -X- _ I-Organisation
) -X- _ I-Organisation
cyber -X- _ I-Organisation
department -X- _ I-Organisation
. -X- _ O

Speaking -X- _ O
inside -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
heavily -X- _ O
protected -X- _ O
SBU -X- _ B-Organisation
headquarters -X- _ I-Organisation
, -X- _ O
he -X- _ O
explains -X- _ O
how -X- _ O
his -X- _ O
teams -X- _ O
mix -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
skills -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
hackers -X- _ O
and -X- _ O
special -X- _ B-MilitaryPlatform
forces -X- _ I-MilitaryPlatform
- -X- _ O
getting -X- _ O
inside -X- _ O
Russian -X- _ O
systems -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
working -X- _ O
alongside -X- _ O
snipers -X- _ O
and -X- _ O
deploying -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
latest -X- _ O
technologies -X- _ O

The -X- _ B-Organisation
department -X- _ I-Organisation
uses -X- _ O
Artificial -X- _ O
Intelligence -X- _ O
( -X- _ O
AI -X- _ O
) -X- _ O
visual -X- _ O
recognition -X- _ O
systems -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
analyse -X- _ O
information -X- _ O
gathered -X- _ O
from -X- _ O
aerial -X- _ B-MilitaryPlatform
drones -X- _ I-MilitaryPlatform
( -X- _ O
alongside -X- _ O
intelligence -X- _ O
from -X- _ O
human -X- _ O
sources -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
satellites -X- _ O
and -X- _ O
other -X- _ O
technical -X- _ O
sources -X- _ O
) -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
provide -X- _ O
targets -X- _ O
for -X- _ O
the -X- _ B-Organisation
military. -X- _ I-Organisation
" -X- _ O
We -X- _ O
understand -X- _ O
which -X- _ O
type -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
military -X- _ B-Weapon
weapons -X- _ I-Weapon
they -X- _ O
are -X- _ O
about -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
use -X- _ O
and -X- _ O
on -X- _ O
what -X- _ O
direction -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
" -X- _ O
Mr -X- _ B-Person
Vitiuk -X- _ I-Person
says -X- _ O
. -X- _ O

His -X- _ O
teams -X- _ O
will -X- _ O
also -X- _ O
hack -X- _ O
into -X- _ O
surveillance -X- _ O
cameras -X- _ O
on -X- _ O
occupied -X- _ O
territory -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
watch -X- _ O
Russian -X- _ B-Organisation
troop -X- _ I-Organisation
movements. -X- _ O
And -X- _ O
they -X- _ O
direct -X- _ O
kamikaze -X- _ B-MilitaryPlatform
drones -X- _ I-MilitaryPlatform
to -X- _ O
take -X- _ O
out -X- _ O
Russian -X- _ B-MilitaryPlatform
cameras -X- _ I-MilitaryPlatform
spying -X- _ O
on -X- _ O
Ukrainian -X- _ O
movements. -X- _ O
Doing -X- _ O
this -X- _ O
often -X- _ O
requires -X- _ O
teams -X- _ O
working -X- _ O
undercover -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
close -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
target -X- _ O
. -X- _ O

Drones -X- _ B-MilitaryPlatform
- -X- _ O
sometimes -X- _ O
used -X- _ O
for -X- _ O
surveillance -X- _ O
and -X- _ O
sometimes -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
act -X- _ O
as -X- _ O
weapons -X- _ B-MilitaryPlatform
- -X- _ O
have -X- _ O
been -X- _ O
at -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
leading -X- _ O
edge -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
innovation -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
this -X- _ O
conflict -X- _ O
. -X- _ O

We -X- _ O
understand -X- _ O
which -X- _ O
type -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
military -X- _ B-Weapon
weapons -X- _ I-Weapon
[ -X- _ O
Russian -X- _ B-MilitaryPlatform
forces -X- _ I-MilitaryPlatform
] -X- _ O
are -X- _ O
about -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
use. -X- _ O
Head -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
Ukraine -X- _ B-Organisation
's -X- _ I-Organisation
cyber -X- _ I-Organisation
security -X- _ I-Organisation
department -X- _ I-Organisation

The -X- _ B-Organisation
SBU -X- _ I-Organisation
cyber-team -X- _ O
flies -X- _ O
its -X- _ O
own -X- _ O
drones -X- _ B-MilitaryPlatform
and -X- _ O
plays -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
cat -X- _ O
and -X- _ O
mouse -X- _ O
game -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
disrupt -X- _ O
those -X- _ O
belonging -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
Russia. -X- _ B-Location
It -X- _ O
deploys -X- _ O
sensors -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
detect -X- _ O
drones -X- _ B-MilitaryPlatform
so -X- _ O
operators -X- _ O
can -X- _ O
not -X- _ O
just -X- _ O
jam -X- _ O
them -X- _ O
but -X- _ O
try -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
take -X- _ O
control -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
sending -X- _ O
commands -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
make -X- _ O
them -X- _ O
land. -X- _ O
All -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
this -X- _ O
frequently -X- _ O
needs -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
be -X- _ O
done -X- _ O
at -X- _ O
close -X- _ O
quarters. -X- _ O
This -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
turn -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
carries -X- _ O
risk -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
team -X- _ O
members. -X- _ O
" -X- _ O
You -X- _ O
need -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
protect -X- _ O
them -X- _ O
there. -X- _ O
So -X- _ O
you -X- _ O
also -X- _ O
need -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
have -X- _ O
security -X- _ O
around -X- _ O
them -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
" -X- _ O
explains -X- _ O
Mr -X- _ B-Person
Vitiuk -X- _ I-Person

Just -X- _ O
outside -X- _ O
the -X- _ B-Location
capital -X- _ I-Location
, -X- _ O
military -X- _ O
operators -X- _ O
are -X- _ O
being -X- _ O
trained -X- _ O
on -X- _ O
drones -X- _ B-MilitaryPlatform
. -X- _ O

Anton -X- _ B-Person
, -X- _ O
who -X- _ O
learnt -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
fly -X- _ O
them -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
previous -X- _ O
life -X- _ O
as -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
high-end -X- _ O
travel -X- _ O
guide -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
says -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
most -X- _ O
important -X- _ O
lesson -X- _ O
is -X- _ O
not -X- _ O
teaching -X- _ O
operators -X- _ O
how -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
fly -X- _ O
drones -X- _ B-MilitaryPlatform
but -X- _ O
how -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
stay -X- _ O
alive -X- _ O
themselves -X- _ O
by -X- _ O
avoiding -X- _ O
being -X- _ O
detected. -X- _ O
In -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
early -X- _ O
stages -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
war -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
small -X- _ O
drones -X- _ B-MilitaryPlatform
were -X- _ O
flown -X- _ O
up -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
10km -X- _ O
( -X- _ O
six -X- _ O
miles -X- _ O
) -X- _ O
from -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
front. -X- _ O
But -X- _ O
now -X- _ O
Ukrainian -X- _ O
operators -X- _ O
need -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
be -X- _ O
much -X- _ O
closer -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
overcome -X- _ O
Russian -X- _ B-Weapon
jamming -X- _ I-Weapon
signals. -X- _ I-Weapon
" -X- _ O
The -X- _ O
distance -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
front -X- _ O
line -X- _ O
is -X- _ O
getting -X- _ O
shorter -X- _ O
right -X- _ O
now -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
" -X- _ O
Anton -X- _ B-Person
explains -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
while -X- _ O
watching -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
drone -X- _ B-MilitaryPlatform
flying -X- _ O
overhead. -X- _ O
" -X- _ O
Our -X- _ O
connection -X- _ O
has -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
be -X- _ O
stronger -X- _ O
than -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
jamming -X- _ O

" -X- _ O
Image -X- _ O
caption -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
Anton -X- _ B-Person
( -X- _ O
R -X- _ O
) -X- _ O
used -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
be -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
drone -X- _ B-MilitaryPlatform
operator -X- _ O
for -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
travel -X- _ O
company -X- _ O
- -X- _ O
now -X- _ O
he -X- _ O
teaches -X- _ O
soldiers -X- _ B-MilitaryPlatform
how -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
fly -X- _ O
drones -X- _ B-MilitaryPlatform
and -X- _ O
avoid -X- _ O
being -X- _ O
caughtRussian -X- _ O
intelligence -X- _ O
services -X- _ O
have -X- _ O
also -X- _ O
moved -X- _ O
some -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
their -X- _ O
cyber-teams -X- _ O
close -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
front -X- _ O
lines -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
according -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
Mr -X- _ B-Person
Vitiuk. -X- _ I-Person
This -X- _ O
is -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
communicate -X- _ O
faster -X- _ O
with -X- _ O
the -X- _ B-Organisation
military -X- _ I-Organisation
and -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
quickly -X- _ O
provide -X- _ O
direct -X- _ O
access -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
captured -X- _ O
Ukrainian -X- _ O
devices -X- _ O
or -X- _ O
nearby -X- _ O
communications. -X- _ O
A -X- _ O
captured -X- _ O
device -X- _ O
can -X- _ O
then -X- _ O
be -X- _ O
used -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
gather -X- _ O
more -X- _ O
tactical -X- _ O
intelligence -X- _ O
before -X- _ O
people -X- _ O
realise -X- _ O
it -X- _ O
is -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
Russian -X- _ O
hands -X- _ O

The -X- _ O
cyber-conflict -X- _ O
was -X- _ O
tightly -X- _ O
bound -X- _ O
with -X- _ O
military -X- _ O
operations -X- _ O
even -X- _ O
before -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
full-scale -X- _ O
invasion -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
February -X- _ B-Temporal
2022. -X- _ I-Temporal
A -X- _ O
month -X- _ O
earlier -X- _ O
Russia -X- _ B-Location
tried -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
cause -X- _ O
public -X- _ O
panic -X- _ O
by -X- _ O
taking -X- _ O
public -X- _ O
websites -X- _ O
offline -X- _ O

" -X- _ O
It -X- _ O
was -X- _ O
definitely -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
psychological -X- _ O
operation -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
" -X- _ O
says -X- _ O
Mr -X- _ B-Person
Vitiuk. -X- _ I-Person
Ukraine -X- _ B-Location
was -X- _ O
able -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
recover -X- _ O
most -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
systems -X- _ O
but -X- _ O
hours -X- _ O
before -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
invasion -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
new -X- _ O
wave -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
cyber-attacks -X- _ O
began. -X- _ O
The -X- _ O
most -X- _ O
effective -X- _ O
took -X- _ O
down -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
US -X- _ B-Organisation
satellite -X- _ O
provider -X- _ O
used -X- _ O
by -X- _ O
Ukraine -X- _ B-Organisation
's -X- _ I-Organisation
military -X- _ I-Organisation
for -X- _ O
communications -X- _ O
for -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
few -X- _ O
hours -X- _ O
. -X- _ O

As -X- _ O
Russia -X- _ B-Location
's -X- _ I-Location
plans -X- _ O
for -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
quick -X- _ O
victory -X- _ O
were -X- _ O
dashed -X- _ O
and -X- _ O
reports -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
atrocities -X- _ O
emerged -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
importance -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
controlling -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
information -X- _ O
flow -X- _ O
increased. -X- _ O
That -X- _ O
was -X- _ O
highlighted -X- _ O
on -X- _ O
1 -X- _ B-Temporal
March -X- _ I-Temporal
2022 -X- _ I-Temporal
when -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
combined -X- _ B-Weapon
cyber -X- _ I-Weapon
and -X- _ I-Weapon
missile -X- _ I-Weapon
strike -X- _ I-Weapon
targeted -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
TV -X- _ O
tower -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
Kyiv -X- _ B-Location

" -X- _ O
They -X- _ O
were -X- _ O
trying -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
deprive -X- _ O
Ukrainians -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
access -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
truthful -X- _ O
information -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
" -X- _ O
Yurii -X- _ B-Person
Shchyhol -X- _ I-Person
, -X- _ O
head -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
state -X- _ O
service -X- _ O
that -X- _ O
protects -X- _ O
communications -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
explains -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
standing -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
front -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
tower -X- _ O
where -X- _ O
black -X- _ O
scars -X- _ O
from -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
missile -X- _ B-Weapon
strike -X- _ O
are -X- _ O
still -X- _ O
evident. -X- _ O
Engineers -X- _ O
scoured -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
city -X- _ O
for -X- _ O
replacement -X- _ O
equipment -X- _ O
and -X- _ O
within -X- _ O
hours -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
TV -X- _ O
broadcasting -X- _ O
was -X- _ O
restored. -X- _ O
Image -X- _ O
caption -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
Kyiv -X- _ B-Location
's -X- _ I-Location
main -X- _ O
TV -X- _ O
tower -X- _ O
was -X- _ O
targeted -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
missile -X- _ B-Weapon
strike -X- _ O
early -X- _ O
on -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
warMissiles -X- _ B-Weapon
also -X- _ O
struck -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
data -X- _ O
centre -X- _ O
at -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
same -X- _ O
location -X- _ O
- -X- _ O
but -X- _ O
vital -X- _ O
data -X- _ O
had -X- _ O
been -X- _ O
moved -X- _ O
on -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
remote -X- _ O
servers -X- _ O
earlier -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
year -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
with -X- _ O
help -X- _ O
from -X- _ O
Western -X- _ B-Organisation
technology -X- _ I-Organisation
companies -X- _ I-Organisation
. -X- _ O

" -X- _ O
The -X- _ O
fact -X- _ O
that -X- _ O
Ukraine -X- _ B-Location
managed -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
withstand -X- _ O
this -X- _ O
war -X- _ O
is -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
achievement -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
both -X- _ O
our -X- _ O
specialists -X- _ O
who -X- _ O
built -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
system -X- _ O
and -X- _ O
thanks -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
help -X- _ O
from -X- _ O
our -X- _ O
partners -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
" -X- _ O
says -X- _ O
Mr -X- _ B-Person
Shchyhol -X- _ I-Person
. -X- _ O

Ukraine -X- _ B-Location
's -X- _ I-Location
own -X- _ O
tech -X- _ O
workers -X- _ O
have -X- _ O
also -X- _ O
aided -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
war -X- _ O
effort. -X- _ O
In -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
cramped -X- _ O
Kyiv -X- _ B-Location
office -X- _ I-Location
, -X- _ O
young -X- _ O
volunteers -X- _ O
explain -X- _ O
how -X- _ O
they -X- _ O
built -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
system -X- _ O
called -X- _ O
Griselda -X- _ O
that -X- _ O
scrapes -X- _ O
data -X- _ O
from -X- _ O
social -X- _ O
media -X- _ O
and -X- _ O
other -X- _ O
sources -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
provide -X- _ O
up-to-date -X- _ O
situational -X- _ O
intelligence. -X- _ O
This -X- _ O
helps -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
military -X- _ O
and -X- _ O
government -X- _ B-Organisation
answer -X- _ O
questions -X- _ O
on -X- _ O
everything -X- _ O
from -X- _ O
where -X- _ O
mines -X- _ B-Weapon
might -X- _ O
be -X- _ O
laid -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
what -X- _ O
infrastructure -X- _ O
requires -X- _ O
repairing -X- _ O
. -X- _ O

The -X- _ O
missiles -X- _ B-Weapon
that -X- _ O
hit -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
TV -X- _ O
tower -X- _ O
and -X- _ O
data -X- _ O
centre -X- _ O
were -X- _ O
also -X- _ O
accompanied -X- _ O
by -X- _ O
cyber-attacks. -X- _ O
And -X- _ O
since -X- _ O
then -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
cyber -X- _ O
and -X- _ O
missile -X- _ B-Weapon
attacks -X- _ O
have -X- _ O
often -X- _ O
been -X- _ O
used -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
tandem. -X- _ O
The -X- _ O
cyber-onslaught -X- _ O
remains -X- _ O
relentless -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
explains -X- _ O
Victor -X- _ B-Person
Zhora -X- _ I-Person
, -X- _ O
who -X- _ O
oversees -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
country -X- _ O
's -X- _ O
cyber-defence -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
as -X- _ O
he -X- _ O
gives -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
tour -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
Ukraine -X- _ B-Person
's -X- _ I-Person
incident -X- _ O
response -X- _ O
facility -X- _ O
which -X- _ O
runs -X- _ O
24 -X- _ O
/ -X- _ O
7. -X- _ O
" -X- _ O
This -X- _ O
is -X- _ O
where -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
heart -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
Ukrainian -X- _ O
cyber-protection -X- _ O
beats -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
" -X- _ O
he -X- _ O
says. -X- _ O
" -X- _ O
It -X- _ O
is -X- _ O
always -X- _ O
busy. -X- _ O
" -X- _ O
A -X- _ O
screen -X- _ O
on -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
wall -X- _ O
shows -X- _ O
peaks -X- _ O
and -X- _ O
troughs -X- _ O
since -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
start -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
war. -X- _ O
The -X- _ O
government -X- _ B-Organisation
is -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
top -X- _ O
target. -X- _ O
While -X- _ O
we -X- _ O
are -X- _ O
at -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
office -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
young -X- _ O
staffers -X- _ O
are -X- _ O
dealing -X- _ O
with -X- _ O
an -X- _ O
attack -X- _ O
on -X- _ O
the -X- _ B-Person
National -X- _ I-Person
Office -X- _ I-Person
of -X- _ I-Person
Statistics -X- _ I-Person
which -X- _ O
delays -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
release -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
inflation -X- _ O
figures. -X- _ O
BBCThis -X- _ O
is -X- _ O
where -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
heart -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
Ukrainian -X- _ O
cyber -X- _ O
protection -X- _ O
beats. -X- _ O
We -X- _ O
do -X- _ O
n't -X- _ O
have -X- _ O
days -X- _ O
offVictor -X- _ O
ZhoraOversees -X- _ O
Ukraine -X- _ B-Location
's -X- _ I-Location
cyber-defenceAt -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
Security -X- _ O
Service -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
Illia -X- _ B-Person
Vitiuk -X- _ I-Person
's -X- _ I-Person
cyber-team -X- _ O
works -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
counter -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
elite -X- _ O
hackers -X- _ O
from -X- _ O
Russia -X- _ B-Location
's -X- _ I-Location
spy -X- _ O
services -X- _ O
by -X- _ O
getting -X- _ O
his -X- _ O
hackers -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
penetrate -X- _ O
their -X- _ O
computer -X- _ O
systems -X- _ O
and -X- _ O
listen -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
their -X- _ O
phone -X- _ O
calls -X- _ O
. -X- _ O

" -X- _ O
I -X- _ O
always -X- _ O
say -X- _ O
that -X- _ O
Ukraine -X- _ B-Location
has -X- _ O
debunked -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
myth -X- _ O
about -X- _ O
mighty -X- _ O
Russian -X- _ O
hackers -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
" -X- _ O
he -X- _ O
says -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
comparing -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
struggle -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
two -X- _ O
closely -X- _ O
matched -X- _ O
fighters -X- _ O
who -X- _ O
know -X- _ O
each -X- _ O
other -X- _ O
well -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
slugging -X- _ O
it -X- _ O
out -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
ring. -X- _ O
It -X- _ O
has -X- _ O
not -X- _ O
been -X- _ O
easy -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
he -X- _ O
adds -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
and -X- _ O
there -X- _ O
have -X- _ O
been -X- _ O
close -X- _ O
calls. -X- _ O
But -X- _ O
Ukraine -X- _ B-Location
, -X- _ O
he -X- _ O
argues -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
is -X- _ O
digesting -X- _ O
Russian -X- _ O
cyber-attacks -X- _ O
by -X- _ O
working -X- _ O
them -X- _ O
through -X- _ O
its -X- _ O
system -X- _ O
. -X- _ O

Moscow -X- _ B-Location
is -X- _ O
throwing -X- _ O
almost -X- _ O
all -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
its -X- _ O
cyber-expertise -X- _ O
against -X- _ O
Ukraine -X- _ B-Location
and -X- _ O
that -X- _ O
leaves -X- _ O
it -X- _ O
with -X- _ O
little -X- _ O
capacity -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
attack -X- _ O
Western -X- _ O
targets. -X- _ O
If -X- _ O
Ukraine -X- _ B-Location
falls -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
Mr -X- _ B-Person
Vitiuk -X- _ I-Person
warns -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
then -X- _ O
those -X- _ O
attacks -X- _ O
will -X- _ O
be -X- _ O
directed -X- _ O
elsewhere -X- _ O
. -X- _ O

But -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
battling -X- _ O
their -X- _ O
Russian -X- _ O
adversary -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
Ukraine -X- _ B-Location
and -X- _ O
other -X- _ O
allies -X- _ O
are -X- _ O
also -X- _ O
learning -X- _ O
new -X- _ O
ways -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
which -X- _ O
technology -X- _ O
can -X- _ O
be -X- _ O
integrated -X- _ O
into -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
modern -X- _ O
battlefield -X- _ O
. -X- _ O

Ukrainian -X- _ B-Person
generals -X- _ I-Person
claim -X- _ O
they -X- _ O
have -X- _ O
breached -X- _ O
Russia -X- _ B-Location
's -X- _ I-Location
formidable -X- _ O
first -X- _ O
line -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
defences -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
south -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
as -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
counter-offensive -X- _ O
launched -X- _ O
earlier -X- _ O
this -X- _ O
summer -X- _ O
may -X- _ O
be -X- _ O
poised -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
gather -X- _ O
pace -X- _ O
. -X- _ O

Since -X- _ O
June -X- _ B-Temporal
, -X- _ O
Kyiv -X- _ B-Location
's -X- _ I-Location
territorial -X- _ O
gains -X- _ O
have -X- _ O
been -X- _ O
very -X- _ O
small -X- _ O
- -X- _ O
but -X- _ O
is -X- _ O
Ukraine -X- _ B-Location
finally -X- _ O
at -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
turning -X- _ O
point -X- _ O
? -X- _ O

" -X- _ O
Yes -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
it -X- _ O
's -X- _ O
true -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
" -X- _ O
says -X- _ O
Yuriy -X- _ B-Person
Sak -X- _ I-Person
, -X- _ O
an -X- _ O
advisor -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
Ukraine -X- _ B-Person
's -X- _ I-Person
defence -X- _ I-Person
minister -X- _ I-Person
, -X- _ O
when -X- _ O
asked -X- _ O
if -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
breach -X- _ O
had -X- _ O
happened. -X- _ O
" -X- _ O
Little -X- _ O
by -X- _ O
little -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
I -X- _ O
think -X- _ O
we -X- _ O
're -X- _ O
gaining -X- _ O
momentum -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
" -X- _ O
he -X- _ O
said -X- _ O

" -X- _ O
We -X- _ O
are -X- _ O
now -X- _ O
between -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
first -X- _ O
and -X- _ O
second -X- _ O
defensive -X- _ O
lines -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
" -X- _ O
one -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
Ukraine -X- _ B-Location
's -X- _ I-Location
top -X- _ B-Person
generals -X- _ I-Person
in -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
south -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
Brig -X- _ B-Person
Gen -X- _ I-Person
Oleksandr -X- _ I-Person
Tarnavskiy -X- _ I-Person
told -X- _ O
Britain -X- _ B-Organisation
's -X- _ I-Organisation
Observer -X- _ I-Organisation
newspaper. -X- _ I-Organisation
His -X- _ O
words -X- _ O
echoed -X- _ O
those -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
the -X- _ B-Organisation
White -X- _ I-Organisation
House -X- _ I-Organisation
spokesman -X- _ O
John -X- _ B-Person
Kirby -X- _ I-Person
, -X- _ O
who -X- _ O
on -X- _ O
Friday -X- _ B-Temporal
told -X- _ O
reporters -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
Washington -X- _ B-Location
that -X- _ O
Ukrainian -X- _ B-Organisation
forces -X- _ I-Organisation
had -X- _ O
" -X- _ O
achieved -X- _ O
some -X- _ O
success -X- _ O
against -X- _ O
that -X- _ O
second -X- _ O
line. -X- _ O
" -X- _ O
The -X- _ O
focus -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
Ukraine -X- _ B-MilitaryPlatform
's -X- _ I-MilitaryPlatform
counter-offensive -X- _ I-MilitaryPlatform
effort -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
recent -X- _ O
weeks -X- _ O
has -X- _ O
been -X- _ O
an -X- _ O
expanding -X- _ O
bridgehead -X- _ O
around -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
tiny -X- _ O
village -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
Robotyne -X- _ B-Location
, -X- _ O
some -X- _ O
56km -X- _ O
( -X- _ O
35 -X- _ O
miles -X- _ O
) -X- _ O
south-east -X- _ B-Location
of -X- _ I-Location
the -X- _ I-Location
city -X- _ I-Location
of -X- _ I-Location
Zaporizhzhia -X- _ I-Location
. -X- _ O

Ukrainian -X- _ B-Organisation
forces -X- _ I-Organisation
raised -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
country -X- _ O
's -X- _ O
blue -X- _ O
and -X- _ O
yellow -X- _ O
flag -X- _ O
over -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
village -X- _ O
more -X- _ O
than -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
week -X- _ O
ago -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
and -X- _ O
are -X- _ O
now -X- _ O
trying -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
widen -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
gap -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
allow -X- _ O
larger -X- _ O
infantry -X- _ B-MilitaryPlatform
and -X- _ O
armoured -X- _ B-Weapon
units -X- _ I-Weapon
to -X- _ O
pass -X- _ O
through -X- _ O
without -X- _ O
coming -X- _ O
under -X- _ O
Russian -X- _ O
fire -X- _ O
. -X- _ O

A -X- _ O
glance -X- _ O
at -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
map -X- _ O
shows -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
mass -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
overlapping -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
complex -X- _ O
Russian -X- _ O
defensive -X- _ O
lines -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
complete -X- _ O
with -X- _ O
minefields -X- _ B-MilitaryPlatform
, -X- _ O
tank -X- _ B-MilitaryPlatform
traps -X- _ I-MilitaryPlatform
and -X- _ O
trenches. -X- _ B-MilitaryPlatform
Some -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
them -X- _ O
converge -X- _ O
at -X- _ O
Verbove -X- _ B-Location
. -X- _ O

Without -X- _ O
air -X- _ O
cover -X- _ O
and -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
face -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
sometimes -X- _ O
withering -X- _ O
Russian -X- _ B-MilitaryPlatform
artillery -X- _ I-MilitaryPlatform
fire -X- _ I-MilitaryPlatform
, -X- _ O
small -X- _ O
Ukrainian -X- _ B-MilitaryPlatform
units -X- _ I-MilitaryPlatform
have -X- _ O
been -X- _ O
clearing -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
way -X- _ O
through -X- _ O
these -X- _ O
hazards -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
preparing -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
ground -X- _ O
for -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
larger -X- _ O
assault. -X- _ O
" -X- _ O
When -X- _ O
these -X- _ O
openings -X- _ O
appear -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
course -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
it -X- _ O
makes -X- _ O
it -X- _ O
easier -X- _ O
for -X- _ O
our -X- _ O
forces -X- _ B-Organisation
to -X- _ O
advance -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
" -X- _ O
Mr -X- _ B-Person
Sak -X- _ I-Person
said -X- _ O

The -X- _ O
fog -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
warIt -X- _ O
is -X- _ O
hard -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
assess -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
significance -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
latest -X- _ O
claims. -X- _ O
Ukrainian -X- _ O
officials -X- _ O
are -X- _ O
extremely -X- _ O
tight-lipped -X- _ O
when -X- _ O
asked -X- _ O
for -X- _ O
precise -X- _ O
details -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
preferring -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
allow -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
fog -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
war -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
shroud -X- _ O
Kyiv -X- _ B-Location
's -X- _ I-Location
intentions -X- _ O
and -X- _ O
extremely -X- _ O
reluctant -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
avoid -X- _ O
releasing -X- _ O
sensitive -X- _ O
information. -X- _ O
It -X- _ O
does -X- _ O
not -X- _ O
help -X- _ O
that -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
forces -X- _ B-MilitaryPlatform
closest -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
fight -X- _ O
sometimes -X- _ O
give -X- _ O
very -X- _ O
different -X- _ O
accounts -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
what -X- _ O
is -X- _ O
happening -X- _ O
at -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
front. -X- _ O
Approached -X- _ O
by -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
BBC -X- _ B-Organisation
on -X- _ O
Saturday -X- _ B-Temporal
, -X- _ O
Ukraine -X- _ B-MilitaryPlatform
's -X- _ I-MilitaryPlatform
46th -X- _ I-MilitaryPlatform
Air -X- _ I-MilitaryPlatform
Assault -X- _ I-MilitaryPlatform
Brigade -X- _ I-MilitaryPlatform
said -X- _ O
fighting -X- _ O
was -X- _ O
continuing -X- _ O
near -X- _ O
Russia -X- _ B-Location
's -X- _ I-Location
first -X- _ O
line -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
defence -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
but -X- _ O
that -X- _ O
" -X- _ O
no -X- _ O
one -X- _ O
has -X- _ O
yet -X- _ O
managed -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
go -X- _ O
beyond -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
first -X- _ O
line. -X- _ O
" -X- _ O
This -X- _ O
may -X- _ O
be -X- _ O
less -X- _ O
surprising -X- _ O
than -X- _ O
it -X- _ O
sounds. -X- _ O
A -X- _ O
plethora -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
units -X- _ O
are -X- _ O
operating -X- _ O
up -X- _ O
and -X- _ O
down -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
front -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
each -X- _ O
concentrating -X- _ O
on -X- _ O
their -X- _ O
own -X- _ O
narrow -X- _ O
section -X- _ O
and -X- _ O
specific -X- _ O
tasks. -X- _ O
They -X- _ O
do -X- _ O
not -X- _ O
necessarily -X- _ O
know -X- _ O
what -X- _ O
is -X- _ O
going -X- _ O
on -X- _ O
elsewhere. -X- _ O
Image -X- _ O
source -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
ReutersImage -X- _ O
caption -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
A -X- _ O
Ukrainian -X- _ O
serviceman -X- _ O
looks -X- _ O
at -X- _ O
a -X- _ B-MilitaryPlatform
destroyed -X- _ I-MilitaryPlatform
Ukrainian -X- _ I-MilitaryPlatform
tank -X- _ I-MilitaryPlatform
near -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
village -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
RobotyneOne -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
those -X- _ O
units -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
volunteer -X- _ B-MilitaryPlatform
battalion -X- _ I-MilitaryPlatform
known -X- _ O
by -X- _ O
its -X- _ O
commander -X- _ O
's -X- _ O
call -X- _ O
sign -X- _ O
" -X- _ O
Skala -X- _ B-Person
" -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
told -X- _ O
Reuters -X- _ B-Organisation
news -X- _ I-Organisation
agency -X- _ I-Organisation
that -X- _ O
its -X- _ O
men -X- _ O
had -X- _ O
broken -X- _ O
through -X- _ O
Russia -X- _ B-Location
's -X- _ I-Location
first -X- _ O
line -X- _ O
on -X- _ O
26 -X- _ B-Temporal
August -X- _ I-Temporal

On -X- _ O
Sunday -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
Skala -X- _ B-Person
told -X- _ O
us -X- _ O
his -X- _ O
men -X- _ O
were -X- _ O
still -X- _ O
pushing -X- _ O
forward -X- _ O
. -X- _ O

" -X- _ O
Literally -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
we -X- _ O
are -X- _ O
moving -X- _ O
along -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
Zaporizhzhia -X- _ B-Location
region -X- _ I-Location
to -X- _ O
the -X- _ B-Location
sea -X- _ I-Location
, -X- _ O
" -X- _ O
he -X- _ O
said -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
voice -X- _ O
message -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
without -X- _ O
giving -X- _ O
further -X- _ O
details -X- _ O
. -X- _ O

" -X- _ O
I -X- _ O
do -X- _ O
n't -X- _ O
want -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
rush -X- _ O
ahead -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
but -X- _ O
both -X- _ O
we -X- _ O
and -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
General -X- _ B-Organisation
Staff -X- _ I-Organisation
are -X- _ O
doing -X- _ O
everything -X- _ O
for -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
fastest -X- _ O
victory -X- _ O
. -X- _ O

" -X- _ O
Hard -X- _ O
as -X- _ O
it -X- _ O
is -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
gauge -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
precise -X- _ O
nature -X- _ O
and -X- _ O
direction -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
Ukraine -X- _ B-Location
's -X- _ I-Location
recent -X- _ O
gains -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
it -X- _ O
is -X- _ O
clear -X- _ O
that -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
Kremlin -X- _ B-Organisation
is -X- _ O
alarmed -X- _ O
. -X- _ O

It -X- _ O
has -X- _ O
recently -X- _ O
sent -X- _ O
elite -X- _ B-MilitaryPlatform
troops -X- _ I-MilitaryPlatform
from -X- _ O
other -X- _ O
parts -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
long -X- _ O
front -X- _ O
line -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
bolster -X- _ O
defences -X- _ O
between -X- _ O
Robotyne -X- _ B-Location
and -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
key -X- _ O
road -X- _ O
and -X- _ O
railway -X- _ O
hub -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
Tokmak -X- _ B-Location
, -X- _ O
21km -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
south -X- _ O
. -X- _ O

According -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
the -X- _ B-Location
Washington-based -X- _ I-Location
Institute -X- _ B-Organisation
for -X- _ I-Organisation
the -X- _ I-Organisation
Study -X- _ I-Organisation
of -X- _ I-Organisation
War -X- _ I-Organisation
( -X- _ I-Organisation
ISW -X- _ I-Organisation
) -X- _ I-Organisation
, -X- _ I-Organisation
this -X- _ O
is -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
third -X- _ O
time -X- _ O
since -X- _ O
June -X- _ B-Temporal
. -X- _ O

" -X- _ O
The -X- _ O
second -X- _ O
lateral -X- _ O
deployment -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
span -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
few -X- _ O
weeks -X- _ O
suggests -X- _ O
an -X- _ O
increasing -X- _ O
Russian -X- _ O
concern -X- _ O
about -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
stability -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
Russian -X- _ B-MilitaryPlatform
defences -X- _ I-MilitaryPlatform
, -X- _ O
" -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
ISW -X- _ B-Organisation
reported -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
its -X- _ O
assessment -X- _ O
on -X- _ O
1 -X- _ B-Temporal
September -X- _ I-Temporal

This -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
Ukrainian -X- _ O
experts -X- _ O
claim -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
is -X- _ O
part -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
Kyiv -X- _ B-Location
's -X- _ I-Location
plan -X- _ O
: -X- _ O
forcing -X- _ O
Moscow -X- _ B-Person
to -X- _ O
move -X- _ O
front -X- _ O
line -X- _ O
units -X- _ O
from -X- _ O
one -X- _ O
place -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
another -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
an -X- _ O
effort -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
wear -X- _ O
them -X- _ O
down -X- _ O
. -X- _ O

" -X- _ O
We -X- _ O
're -X- _ O
trying -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
involve -X- _ O
their -X- _ O
reserves -X- _ O
and -X- _ O
exhaust -X- _ O
them -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
" -X- _ O
says -X- _ O
Serhiy -X- _ B-Person
Kuzan -X- _ I-Person
, -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
the -X- _ B-Organisation
Ukrainian -X- _ I-Organisation
Security -X- _ I-Organisation
and -X- _ I-Organisation
Cooperation -X- _ I-Organisation
Centre -X- _ I-Organisation
, -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
Kyiv -X- _ B-Organisation
think -X- _ I-Organisation
tank -X- _ I-Organisation
with -X- _ O
close -X- _ O
ties -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
the -X- _ B-Organisation
military -X- _ I-Organisation
. -X- _ O

The -X- _ O
next -X- _ O
job -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
he -X- _ O
says -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
is -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
exploit -X- _ O
any -X- _ O
sign -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
Russian -X- _ O
weakness -X- _ O
. -X- _ O

" -X- _ O
The -X- _ O
main -X- _ O
thing -X- _ O
is -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
widen -X- _ O
this -X- _ O
bridgehead -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
" -X- _ O
he -X- _ O
says. -X- _ O
" -X- _ O
There -X- _ O
wo -X- _ O
n't -X- _ O
be -X- _ O
any -X- _ O
orders -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
go -X- _ O
deeper -X- _ O
until -X- _ O
we -X- _ O
do -X- _ O
that -X- _ O
. -X- _ O

" -X- _ O
Despite -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
apparently -X- _ O
glacial -X- _ O
progress -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
offensive -X- _ O
since -X- _ O
June -X- _ B-Temporal
, -X- _ O
Mr -X- _ B-Person
Kuzan -X- _ I-Person
says -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
fundamental -X- _ O
objective -X- _ O
has -X- _ O
not -X- _ O
changed -X- _ O
: -X- _ O
control -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
south -X- _ O
. -X- _ O

What -X- _ O
that -X- _ O
looks -X- _ O
like -X- _ O
by -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
time -X- _ O
winter -X- _ O
arrives -X- _ O
is -X- _ O
an -X- _ O
open -X- _ O
question -X- _ O
. -X- _ O

Ideally -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
Kyiv -X- _ B-Location
would -X- _ O
like -X- _ O
its -X- _ O
forces -X- _ B-MilitaryPlatform
to -X- _ O
have -X- _ O
reached -X- _ O
the -X- _ B-Location
Sea -X- _ I-Location
of -X- _ I-Location
Azov -X- _ I-Location
, -X- _ O
cutting -X- _ O
through -X- _ O
Moscow -X- _ B-Location
's -X- _ I-Location
" -X- _ O
land -X- _ O
bridge -X- _ O
" -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
the -X- _ B-Location
Crimean -X- _ I-Location
Peninsula -X- _ I-Location
. -X- _ O

But -X- _ O
even -X- _ O
if -X- _ O
this -X- _ O
does -X- _ O
not -X- _ O
happen -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
Ukraine -X- _ B-Location
is -X- _ O
determined -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
cut -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
supply -X- _ O
lines -X- _ O
that -X- _ O
allow -X- _ O
Russian -X- _ B-Organisation
forces -X- _ I-Organisation
to -X- _ O
maintain -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
presence -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
southern -X- _ O
part -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
the -X- _ B-MilitaryPlatform
Kherson -X- _ I-MilitaryPlatform
region -X- _ I-MilitaryPlatform
, -X- _ O
between -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
Dnipro -X- _ B-Location
river -X- _ I-Location
and -X- _ O
Crimea -X- _ B-Location

Some -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
those -X- _ O
links -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
including -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
railway -X- _ O
that -X- _ O
passes -X- _ O
through -X- _ O
Tokmak -X- _ B-Location
, -X- _ O
are -X- _ O
already -X- _ O
highly -X- _ O
vulnerable -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
Ukrainian -X- _ O
long -X- _ B-Weapon
range -X- _ I-Weapon
weapons -X- _ I-Weapon
, -X- _ O
such -X- _ O
as -X- _ O
the -X- _ B-Weapon
Himars -X- _ I-Weapon
multiple -X- _ I-Weapon
rocket -X- _ I-Weapon
launcher -X- _ I-Weapon
. -X- _ O

With -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
other -X- _ O
key -X- _ O
rail -X- _ O
link -X- _ O
- -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
one -X- _ O
across -X- _ O
the -X- _ B-Location
Kerch -X- _ I-Location
Bridge -X- _ I-Location
- -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
target -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
repeated -X- _ O
Ukrainian -X- _ O
attacks -X- _ O
since -X- _ O
last -X- _ O
October -X- _ B-Temporal
, -X- _ O
Mr -X- _ B-Person
Kuzan -X- _ I-Person
says -X- _ O
Russia -X- _ B-Location
is -X- _ O
transporting -X- _ O
70 -X- _ O
% -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
its -X- _ O
supplies -X- _ O
along -X- _ O
the -X- _ B-Location
M-14 -X- _ I-Location
highway -X- _ I-Location
, -X- _ O
which -X- _ O
runs -X- _ O
closer -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
coast -X- _ O
. -X- _ O

" -X- _ O
We -X- _ O
have -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
get -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
land -X- _ O
route -X- _ O
under -X- _ O
fire -X- _ O
control -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
" -X- _ O
he -X- _ O
says -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
meaning -X- _ O
that -X- _ O
Ukrainian -X- _ O
guns -X- _ O
need -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
be -X- _ O
close -X- _ O
enough -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
be -X- _ O
able -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
target -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
road -X- _ O
. -X- _ O

That -X- _ O
's -X- _ O
still -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
distant -X- _ O
goal. -X- _ O
The -X- _ B-Location
M-14 -X- _ I-Location
is -X- _ O
still -X- _ O
more -X- _ O
than -X- _ O
80km -X- _ O
away. -X- _ O
There -X- _ O
are -X- _ O
multiple -X- _ O
Russian -X- _ O
lines -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
defence -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
and -X- _ O
Ukrainian -X- _ B-Organisation
forces -X- _ I-Organisation
will -X- _ O
be -X- _ O
attacked -X- _ O
from -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
ground -X- _ O
and -X- _ O
air -X- _ O
every -X- _ O
step -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
way -X- _ O
. -X- _ O

Another -X- _ O
glance -X- _ O
at -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
map -X- _ O
shows -X- _ O
that -X- _ O
Ukraine -X- _ B-Location
's -X- _ I-Location
territorial -X- _ O
gains -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
since -X- _ O
June -X- _ B-Temporal
, -X- _ O
have -X- _ O
been -X- _ O
tiny -X- _ O
. -X- _ O

Kyiv -X- _ B-Location
's -X- _ I-Location
first -X- _ O
encounter -X- _ O
with -X- _ O
Russia -X- _ B-Location
's -X- _ I-Location
well-entrenched -X- _ O
defences -X- _ O
was -X- _ O
always -X- _ O
going -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
be -X- _ O
among -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
hardest -X- _ O
phases. -X- _ O
It -X- _ O
may -X- _ O
be -X- _ O
some -X- _ O
time -X- _ O
before -X- _ O
we -X- _ O
know -X- _ O
if -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
breach -X- _ O
at -X- _ O
Robotyne -X- _ B-Location
represents -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
turning -X- _ O
point. -X- _ O
" -X- _ O
Tough -X- _ O
battles -X- _ O
are -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
be -X- _ O
expected -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
" -X- _ O
Mr -X- _ B-Person
Kuzan -X- _ I-Person
adds -X- _ O
. -X- _ O

Ukraine -X- _ B-Location
is -X- _ O
fighting -X- _ O
Russia -X- _ B-Location
on -X- _ O
many -X- _ O
fronts. -X- _ O
And -X- _ O
just -X- _ O
as -X- _ O
progress -X- _ O
on -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
battlefield -X- _ O
is -X- _ O
hard -X- _ O
won -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
so -X- _ O
too -X- _ O
these -X- _ O
days -X- _ O
are -X- _ O
its -X- _ O
diplomatic -X- _ O
gains. -X- _ O
Since -X- _ O
Russia -X- _ B-Location
's -X- _ I-Location
invasion -X- _ O
last -X- _ O
year -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
Western -X- _ O
support -X- _ O
for -X- _ O
Kyiv -X- _ B-Location
has -X- _ O
remained -X- _ O
largely -X- _ O
strong. -X- _ O
But -X- _ O
cracks -X- _ O
are -X- _ O
beginning -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
form -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
the -X- _ B-Organisation
pro-Ukraine -X- _ I-Organisation
alliance. -X- _ I-Organisation
The -X- _ B-Location
United -X- _ I-Location
States -X- _ I-Location
is -X- _ O
Ukraine -X- _ B-Location
's -X- _ I-Location
greatest -X- _ O
supporter -X- _ O
by -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
long -X- _ O
way -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
allocating -X- _ O
more -X- _ O
than -X- _ O
$ -X- _ B-Money
110bn -X- _ I-Money
( -X- _ O
90bn -X- _ B-Money
) -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
military -X- _ O
and -X- _ O
economic -X- _ O
support. -X- _ O
Yet -X- _ O
over -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
weekend -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
Congress -X- _ B-Organisation
ditched -X- _ O
plans -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
give -X- _ O
Ukraine -X- _ B-Location
another -X- _ O
$ -X- _ B-Money
6bn -X- _ I-Money
in -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
bitter -X- _ O
internal -X- _ O
battle -X- _ O
over -X- _ O
how -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
fund -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
federal -X- _ O
government. -X- _ B-Organisation
Some -X- _ O
Republicans -X- _ O
think -X- _ O
support -X- _ O
for -X- _ O
Ukraine -X- _ B-Location
should -X- _ O
be -X- _ O
curbed -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
others -X- _ O
think -X- _ O
it -X- _ O
should -X- _ O
be -X- _ O
provided -X- _ O
only -X- _ O
if -X- _ O
President -X- _ B-Person
Biden -X- _ I-Person
spends -X- _ O
more -X- _ O
on -X- _ O
US -X- _ B-Organisation
border -X- _ I-Organisation
security. -X- _ I-Organisation
Mr -X- _ B-Person
Biden -X- _ I-Person
has -X- _ O
promised -X- _ O
Ukraine -X- _ B-Location
another -X- _ O
$ -X- _ B-Money
24bn -X- _ I-Money
soon -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
but -X- _ O
that -X- _ O
may -X- _ O
now -X- _ O
be -X- _ O
vulnerable -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
internal -X- _ O
US -X- _ B-Organisation
politics. -X- _ O
On -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
other -X- _ O
side -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
the -X- _ B-Location
Atlantic -X- _ I-Location
, -X- _ O
Ukraine -X- _ B-Location
may -X- _ O
be -X- _ O
about -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
lose -X- _ O
another -X- _ O
ally -X- _ O
. -X- _ O

In -X- _ O
Slovakia -X- _ B-Location
, -X- _ O
elections -X- _ O
saw -X- _ O
Robert -X- _ B-Person
Fico -X- _ I-Person
's -X- _ I-Person
Smer -X- _ O
party -X- _ O
win -X- _ O
most -X- _ O
seats -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
although -X- _ O
he -X- _ O
still -X- _ O
needs -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
form -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
coalition. -X- _ O
The -X- _ O
populist -X- _ O
former -X- _ O
prime -X- _ O
minister -X- _ O
is -X- _ O
widely -X- _ O
seen -X- _ O
as -X- _ O
pro-Moscow -X- _ O
and -X- _ O
anti-Kyiv -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
having -X- _ O
campaigned -X- _ O
on -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
promise -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
end -X- _ O
military -X- _ O
support -X- _ O
for -X- _ O
Ukraine. -X- _ B-Location
" -X- _ O
People -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
Slovakia -X- _ B-Location
have -X- _ O
bigger -X- _ O
problems -X- _ O
than -X- _ O
Ukraine -X- _ B-Location
, -X- _ O
" -X- _ O
he -X- _ O
said. -X- _ O
That -X- _ O
means -X- _ O
- -X- _ O
alongside -X- _ O
Viktor -X- _ B-Person
Orban -X- _ I-Person
's -X- _ I-Person
Hungary -X- _ B-Location
- -X- _ O
there -X- _ O
are -X- _ O
now -X- _ O
two -X- _ O
European -X- _ B-Organisation
Union -X- _ I-Organisation
countries -X- _ O
ready -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
veto -X- _ O
further -X- _ O
collective -X- _ O
EU -X- _ B-Organisation
action -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
support -X- _ O
Ukraine -X- _ B-Location

Neighbouring -X- _ O
Poland -X- _ B-Location
is -X- _ O
also -X- _ O
holding -X- _ O
elections -X- _ O
soon -X- _ O
- -X- _ O
and -X- _ O
there -X- _ O
too -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
doubts -X- _ O
about -X- _ O
supporting -X- _ O
Ukraine -X- _ B-Location
have -X- _ O
been -X- _ O
aired. -X- _ O
The -X- _ O
ruling -X- _ O
Law -X- _ O
and -X- _ O
Justice -X- _ O
Party -X- _ O
has -X- _ O
promised -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
halt -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
import -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
cheap -X- _ O
Ukrainian -X- _ O
grain -X- _ O
that -X- _ O
Polish -X- _ O
farmers -X- _ O
oppose. -X- _ O
The -X- _ B-Person
President -X- _ I-Person
, -X- _ I-Person
Andrzej -X- _ I-Person
Duda -X- _ I-Person
, -X- _ O
has -X- _ O
described -X- _ O
Ukraine -X- _ B-Location
as -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
drowning -X- _ O
man -X- _ O
dragging -X- _ O
down -X- _ O
his -X- _ O
rescuers. -X- _ O
Prime -X- _ B-Person
Minister -X- _ I-Person
Mateusz -X- _ I-Person
Morawiecki -X- _ I-Person
said -X- _ O
Poland -X- _ B-Location
was -X- _ O
" -X- _ O
no -X- _ O
longer -X- _ O
transferring -X- _ O
any -X- _ O
weapons -X- _ B-Weapon
to -X- _ O
Ukraine -X- _ B-Location
" -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
although -X- _ O
this -X- _ O
was -X- _ O
later -X- _ O
reversed. -X- _ O
So -X- _ O
electoral -X- _ O
politics -X- _ O
are -X- _ O
beginning -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
bite -X- _ O
into -X- _ O
Ukraine -X- _ B-Location
's -X- _ I-Location
support. -X- _ O
So -X- _ O
too -X- _ O
are -X- _ O
other -X- _ O
issues -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
whether -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
global -X- _ O
cost-of-living -X- _ O
crisis -X- _ O
or -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
climate -X- _ O
emergency. -X- _ O
At -X- _ O
the -X- _ B-Organisation
United -X- _ I-Organisation
Nations -X- _ I-Organisation
General -X- _ I-Organisation
Assembly -X- _ I-Organisation
recently -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
it -X- _ O
was -X- _ O
noticeable -X- _ O
how -X- _ O
Ukraine -X- _ B-Location
was -X- _ O
no -X- _ O
longer -X- _ O
automatically -X- _ O
at -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
top -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
agenda. -X- _ O
President -X- _ B-Person
Volodymyr -X- _ I-Person
Zelensky -X- _ I-Person
's -X- _ I-Person
first -X- _ O
in-person -X- _ O
speeches -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
UN -X- _ B-Organisation
assembly -X- _ O
and -X- _ O
the -X- _ B-Organisation
Security -X- _ I-Organisation
Council -X- _ I-Organisation
did -X- _ O
not -X- _ O
command -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
same -X- _ O
attention -X- _ O
as -X- _ O
before. -X- _ O
Diplomats -X- _ O
noticed -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
sheen -X- _ O
had -X- _ O
come -X- _ O
off -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
Ukrainian -X- _ O
delegation -X- _ O
as -X- _ O
leaders -X- _ O
from -X- _ O
the -X- _ B-Organisation
Global -X- _ I-Organisation
South -X- _ I-Organisation
pressed -X- _ O
their -X- _ O
own -X- _ O
agendas. -X- _ O
All -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
this -X- _ O
is -X- _ O
what -X- _ O
strategists -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
Kremlin -X- _ B-Organisation
have -X- _ O
been -X- _ O
long -X- _ O
been -X- _ O
hoping -X- _ O
for. -X- _ O
Diplomats -X- _ O
believe -X- _ O
Vladimir -X- _ B-Person
Putin -X- _ I-Person
wants -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
wait -X- _ O
out -X- _ O
the -X- _ B-Organisation
West -X- _ I-Organisation
, -X- _ O
keeping -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
fighting -X- _ O
going -X- _ O
until -X- _ O
Ukraine -X- _ B-Location
begins -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
lose -X- _ O
international -X- _ O
support -X- _ O
and -X- _ O
seeks -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
political -X- _ O
settlement. -X- _ O
Western -X- _ B-Organisation
leaders -X- _ I-Organisation
insist -X- _ O
they -X- _ O
have -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
stamina -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
stay -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
course -X- _ O
and -X- _ O
show -X- _ O
more -X- _ O
strategic -X- _ O
patience -X- _ O
than -X- _ O
Russia -X- _ B-Location
expects -X- _ O
. -X- _ O

Not -X- _ O
for -X- _ O
nothing -X- _ O
did -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
UK -X- _ B-Organisation
Foreign -X- _ O
Secretary -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
James -X- _ B-Person
Cleverly -X- _ I-Person
, -X- _ O
tell -X- _ O
the -X- _ B-Organisation
House -X- _ I-Organisation
Magazine -X- _ I-Organisation
this -X- _ O
weekend -X- _ O
that -X- _ O
international -X- _ O
fatigue -X- _ O
with -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
war -X- _ O
was -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
" -X- _ O
big -X- _ O
thing -X- _ O
" -X- _ O
and -X- _ O
" -X- _ O
something -X- _ O
we -X- _ O
have -X- _ O
got -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
deal -X- _ O
with -X- _ O
" -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
acknowledging -X- _ O
it -X- _ O
was -X- _ O
" -X- _ O
putting -X- _ O
pressure -X- _ O
on -X- _ O
countries -X- _ O
all -X- _ O
over -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
world -X- _ O
" -X- _ O
. -X- _ O
His -X- _ O
counter-argument -X- _ O
was -X- _ O
that -X- _ O
if -X- _ O
Western -X- _ O
support -X- _ O
for -X- _ O
Ukraine -X- _ B-Location
diminished -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
then -X- _ O
those -X- _ O
pressures -X- _ O
- -X- _ O
whether -X- _ O
economic -X- _ O
or -X- _ O
political -X- _ O
- -X- _ O
would -X- _ O
only -X- _ O
get -X- _ O
worse -X- _ O
: -X- _ O
" -X- _ O
This -X- _ O
is -X- _ O
tough -X- _ O
and -X- _ O
this -X- _ O
is -X- _ O
painful. -X- _ O
But -X- _ O
it -X- _ O
will -X- _ O
only -X- _ O
be -X- _ O
more -X- _ O
tough -X- _ O
and -X- _ O
more -X- _ O
painful -X- _ O
if -X- _ O
we -X- _ O
falter. -X- _ O
" -X- _ O
To -X- _ O
counter -X- _ O
that -X- _ O
impression -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
EU -X- _ B-Person
foreign -X- _ I-Person
ministers -X- _ I-Person
visited -X- _ O
Kyiv -X- _ B-Location
on -X- _ O
Monday -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
meeting -X- _ O
there -X- _ O
collectively -X- _ O
for -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
first -X- _ O
time -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
demonstration -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
support. -X- _ O
Josep -X- _ B-Person
Borrell -X- _ I-Person
, -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
EU -X- _ B-Organisation
's -X- _ I-Organisation
foreign -X- _ O
policy -X- _ O
chief -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
told -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
BBC -X- _ B-Organisation
that -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
EU -X- _ B-Organisation
would -X- _ O
maintain -X- _ O
its -X- _ O
military -X- _ O
backing -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
so -X- _ O
far -X- _ O
worth -X- _ O
more -X- _ O
than -X- _ O
5bn -X- _ B-Money
( -X- _ O
4.3bn -X- _ B-Money
) -X- _ O
. -X- _ O

" -X- _ O
One -X- _ O
thing -X- _ O
is -X- _ O
clear -X- _ O
: -X- _ O
for -X- _ O
us -X- _ O
Europeans -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
war -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
Russia -X- _ B-Location
against -X- _ O
Ukraine -X- _ B-Location
is -X- _ O
an -X- _ O
existential -X- _ O
threat -X- _ O
and -X- _ O
we -X- _ O
have -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
react -X- _ O
according -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
that -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
" -X- _ O
he -X- _ O
said. -X- _ O
But -X- _ O
he -X- _ O
admitted -X- _ O
he -X- _ O
was -X- _ O
" -X- _ O
worried -X- _ O
" -X- _ O
about -X- _ O
Congress -X- _ B-Organisation
's -X- _ I-Organisation
decision -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
block -X- _ O
further -X- _ O
aid -X- _ O
. -X- _ O
