-DOCSTART- -X- O
Russian -X- _ O
troops -X- _ B-MilitaryPlatform
have -X- _ O
launched -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
major -X- _ O
offensive -X- _ O
on -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
town -X- _ B-Location
of -X- _ I-Location
Avdiivka -X- _ I-Location
in -X- _ O
eastern -X- _ O
Ukraine. -X- _ B-Location
Three -X- _ O
battalions -X- _ B-MilitaryPlatform
involving -X- _ O
some -X- _ O
2,000 -X- _ O
troops -X- _ B-MilitaryPlatform
, -X- _ O
dozens -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
armoured -X- _ O
vehicles -X- _ O
as -X- _ O
well -X- _ O
as -X- _ O
jets -X- _ O
have -X- _ O
been -X- _ O
reportedly -X- _ O
involved -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
what -X- _ O
is -X- _ O
described -X- _ O
as -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
largest-scale -X- _ O
attack -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
this -X- _ O
area. -X- _ O
The -X- _ B-Organisation
General -X- _ I-Organisation
Staff -X- _ I-Organisation
of -X- _ I-Organisation
Ukraine -X- _ I-Organisation
says -X- _ O
they -X- _ O
have -X- _ O
managed -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
repel -X- _ O
dozens -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
attacks -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
Avdiivka -X- _ B-Location
and -X- _ O
nearby -X- _ O
areas -X- _ O
since -X- _ O
Tuesday. -X- _ O
" -X- _ O
They -X- _ O
launched -X- _ O
their -X- _ O
offensive -X- _ O
on -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
wide -X- _ O
front -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
" -X- _ O
Serhiy -X- _ B-Person
Tsekhovsky -X- _ I-Person
, -X- _ O
an -X- _ O
officer -X- _ O
from -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
59th -X- _ B-Organisation
brigade -X- _ I-Organisation
, -X- _ O
told -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
BBC. -X- _ B-Organisation
" -X- _ O
Since -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
beginning -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
invasion -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
we -X- _ O
have -X- _ O
n't -X- _ O
dealt -X- _ O
with -X- _ O
such -X- _ O
an -X- _ O
intensive -X- _ O
attack -X- _ O
[ -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
area -X- _ O
near -X- _ O
Avdiivka -X- _ B-Location
] -X- _ O
. -X- _ O
They -X- _ O
are -X- _ O
using -X- _ O
multiple -X- _ O
rocket -X- _ B-MilitaryPlatform
launchers -X- _ I-MilitaryPlatform
, -X- _ O
artillery -X- _ B-MilitaryPlatform
, -X- _ O
tanks -X- _ B-MilitaryPlatform
and -X- _ O
infantry -X- _ B-MilitaryPlatform
- -X- _ O
all -X- _ O
at -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
same -X- _ O
time -X- _ O
. -X- _ O
" -X- _ O

Avdiivka -X- _ B-Location
is -X- _ O
described -X- _ O
as -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
gateway -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
city -X- _ B-Location
of -X- _ I-Location
Donetsk -X- _ I-Location
, -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
capital -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
Ukraine -X- _ B-Location
's -X- _ I-Location
eastern -X- _ I-Location
Donbas -X- _ I-Location
region. -X- _ I-Location
Although -X- _ O
Russia -X- _ B-Location
and -X- _ O
its -X- _ O
proxy -X- _ O
forces -X- _ O
have -X- _ O
occupied -X- _ O
Donetsk -X- _ B-Location
city -X- _ I-Location
since -X- _ O
2014 -X- _ B-Temporal
, -X- _ O
they -X- _ O
have -X- _ O
been -X- _ O
unable -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
use -X- _ O
its -X- _ O
resources -X- _ O
as -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
key -X- _ O
military -X- _ O
communications -X- _ O
hub -X- _ O
because -X- _ O
it -X- _ O
is -X- _ O
too -X- _ O
close -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
front -X- _ O
line. -X- _ O
By -X- _ O
capturing -X- _ O
Avdiivka -X- _ B-Location
, -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
occupying -X- _ O
force -X- _ O
could -X- _ O
push -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
front -X- _ O
line -X- _ O
away. -X- _ O
But -X- _ O
Avdiivka -X- _ B-Location
is -X- _ O
important -X- _ O
not -X- _ O
just -X- _ O
because -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
its -X- _ O
strategic -X- _ O
role. -X- _ O
This -X- _ O
town -X- _ O
has -X- _ O
been -X- _ O
right -X- _ O
on -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
front -X- _ O
line -X- _ O
since -X- _ O
Moscow -X- _ B-Location
annexed -X- _ O
Crimea -X- _ B-Location
nine -X- _ O
years -X- _ O
ago -X- _ O
and -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
conflict -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
eastern -X- _ B-Location
Ukraine -X- _ I-Location
began. -X- _ O
As -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
result -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
the -X- _ B-Location
town -X- _ I-Location
of -X- _ I-Location
Avdiivka -X- _ I-Location
has -X- _ O
turned -X- _ O
into -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
symbol -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
Ukrainian -X- _ O
resistance -X- _ O
and -X- _ O
resilience -X- _ O
. -X- _ O

Ukraine -X- _ B-Location
's -X- _ I-Location
president -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
Volodymyr -X- _ B-Person
Zelensky -X- _ I-Person
, -X- _ O
has -X- _ O
shared -X- _ O
photos -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
Avdiivka -X- _ B-Location
on -X- _ O
social -X- _ O
media -X- _ O
saying -X- _ O
: -X- _ O
" -X- _ O
We -X- _ O
are -X- _ O
holding -X- _ O
our -X- _ O
ground. -X- _ O
It -X- _ O
is -X- _ O
Ukrainian -X- _ O
courage -X- _ O
and -X- _ O
unity -X- _ O
that -X- _ O
will -X- _ O
determine -X- _ O
how -X- _ O
this -X- _ O
war -X- _ O
will -X- _ O
end -X- _ O
. -X- _ O
" -X- _ O

Military -X- _ O
positions -X- _ O
and -X- _ O
residential -X- _ O
areas -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
Avdiivka -X- _ B-Location
have -X- _ O
been -X- _ O
relentlessly -X- _ O
pummelled -X- _ O
for -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
last -X- _ O
three -X- _ O
days -X- _ O
. -X- _ O

Apartment -X- _ O
blocks -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
office -X- _ O
buildings -X- _ O
and -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
hospital -X- _ O
have -X- _ O
been -X- _ O
damaged -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
he -X- _ O
complains. -X- _ O
" -X- _ O
The -X- _ O
firing -X- _ O
does -X- _ O
n't -X- _ O
stop -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
" -X- _ O
he -X- _ O
adds. -X- _ O
" -X- _ O
There -X- _ O
were -X- _ O
about -X- _ O
20 -X- _ O
air -X- _ O
strikes -X- _ O
yesterday -X- _ O
during -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
day -X- _ O
time. -X- _ O
At -X- _ O
night -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
12 -X- _ B-Weapon
KAB-500 -X- _ I-Weapon
bombs -X- _ I-Weapon
were -X- _ O
dropped -X- _ O
on -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
town. -X- _ O
" -X- _ O
The -X- _ B-Organisation
BBC -X- _ I-Organisation
can -X- _ O
not -X- _ O
verify -X- _ O
his -X- _ O
comments. -X- _ O
Some -X- _ O
1,600 -X- _ O
residents -X- _ O
remain -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
Avdiivka. -X- _ B-Location
Most -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
them -X- _ O
moved -X- _ O
into -X- _ O
basements -X- _ O
long -X- _ O
ago -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
but -X- _ O
they -X- _ O
do -X- _ O
n't -X- _ O
always -X- _ O
provide -X- _ O
good -X- _ O
protection. -X- _ O
According -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
Mr -X- _ B-Person
Barabash -X- _ I-Person
, -X- _ O
as -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
result -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
latest -X- _ O
attacks -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
one -X- _ O
person -X- _ O
was -X- _ O
killed -X- _ O
and -X- _ O
at -X- _ O
least -X- _ O
two -X- _ O
more -X- _ O
are -X- _ O
feared -X- _ O
dead -X- _ O
under -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
rubble. -X- _ O
Russian -X- _ O
attempts -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
move -X- _ O
forward -X- _ O
appear -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
be -X- _ O
aimed -X- _ O
at -X- _ O
seizing -X- _ O
the -X- _ B-Location
villages -X- _ I-Location
of -X- _ I-Location
Berdyche -X- _ I-Location
and -X- _ I-Location
Stepove -X- _ I-Location
to -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
north -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
Avdiivka -X- _ B-Location
and -X- _ O
the -X- _ B-Location
villages -X- _ I-Location
of -X- _ I-Location
Tonenke -X- _ I-Location
and -X- _ I-Location
Severne -X- _ I-Location
to -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
south. -X- _ O
Moscow -X- _ B-Location
asserts -X- _ O
that -X- _ O
its -X- _ O
troops -X- _ O
have -X- _ O
" -X- _ O
improved -X- _ O
their -X- _ O
positions -X- _ O
" -X- _ O
near -X- _ O
Avdiivka -X- _ B-Location
and -X- _ O
Russian -X- _ B-Organisation
military -X- _ I-Organisation
bloggers -X- _ O
report -X- _ O
that -X- _ O
Russian -X- _ B-Organisation
forces -X- _ I-Organisation
have -X- _ O
taken -X- _ O
some -X- _ O
strategic -X- _ O
positions -X- _ O
belonging -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
Ukrainians -X- _ O
and -X- _ O
already -X- _ O
entered -X- _ O
Stepove. -X- _ B-Location
Ukraine -X- _ B-Organisation
's -X- _ I-Organisation
military -X- _ I-Organisation
denies -X- _ O
those -X- _ O
reports -X- _ O
but -X- _ O
these -X- _ O
intense -X- _ O
battles -X- _ O
suggest -X- _ O
that -X- _ O
Russia -X- _ B-Location
is -X- _ O
trying -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
encircle -X- _ O
the -X- _ B-Location
city -X- _ I-Location
of -X- _ I-Location
Avdiivka -X- _ I-Location
by -X- _ O
pushing -X- _ O
from -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
north -X- _ O
and -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
south. -X- _ O
The -X- _ O
town -X- _ O
has -X- _ O
been -X- _ O
well -X- _ O
fortified -X- _ O
and -X- _ O
protected -X- _ O
since -X- _ O
2014 -X- _ B-Money
, -X- _ O
making -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
Russian -X- _ O
breakthrough -X- _ O
inside -X- _ O
Avdiivka -X- _ B-Location
much -X- _ O
harder. -X- _ O
For -X- _ O
that -X- _ O
reason -X- _ O
they -X- _ O
are -X- _ O
trying -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
cut -X- _ O
it -X- _ O
off -X- _ O
from -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
rest -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
Ukrainian-controlled -X- _ O
territories -X- _ O
and -X- _ O
encircle -X- _ O
it -X- _ O
. -X- _ O

Russia -X- _ B-Location
has -X- _ O
launched -X- _ O
massive -X- _ O
attacks -X- _ O
along -X- _ O
other -X- _ O
parts -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
front -X- _ O
line -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
eastern -X- _ B-Location
Ukraine. -X- _ I-Location
Its -X- _ O
forces -X- _ B-MilitaryPlatform
are -X- _ O
pushing -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
direction -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
Kupyansk -X- _ B-Location
in -X- _ O
Kharkiv -X- _ B-Location
region -X- _ I-Location
and -X- _ O
Lyman -X- _ B-Location
in -X- _ I-Location
Donetsk -X- _ I-Location
region -X- _ I-Location
. -X- _ O

Analysts -X- _ O
from -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
Institute -X- _ B-Organisation
of -X- _ I-Organisation
Study -X- _ I-Organisation
of -X- _ I-Organisation
War -X- _ I-Organisation
argue -X- _ O
that -X- _ O
these -X- _ O
operations -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
Avdiivka -X- _ B-Location
and -X- _ O
other -X- _ O
parts -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
Donbas -X- _ B-Location
are -X- _ O
aimed -X- _ O
at -X- _ O
fixing -X- _ O
Ukrainian -X- _ O
forces -X- _ B-MilitaryPlatform
to -X- _ O
" -X- _ O
prevent -X- _ O
them -X- _ O
from -X- _ O
redeploying -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
other -X- _ O
areas -X- _ O
" -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
particularly -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
Zaporizhzhia -X- _ B-Location
region -X- _ I-Location
further -X- _ O
west -X- _ O
where -X- _ O
Ukraine -X- _ B-Location
is -X- _ O
making -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
slow -X- _ O
progress -X- _ O
. -X- _ O

Poland -X- _ B-Location
's -X- _ I-Location
two -X- _ O
highest-ranking -X- _ O
military -X- _ O
officers -X- _ O
have -X- _ O
resigned -X- _ O
days -X- _ O
before -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
key -X- _ O
election -X- _ O
and -X- _ O
amid -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
war -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
neighbouring -X- _ O
Ukraine -X- _ B-Location
. -X- _ O

The -X- _ B-Person
army -X- _ I-Person
's -X- _ I-Person
Chief -X- _ I-Person
of -X- _ I-Person
General -X- _ I-Person
Staff -X- _ I-Person
, -X- _ I-Person
Gen -X- _ I-Person
Rajmund -X- _ I-Person
Andrzejczak -X- _ I-Person
, -X- _ O
and -X- _ O
Operational -X- _ B-Person
Commander -X- _ I-Person
Gen -X- _ I-Person
Tomasz -X- _ I-Person
Piotrowski -X- _ I-Person
gave -X- _ O
no -X- _ O
reason -X- _ O
for -X- _ O
their -X- _ O
decision -X- _ O
. -X- _ O

Media -X- _ O
reports -X- _ O
say -X- _ O
they -X- _ O
are -X- _ O
worried -X- _ O
about -X- _ O
attempts -X- _ O
by -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
right-wing -X- _ O
government -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
politicise -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
military -X- _ O
ahead -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
Sunday -X- _ O
's -X- _ O
general -X- _ O
elections -X- _ O
. -X- _ O

The -X- _ B-Organisation
government -X- _ I-Organisation
denies -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
claim. -X- _ O
It -X- _ O
also -X- _ O
rejects -X- _ O
accusations -X- _ O
by -X- _ O
Poland -X- _ B-Location
's -X- _ I-Location
opposition -X- _ O
and -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
European -X- _ B-Organisation
Union -X- _ I-Organisation
that -X- _ O
it -X- _ O
is -X- _ O
politicising -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
country -X- _ O
's -X- _ O
judiciary -X- _ O
and -X- _ O
curbing -X- _ O
media -X- _ O
freedoms -X- _ O
. -X- _ O

“Why -X- _ O
Europe -X- _ B-Organisation
is -X- _ O
watching -X- _ O
Poland -X- _ B-Location
's -X- _ I-Location
election -X- _ O
" -X- _ O
General -X- _ B-Person
Rajmund -X- _ I-Person
Andrzejczak -X- _ I-Person
submitted -X- _ O
his -X- _ O
resignation -X- _ O
... -X- _ O
on -X- _ O
Monday -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
" -X- _ O
his -X- _ O
spokeswoman -X- _ O
Col -X- _ B-Person
Joanna -X- _ I-Person
Klejszmit -X- _ I-Person
told -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
AFP -X- _ B-Organisation
news -X- _ I-Organisation
agency -X- _ I-Organisation

" -X- _ O
Like -X- _ O
any -X- _ O
soldier -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
he -X- _ O
's -X- _ O
entitled -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
resign -X- _ O
without -X- _ O
giving -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
reason -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
" -X- _ O
she -X- _ O
added. -X- _ O
Gen -X- _ B-Person
Piotrowski -X- _ I-Person
also -X- _ O
tendered -X- _ O
his -X- _ O
resignation -X- _ O
. -X- _ O

The -X- _ B-Organisation
daily -X- _ I-Organisation
Rzeczpospolita -X- _ I-Organisation
- -X- _ O
one -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
Poland -X- _ B-Location
's -X- _ I-Location
leading -X- _ O
newspapers -X- _ O
- -X- _ O
reported -X- _ O
that -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
two -X- _ O
generals -X- _ O
were -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
conflict -X- _ O
with -X- _ O
Defence -X- _ B-Person
Minister -X- _ I-Person
Mariusz -X- _ I-Person
Blaszczak -X- _ I-Person
about -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
politicisation -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
military -X- _ O
and -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
row -X- _ O
over -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
Russian -X- _ B-Location
cruise -X- _ O
missile -X- _ O
over -X- _ O
Poland -X- _ B-Location
late -X- _ O
last -X- _ O
year -X- _ O
. -X- _ O

In -X- _ O
May -X- _ B-Temporal
, -X- _ O
Mr -X- _ B-Person
Blaszczak -X- _ I-Person
, -X- _ O
said -X- _ O
Gen -X- _ B-Person
Piotrowski -X- _ I-Person
failed -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
inform -X- _ O
him -X- _ O
last -X- _ O
December -X- _ B-Temporal
that -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
unarmed -X- _ O
missile -X- _ B-MilitaryPlatform
had -X- _ O
entered -X- _ O
Polish -X- _ O
airspace -X- _ O
from -X- _ O
Belarus -X- _ B-Location
and -X- _ O
flown -X- _ O
hundreds -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
kilometres -X- _ O
before -X- _ O
crashing -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
forest. -X- _ O
The -X- _ O
missile -X- _ B-MilitaryPlatform
was -X- _ O
only -X- _ O
discovered -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
April -X- _ B-Temporal
by -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
member -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
public -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
causing -X- _ O
considerable -X- _ O
embarrassment -X- _ O
for -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
minister -X- _ O
. -X- _ O

Mr -X- _ B-Person
Blaszczak -X- _ I-Person
and -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
two -X- _ O
generals -X- _ O
have -X- _ O
not -X- _ O
publicly -X- _ O
commented -X- _ O
on -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
Rzeczpospolita -X- _ B-Organisation
report -X- _ O
. -X- _ O

On -X- _ O
Sunday -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
Poles -X- _ O
will -X- _ O
be -X- _ O
voting -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
what -X- _ O
opposition -X- _ O
leader -X- _ O
Donald -X- _ B-Person
Tusk -X- _ I-Person
has -X- _ O
billed -X- _ O
as -X- _ O
their -X- _ O
" -X- _ O
most -X- _ O
important -X- _ O
election -X- _ O
since -X- _ O
1989 -X- _ B-Temporal
and -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
fall -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
communism -X- _ O
" -X- _ O

The -X- _ O
populist -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
right-wing -X- _ O
United -X- _ B-Organisation
Right -X- _ I-Organisation
coalition -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
led -X- _ O
by -X- _ O
the -X- _ B-Organisation
Law -X- _ I-Organisation
and -X- _ I-Organisation
Justice -X- _ I-Organisation
party -X- _ I-Organisation
of -X- _ I-Organisation
Jaroslaw -X- _ I-Organisation
Kaczynski -X- _ I-Organisation
is -X- _ O
seeking -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
third -X- _ O
term -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
office -X- _ O
. -X- _ O

However -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
gap -X- _ O
between -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
right -X- _ O
and -X- _ O
centre -X- _ O
has -X- _ O
narrowed -X- _ O
after -X- _ O
an -X- _ O
intensely -X- _ O
bitter -X- _ O
election -X- _ O
campaign -X- _ O
. -X- _ O

Poland -X- _ B-Location
has -X- _ O
been -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
staunch -X- _ O
supporter -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
Ukraine -X- _ B-Location
since -X- _ O
Russia -X- _ B-Location
's -X- _ I-Location
full-scale -X- _ O
invasion -X- _ O
began -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
February -X- _ B-Temporal
2022 -X- _ I-Temporal
, -X- _ O
housing -X- _ O
more -X- _ O
than -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
million -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
Ukrainian -X- _ O
refugees -X- _ O
and -X- _ O
providing -X- _ O
Kyiv -X- _ B-Location
with -X- _ O
more -X- _ O
than -X- _ O
$ -X- _ B-Money
3bn -X- _ I-Money
( -X- _ O
£2.4bn -X- _ B-Money
) -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
weapons. -X- _ B-MilitaryPlatform
But -X- _ O
relations -X- _ O
have -X- _ O
frayed -X- _ O
during -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
campaign -X- _ O
over -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
Polish -X- _ O
ban -X- _ O
on -X- _ O
Ukrainian -X- _ O
grain -X- _ O
imports -X- _ O

Prime -X- _ B-Person
Minister -X- _ I-Person
Mateusz -X- _ I-Person
Morawiecki -X- _ I-Person
said -X- _ O
Warsaw -X- _ B-Location
would -X- _ O
supply -X- _ O
no -X- _ O
more -X- _ O
weapons -X- _ B-MilitaryPlatform
, -X- _ O
and -X- _ O
would -X- _ O
instead -X- _ O
focus -X- _ O
on -X- _ O
rebuilding -X- _ O
its -X- _ O
own -X- _ O
depleted -X- _ O
stocks -X- _ O

Russia -X- _ B-Location
has -X- _ O
failed -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
get -X- _ O
re-elected -X- _ O
as -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
member -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
UN -X- _ B-Organisation
's -X- _ I-Organisation
human -X- _ O
rights -X- _ O
council -X- _ O
. -X- _ O

The -X- _ O
state -X- _ O
was -X- _ O
expelled -X- _ O
from -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
top -X- _ O
human -X- _ O
rights -X- _ O
body -X- _ O
last -X- _ O
April -X- _ B-Temporal
after -X- _ O
its -X- _ O
forces -X- _ O
invaded -X- _ O
Ukraine -X- _ B-Location

It -X- _ O
had -X- _ O
hoped -X- _ O
getting -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
fresh -X- _ O
three-year -X- _ O
term -X- _ O
would -X- _ O
highlight -X- _ O
divisions -X- _ O
between -X- _ O
UN -X- _ B-Organisation
member -X- _ O
states -X- _ O
over -X- _ O
whether -X- _ O
or -X- _ O
not -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
keep -X- _ O
supporting -X- _ O
Ukraine -X- _ B-Location
. -X- _ O

But -X- _ O
Bulgaria -X- _ B-Location
and -X- _ O
Albania -X- _ B-Location
won -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
two -X- _ O
seats -X- _ O
allocated -X- _ O
for -X- _ O
Eastern -X- _ O
European -X- _ O
countries -X- _ O
instead -X- _ O
. -X- _ O

The -X- _ O
vote -X- _ O
came -X- _ O
days -X- _ O
after -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
Russian -X- _ O
missile -X- _ B-MilitaryPlatform
attack -X- _ O
that -X- _ O
killed -X- _ O
52 -X- _ O
people -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
north-eastern -X- _ B-Location
Ukrainian -X- _ I-Location
village -X- _ I-Location
of -X- _ I-Location
Hroza -X- _ I-Location
. -X- _ I-Location

Russia -X- _ B-Location
received -X- _ O
83 -X- _ O
votes -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
favour -X- _ O
from -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
UN -X- _ B-Organisation
's -X- _ I-Organisation
193 -X- _ O
general -X- _ O
assembly -X- _ O
members -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
while -X- _ O
Bulgaria -X- _ B-Location
got -X- _ O
160 -X- _ O
and -X- _ O
Albania -X- _ B-Location
got -X- _ O
123. -X- _ O
Earlier -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
Albania -X- _ B-Location
's -X- _ I-Location
ambassador -X- _ B-Person
Ferit -X- _ I-Person
Hoxha -X- _ I-Person
had -X- _ O
said -X- _ O
it -X- _ O
was -X- _ O
important -X- _ O
for -X- _ O
member -X- _ O
states -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
show -X- _ O
it -X- _ O
was -X- _ O
not -X- _ O
ready -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
" -X- _ O
take -X- _ O
an -X- _ O
arsonist -X- _ O
for -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
firefighter -X- _ O
" -X- _ O
. -X- _ O

Russia -X- _ B-Location
had -X- _ O
promised -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
find -X- _ O
" -X- _ O
adequate -X- _ O
solutions -X- _ O
for -X- _ O
human -X- _ O
rights -X- _ O
issues -X- _ O
" -X- _ O
and -X- _ O
said -X- _ O
it -X- _ O
wanted -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
stop -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
body -X- _ O
becoming -X- _ O
an -X- _ O
" -X- _ O
instrument -X- _ O
which -X- _ O
serves -X- _ O
political -X- _ O
wills -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
one -X- _ O
group -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
countries -X- _ O
" -X- _ O
- -X- _ O
understood -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
be -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
reference -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
West -X- _ O

Diplomats -X- _ B-Organisation
said -X- _ O
it -X- _ O
was -X- _ O
hoping -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
regain -X- _ O
some -X- _ O
international -X- _ O
credibility -X- _ O
after -X- _ O
being -X- _ O
accused -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
widespread -X- _ O
rights -X- _ O
abuses -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
Ukraine -X- _ B-Location
and -X- _ O
inside -X- _ O
its -X- _ O
own -X- _ O
borders -X- _ O
. -X- _ O

Russia -X- _ B-Location
had -X- _ O
claimed -X- _ O
it -X- _ O
would -X- _ O
win -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
votes -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
many -X- _ O
member -X- _ O
states -X- _ O
- -X- _ O
particularly -X- _ O
developing -X- _ O
nations -X- _ O
- -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
secret -X- _ O
ballot -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
suggesting -X- _ O
they -X- _ O
privately -X- _ O
sympathised -X- _ O
with -X- _ O
Moscow -X- _ B-Location
but -X- _ O
avoided -X- _ O
doing -X- _ O
so -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
public -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
avoid -X- _ O
angering -X- _ O
Western -X- _ B-Location
states -X- _ I-Location

Russia -X- _ B-Location
is -X- _ O
said -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
have -X- _ O
campaigned -X- _ O
aggressively -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
offering -X- _ O
small -X- _ O
countries -X- _ O
grain -X- _ O
and -X- _ O
arms -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
return -X- _ O
for -X- _ O
their -X- _ O
votes. -X- _ O
Moscow -X- _ B-Person
's -X- _ I-Person
ambassador -X- _ I-Person
to -X- _ I-Person
the -X- _ I-Person
UN -X- _ I-Person
, -X- _ I-Person
Vassily -X- _ I-Person
Nebenzia -X- _ I-Person
, -X- _ O
accused -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
US -X- _ B-Organisation
of -X- _ O
leading -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
campaign -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
stop -X- _ O
them -X- _ O
from -X- _ O
returning -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
council. -X- _ O
The -X- _ O
state -X- _ O
was -X- _ O
suspended -X- _ O
from -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
human -X- _ O
rights -X- _ O
council -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
April -X- _ B-Temporal
2022 -X- _ I-Temporal
with -X- _ O
93 -X- _ O
members -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
UN -X- _ B-Organisation
general -X- _ O
assembly -X- _ O
voting -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
favour -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
24 -X- _ O
against -X- _ O
and -X- _ O
58 -X- _ O
abstaining -X- _ O
. -X- _ O

The -X- _ O
council -X- _ O
will -X- _ O
consist -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
following -X- _ O
countries -X- _ O
from -X- _ O
2024 -X- _ B-Location
, -X- _ O
for -X- _ O
three -X- _ O
years -X- _ O
: -X- _ O
Albania -X- _ B-Location
, -X- _ O
Brazil -X- _ B-Location
, -X- _ O
Bulgaria -X- _ B-Location
, -X- _ O
Burundi -X- _ B-Location
, -X- _ O
China -X- _ B-Location
, -X- _ O
the -X- _ B-Location
Ivory -X- _ I-Location
Coast -X- _ I-Location
, -X- _ O
Cuba -X- _ B-Location
, -X- _ O
Dominican -X- _ B-Location
Republic -X- _ I-Location
, -X- _ O
France -X- _ B-Location
, -X- _ O
Ghana -X- _ B-Location
, -X- _ O
Indonesia -X- _ B-Location
, -X- _ O
Japan -X- _ B-Location
, -X- _ O
Kuwait -X- _ B-Location
, -X- _ O
Malawi -X- _ B-Location
and -X- _ O
the -X- _ B-Location
Netherlands -X- _ I-Location
. -X- _ O

When -X- _ O
Ukraine -X- _ B-Location
's -X- _ I-Location
Kakhovka -X- _ I-Location
dam -X- _ I-Location
was -X- _ O
blown -X- _ O
up -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
June -X- _ B-Temporal
, -X- _ O
it -X- _ O
led -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
devastating -X- _ O
floods -X- _ O
that -X- _ O
destroyed -X- _ O
homes -X- _ O
and -X- _ O
farmland -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
and -X- _ O
left -X- _ O
hundreds -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
thousands -X- _ O
without -X- _ O
drinking -X- _ O
water. -X- _ O
Four -X- _ O
months -X- _ O
on -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
Ukrainians -X- _ O
are -X- _ O
still -X- _ O
facing -X- _ O
water -X- _ O
shortages -X- _ O
but -X- _ O
say -X- _ O
they -X- _ O
are -X- _ O
determined -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
overcome -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
destruction. -X- _ O
When -X- _ O
Svitlana -X- _ B-Person
Kridiner -X- _ I-Person
heard -X- _ O
about -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
dam -X- _ O
collapse -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
she -X- _ O
knew -X- _ O
it -X- _ O
was -X- _ O
only -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
matter -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
time -X- _ O
before -X- _ O
her -X- _ O
village -X- _ O
would -X- _ O
be -X- _ O
flooded. -X- _ O
In -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
end -X- _ O
it -X- _ O
took -X- _ O
two -X- _ O
days -X- _ O
for -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
water -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
reach -X- _ O
her. -X- _ O
It -X- _ O
arrived -X- _ O
at -X- _ O
around -X- _ O
17:00 -X- _ O
on -X- _ O
8 -X- _ B-Temporal
June -X- _ I-Temporal
. -X- _ O

" -X- _ O
We -X- _ O
packed -X- _ O
quickly. -X- _ O
We -X- _ O
took -X- _ O
our -X- _ O
livestock -X- _ O
- -X- _ O
cows -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
dogs -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
ducklings -X- _ O
- -X- _ O
and -X- _ O
our -X- _ O
equipment -X- _ O
: -X- _ O
milking -X- _ O
kits -X- _ O
and -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
generator -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
" -X- _ O
she -X- _ O
says. -X- _ O
" -X- _ O
We -X- _ O
had -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
leave -X- _ O
all -X- _ O
our -X- _ O
other -X- _ O
possessions -X- _ O
behind -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
they -X- _ O
were -X- _ O
all -X- _ O
lost. -X- _ O
" -X- _ O
The -X- _ O
52-year-old -X- _ O
farmer -X- _ O
and -X- _ O
her -X- _ O
husband -X- _ O
Vasyl -X- _ B-Person
had -X- _ O
devoted -X- _ O
their -X- _ O
lives -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
their -X- _ O
herd -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
two -X- _ O
dozen -X- _ O
cows -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
which -X- _ O
they -X- _ O
had -X- _ O
raised -X- _ O
from -X- _ O
calves -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
and -X- _ O
did -X- _ O
everything -X- _ O
they -X- _ O
could -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
save -X- _ O
them. -X- _ O
It -X- _ O
took -X- _ O
just -X- _ O
five -X- _ O
more -X- _ O
hours -X- _ O
for -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
water -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
engulf -X- _ O
their -X- _ O
whole -X- _ O
farm. -X- _ O
Their -X- _ O
village -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
Afanasiivka -X- _ B-Location
, -X- _ O
is -X- _ O
70km -X- _ O
( -X- _ O
45 -X- _ O
miles -X- _ O
) -X- _ O
north -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
dam -X- _ O
and -X- _ O
there -X- _ O
are -X- _ O
signs -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
damage -X- _ O
everywhere -X- _ O
. -X- _ O

Svitlana -X- _ B-Person
shows -X- _ O
us -X- _ O
water -X- _ O
marks -X- _ O
inside -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
barn -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
close -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
ceiling -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
and -X- _ O
explains -X- _ O
that -X- _ O
most -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
hay -X- _ O
she -X- _ O
and -X- _ O
her -X- _ O
husband -X- _ O
had -X- _ O
prepared -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
feed -X- _ O
their -X- _ O
cows -X- _ O
over -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
winter -X- _ O
was -X- _ O
destroyed. -X- _ O
So -X- _ O
was -X- _ O
their -X- _ O
other -X- _ O
animal -X- _ O
feed. -X- _ O
" -X- _ O
The -X- _ O
water -X- _ O
rose -X- _ O
by -X- _ O
six -X- _ O
metres -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
but -X- _ O
at -X- _ O
least -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
farm -X- _ O
building -X- _ O
survived -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
" -X- _ O
she -X- _ O
says. -X- _ O
" -X- _ O
Only -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
floor -X- _ O
got -X- _ O
washed -X- _ O
away -X- _ O
but -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
walls -X- _ O
are -X- _ O
still -X- _ O
standing. -X- _ O
" -X- _ O
On -X- _ O
top -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
this -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
Svitlana -X- _ B-Location
's -X- _ I-Location
village -X- _ I-Location
is -X- _ O
near -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
front -X- _ O
line -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
and -X- _ O
like -X- _ O
many -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
flood-hit -X- _ O
areas -X- _ O
is -X- _ O
contaminated -X- _ O
with -X- _ O
ammunition. -X- _ O
She -X- _ O
shows -X- _ O
us -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
rocket -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
stuck -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
ground -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
one -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
her -X- _ O
hay -X- _ O
meadows. -X- _ O
" -X- _ O
My -X- _ O
husband -X- _ O
has -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
mow -X- _ O
around -X- _ O
it -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
" -X- _ O
she -X- _ O
says -X- _ O
. -X- _ O

Image -X- _ O
caption -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
A -X- _ B-MilitaryPlatform
rocket -X- _ I-MilitaryPlatform
is -X- _ O
stuck -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
the -X- _ B-Location
middle -X- _ I-Location
of -X- _ I-Location
Svitlana -X- _ I-Location
's -X- _ I-Location
hay -X- _ I-Location
meadow -X- _ I-Location
which -X- _ O
they -X- _ O
now -X- _ O
have -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
mow -X- _ O
around -X- _ O
The -X- _ B-Organisation
Ukrainian -X- _ I-Organisation
government -X- _ I-Organisation
is -X- _ O
offering -X- _ O
her -X- _ O
compensation -X- _ O
for -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
flood -X- _ O
damage -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
although -X- _ O
she -X- _ O
says -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
5,000 -X- _ O
Ukrainian -X- _ O
hryvnia -X- _ O
offered -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
equivalent -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
$ -X- _ B-Money
135 -X- _ I-Money
or -X- _ O
£110 -X- _ B-Money
, -X- _ O
is -X- _ O
nowhere -X- _ O
near -X- _ O
enough -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
repair -X- _ O
everything.Somehow -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
she -X- _ O
's -X- _ O
not -X- _ O
disheartened. -X- _ O
" -X- _ O
Maybe -X- _ O
we -X- _ O
will -X- _ O
take -X- _ O
out -X- _ O
another -X- _ O
loan -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
we -X- _ O
will -X- _ O
mow -X- _ O
some -X- _ O
hay -X- _ O
for -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
cows -X- _ O
or -X- _ O
buy -X- _ O
some -X- _ O
more. -X- _ O
We -X- _ O
will -X- _ O
make -X- _ O
it -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
rest -X- _ O
assured. -X- _ O
" -X- _ O
Her -X- _ O
optimism -X- _ O
is -X- _ O
shared -X- _ O
by -X- _ O
another -X- _ O
farmer -X- _ O
we -X- _ O
meet -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
Vadym -X- _ B-Person
Sheremet -X- _ I-Person
, -X- _ O
who -X- _ O
shows -X- _ O
us -X- _ O
round -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
ruins -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
his -X- _ O
home -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
the -X- _ B-Location
village -X- _ I-Location
of -X- _ I-Location
Pavlo-Marianivka -X- _ I-Location
, -X- _ O
10km -X- _ O
( -X- _ O
six -X- _ O
miles -X- _ O
) -X- _ O
away. -X- _ O
" -X- _ O
Here -X- _ O
we -X- _ O
had -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
fireplace -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
where -X- _ O
our -X- _ O
family -X- _ O
gathered -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
" -X- _ O
says -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
52-year-old -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
pointing -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
pile -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
bricks -X- _ O
and -X- _ O
chimney -X- _ O
debris. -X- _ O
" -X- _ O
It -X- _ O
was -X- _ O
such -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
happy -X- _ O
time -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
" -X- _ O
he -X- _ O
trails -X- _ O
off -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
remembering -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
old -X- _ O
days. -X- _ O
Image -X- _ O
caption -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
Vadym -X- _ B-Person
Sheremet -X- _ I-Person
is -X- _ O
having -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
rebuild -X- _ O
his -X- _ O
entire -X- _ O
farm -X- _ O
after -X- _ O
flood-water -X- _ O
hit. -X- _ O
The -X- _ O
water -X- _ O
reached -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
roof -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
his -X- _ O
house -X- _ O
and -X- _ O
destroyed -X- _ O
his -X- _ O
crops. -X- _ O
Before -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
flood -X- _ O
he -X- _ O
grew -X- _ O
wheat -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
barley -X- _ O
and -X- _ O
sunflowers. -X- _ O
And -X- _ O
this -X- _ O
is -X- _ O
n't -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
first -X- _ O
time -X- _ O
he -X- _ O
has -X- _ O
had -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
start -X- _ O
again. -X- _ O
Vadym -X- _ B-Location
's -X- _ I-Location
village -X- _ I-Location
was -X- _ O
under -X- _ O
Russian -X- _ O
occupation -X- _ O
for -X- _ O
much -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
2022. -X- _ B-Temporal
" -X- _ O
Last -X- _ O
autumn -X- _ O
we -X- _ O
had -X- _ O
250 -X- _ O
hectares -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
grain -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
ready -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
harvest. -X- _ O
Russians -X- _ O
burnt -X- _ O
it -X- _ O
all. -X- _ O
That -X- _ O
was -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
first -X- _ O
blow -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
" -X- _ O
he -X- _ O
says. -X- _ O
" -X- _ O
Then -X- _ O
spring -X- _ O
2023 -X- _ B-Temporal
came. -X- _ O
We -X- _ O
gave -X- _ O
it -X- _ O
our -X- _ O
all -X- _ O
and -X- _ O
sowed -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
however -X- _ O
hard -X- _ O
it -X- _ O
was. -X- _ O
Then -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
water -X- _ O
came. -X- _ O
We -X- _ O
were -X- _ O
knocked -X- _ O
down -X- _ O
once -X- _ O
again -X- _ O
. -X- _ O
" -X- _ O

The -X- _ O
impact -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
dam -X- _ O
explosion -X- _ O
is -X- _ O
so -X- _ O
huge -X- _ O
that -X- _ O
it -X- _ O
is -X- _ O
described -X- _ O
as -X- _ O
" -X- _ O
one -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
biggest -X- _ O
human-caused -X- _ O
disasters -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
our -X- _ O
time -X- _ O
" -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
report -X- _ O
by -X- _ O
US -X- _ B-Organisation
research -X- _ O
institute -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
the -X- _ B-Location
Wilson -X- _ I-Location
Centre. -X- _ I-Location
It -X- _ O
also -X- _ O
says -X- _ O
that -X- _ O
" -X- _ O
more -X- _ O
than -X- _ O
one -X- _ O
million -X- _ O
hectares -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
land -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
three -X- _ O
southern -X- _ O
oblasts -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
Ukraine -X- _ B-Location
- -X- _ I-Location
Kherson -X- _ I-Location
, -X- _ O
Zaporizhzhia -X- _ B-Location
and -X- _ O
Dnipropetrovsk -X- _ B-Location
- -X- _ O
will -X- _ O
be -X- _ O
unusable -X- _ O
for -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
next -X- _ O
three -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
five -X- _ O
years -X- _ O
for -X- _ O
lack -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
water -X- _ O
supply -X- _ O
" -X- _ O
. -X- _ O
Damage -X- _ O
worth -X- _ O
an -X- _ O
estimated -X- _ O
$ -X- _ B-Money
2bn -X- _ I-Money
( -X- _ O
£1.6bn -X- _ B-Money
) -X- _ O
was -X- _ O
caused -X- _ O
by -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
breach -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
excluding -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
cost -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
rebuilding -X- _ O
it -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
according -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
Ukrainian -X- _ B-Organisation
authorities. -X- _ I-Organisation
They -X- _ O
said -X- _ O
more -X- _ O
than -X- _ O
two-thirds -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
affected -X- _ O
area -X- _ O
was -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
Russian-occupied -X- _ O
territory -X- _ O
where -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
flooding -X- _ O
was -X- _ O
worse -X- _ O
because -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
bank -X- _ O
on -X- _ O
that -X- _ O
side -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
river -X- _ O
is -X- _ O
lower. -X- _ O
Watch -X- _ O
on -X- _ O
iPlayer -X- _ O
: -X- _ O
After -X- _ O
Kakhovka -X- _ B-Location
, -X- _ O
The -X- _ B-Location
Kakhovka -X- _ I-Location
dam -X- _ I-Location
held -X- _ O
back -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
vast -X- _ O
reservoir -X- _ O
that -X- _ O
supplied -X- _ O
water -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
irrigate -X- _ O
farms -X- _ O
as -X- _ O
well -X- _ O
as -X- _ O
provided -X- _ O
drinking -X- _ O
water. -X- _ O
A -X- _ O
report -X- _ O
by -X- _ O
the -X- _ B-Organisation
United -X- _ I-Organisation
Nations -X- _ I-Organisation
warns -X- _ O
that -X- _ O
there -X- _ O
is -X- _ O
unlikely -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
be -X- _ O
enough -X- _ O
rain -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
water -X- _ O
farmers -X- _ O
' -X- _ O
crops -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
so -X- _ O
people -X- _ O
have -X- _ O
been -X- _ O
digging -X- _ O
new -X- _ O
wells -X- _ O
and -X- _ O
laying -X- _ O
water -X- _ O
supply -X- _ O
lines -X- _ O
with -X- _ O
help -X- _ O
from -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
authorities -X- _ O
and -X- _ O
aid -X- _ O
groups. -X- _ O
With -X- _ O
help -X- _ O
from -X- _ O
volunteers -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
Vadym -X- _ B-Person
is -X- _ O
building -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
new -X- _ O
house -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
ploughing -X- _ O
his -X- _ O
fields -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
prepare -X- _ O
for -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
season -X- _ O
ahead -X- _ O
and -X- _ O
plans -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
lay -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
new -X- _ O
water -X- _ O
supply -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
help -X- _ O
his -X- _ O
community. -X- _ O
" -X- _ O
Everything -X- _ O
will -X- _ O
work -X- _ O
out -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
" -X- _ O
says -X- _ O
Vadim. -X- _ B-Person
" -X- _ O
Life -X- _ O
is -X- _ O
wonderful. -X- _ O
You -X- _ O
can -X- _ O
give -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
or -X- _ O
become -X- _ O
stronger. -X- _ O
" -X- _ O
Image -X- _ O
source -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
Family -X- _ O
handout -X- _ O
Image -X- _ O
caption -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
Ivan -X- _ B-Person
Sheremet -X- _ I-Person
was -X- _ O
killed -X- _ O
by -X- _ O
an -X- _ O
explosive -X- _ B-MilitaryPlatform
in -X- _ O
southern -X- _ B-Location
Ukraine -X- _ I-Location
at -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
age -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
20. -X- _ O
Two -X- _ O
days -X- _ O
after -X- _ O
we -X- _ O
left -X- _ O
Vadym -X- _ B-Person
's -X- _ I-Person
village -X- _ O
he -X- _ O
received -X- _ O
some -X- _ O
devastating -X- _ O
news. -X- _ O
His -X- _ O
20-year-old -X- _ O
son -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
Ivan -X- _ B-Person
, -X- _ O
was -X- _ O
killed -X- _ O
by -X- _ O
an -X- _ O
explosive -X- _ B-MilitaryPlatform
by -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
side -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
road -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
not -X- _ O
far -X- _ O
from -X- _ O
his -X- _ O
home. -X- _ O
Vadim -X- _ B-Person
believes -X- _ O
it -X- _ O
was -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
Russian -X- _ B-MilitaryPlatform
munition -X- _ I-MilitaryPlatform
, -X- _ O
although -X- _ O
there -X- _ O
is -X- _ O
no -X- _ O
way -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
confirm -X- _ O
this -X- _ O
at -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
moment. -X- _ O
Since -X- _ O
Russia -X- _ B-Location
's -X- _ I-Location
invasion -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
Ukraine -X- _ B-Location
has -X- _ O
become -X- _ O
one -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
most -X- _ O
heavily -X- _ O
mined -X- _ O
countries -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
world -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
according -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
the -X- _ B-Organisation
United -X- _ I-Organisation
Nations. -X- _ O
The -X- _ O
head -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
the -X- _ B-Organisation
Red -X- _ I-Organisation
Cross -X- _ I-Organisation
's -X- _ I-Organisation
weapon -X- _ O
contamination -X- _ O
unit -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
Erik -X- _ B-Person
Tollefsen -X- _ I-Person
, -X- _ O
says -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
dam -X- _ O
disaster -X- _ O
dislodged -X- _ O
mines -X- _ B-MilitaryPlatform
, -X- _ O
exacerbating -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
problem. -X- _ O
" -X- _ O
We -X- _ O
knew -X- _ O
where -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
hazards -X- _ O
were. -X- _ O
Now -X- _ O
we -X- _ O
don't. -X- _ O
All -X- _ O
we -X- _ O
know -X- _ O
is -X- _ O
that -X- _ O
they -X- _ O
are -X- _ O
somewhere -X- _ O
downstream -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
" -X- _ O
he -X- _ O
told -X- _ O
the -X- _ B-Organisation
AFP -X- _ I-Organisation
news -X- _ I-Organisation
agency. -X- _ I-Organisation
Ukrainian -X- _ B-Organisation
government -X- _ I-Organisation
/ -X- _ O
UN -X- _ B-Organisation
estimates -X- _ O
Russia -X- _ B-Location
and -X- _ O
Ukraine -X- _ B-Location
have -X- _ O
blamed -X- _ O
each -X- _ O
other -X- _ O
for -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
destruction -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
dam. -X- _ O
Two -X- _ O
days -X- _ O
after -X- _ O
it -X- _ O
started -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
burst -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
Norwegian -X- _ B-Organisation
agency -X- _ I-Organisation
analysed -X- _ O
seismic -X- _ O
signals -X- _ O
from -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
regional -X- _ O
station -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
Romania -X- _ B-Location
, -X- _ O
which -X- _ O
indicated -X- _ O
an -X- _ O
explosion -X- _ O
at -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
same -X- _ O
time -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
dam -X- _ O
collapse -X- _ O
was -X- _ O
registered. -X- _ O
Experts -X- _ O
with -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
international -X- _ O
human -X- _ O
rights -X- _ O
law -X- _ O
firm -X- _ O
Global -X- _ B-Organisation
Rights -X- _ I-Organisation
Compliance -X- _ I-Organisation
, -X- _ O
which -X- _ O
is -X- _ O
implementing -X- _ O
Western-backed -X- _ O
efforts -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
support -X- _ O
accountability -X- _ O
for -X- _ O
atrocities -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
Ukraine -X- _ B-Location
, -X- _ O
visited -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
Kherson -X- _ B-Location
region -X- _ I-Location
from -X- _ O
10 -X- _ B-Temporal
to -X- _ I-Temporal
11 -X- _ I-Temporal
June -X- _ I-Temporal
with -X- _ O
Ukraine -X- _ O
's -X- _ O
prosecutor -X- _ O
general -X- _ O
and -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
team -X- _ O
from -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
International -X- _ B-Organisation
Criminal -X- _ I-Organisation
Court. -X- _ I-Organisation
The -X- _ O
group -X- _ O
concluded -X- _ O
it -X- _ O
was -X- _ O
" -X- _ O
highly -X- _ O
likely -X- _ O
" -X- _ O
that -X- _ O
Russia -X- _ B-Location
was -X- _ O
behind -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
attack -X- _ O
. -X- _ O

Despite -X- _ O
everything -X- _ O
that -X- _ O
has -X- _ O
happened -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
Vadym -X- _ B-Person
is -X- _ O
determined -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
rebuild -X- _ O
his -X- _ O
life -X- _ O
and -X- _ O
his -X- _ O
farm. -X- _ O
He -X- _ O
was -X- _ O
too -X- _ O
upset -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
talk -X- _ O
straight -X- _ O
after -X- _ O
Ivan -X- _ B-Person
's -X- _ I-Person
death -X- _ O
but -X- _ O
eventually -X- _ O
he -X- _ O
called -X- _ O
us -X- _ O
from -X- _ O
his -X- _ O
courtyard -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
sitting -X- _ O
with -X- _ O
his -X- _ O
back -X- _ O
against -X- _ O
his -X- _ O
tractor. -X- _ O
" -X- _ O
My -X- _ O
son -X- _ O
was -X- _ O
someone -X- _ O
who -X- _ O
could -X- _ O
do -X- _ O
anything -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
" -X- _ O
he -X- _ O
said. -X- _ O
And -X- _ O
he -X- _ O
vowed -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
keep -X- _ O
strong -X- _ O
for -X- _ O
Ivan. -X- _ B-Person
" -X- _ O
We -X- _ O
have -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
be -X- _ O
strong. -X- _ O
We -X- _ O
have -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
live. -X- _ O
We -X- _ O
will -X- _ O
make -X- _ O
it -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
" -X- _ O
he -X- _ O
says. -X- _ O
" -X- _ O
We -X- _ O
are -X- _ O
good -X- _ O
people -X- _ O
who -X- _ O
deserve -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
live -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
peaceful -X- _ O
and -X- _ O
flourishing -X- _ O
Ukraine -X- _ B-Location
. -X- _ O

The -X- _ O
two -X- _ O
largest -X- _ O
hacktivist -X- _ B-Organisation
groups -X- _ I-Organisation
in -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
Ukraine -X- _ B-Location
conflict -X- _ O
have -X- _ O
vowed -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
de-escalate -X- _ O
cyber-attacks -X- _ O
and -X- _ O
comply -X- _ O
with -X- _ O
new -X- _ O
rules -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
engagement -X- _ O
published -X- _ O
by -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
war -X- _ O
watchdog -X- _ O
. -X- _ O

Dubbed -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
" -X- _ O
Geneva -X- _ O
Code -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
cyber-war -X- _ O
" -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
it -X- _ O
was -X- _ O
initially -X- _ O
criticised -X- _ O
as -X- _ O
unworkable -X- _ O
. -X- _ O

But -X- _ O
now -X- _ O
Ukrainian -X- _ O
and -X- _ O
Russian -X- _ O
hackers -X- _ O
say -X- _ O
they -X- _ O
will -X- _ O
comply -X- _ O
with -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
rules -X- _ O
. -X- _ O

Since -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
invasion -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
Ukraine -X- _ B-Location
there -X- _ O
has -X- _ O
been -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
steady -X- _ O
stream -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
disruptive -X- _ O
cyber-attacks -X- _ O
against -X- _ O
public -X- _ O
services -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
both -X- _ O
Ukraine -X- _ B-Location
and -X- _ O
Russia -X- _ B-Location
with -X- _ O
varying -X- _ O
degrees -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
impact -X- _ O
. -X- _ O

Hacktivist -X- _ O
groups -X- _ O
have -X- _ O
been -X- _ O
using -X- _ O
largely -X- _ O
unsophisticated -X- _ O
forms -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
cyber-attack -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
but -X- _ O
successfully -X- _ O
temporarily -X- _ O
disrupted -X- _ O
banks -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
companies -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
pharmacies -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
hospitals -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
railway -X- _ O
networks -X- _ O
and -X- _ O
civilian -X- _ O
government -X- _ O
services -X- _ O
for -X- _ O
Ukrainian -X- _ O
and -X- _ O
Russian -X- _ O
citizens -X- _ O
. -X- _ O

With -X- _ O
few -X- _ O
soft -X- _ O
targets -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
government -X- _ O
or -X- _ O
military -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
hacktivists -X- _ O
on -X- _ O
both -X- _ O
sides -X- _ O
have -X- _ O
revelled -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
causing -X- _ O
friction -X- _ O
for -X- _ O
ordinary -X- _ O
people -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
further -X- _ O
their -X- _ O
causes -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
often -X- _ O
collecting -X- _ O
angry -X- _ O
social -X- _ O
media -X- _ O
posts -X- _ O
from -X- _ O
those -X- _ O
affected -X- _ O
by -X- _ O
their -X- _ O
attacks -X- _ O
. -X- _ O

By -X- _ O
vowing -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
comply -X- _ O
with -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
ICRC -X- _ B-Organisation
rules -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
hacker -X- _ O
groups -X- _ O
will -X- _ O
avoid -X- _ O
cyber-attacks -X- _ O
that -X- _ O
affect -X- _ O
civilians -X- _ O
. -X- _ O

Speaking -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
the -X- _ B-Organisation
BBC -X- _ I-Organisation
, -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
leader -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
the -X- _ B-Organisation
infamous -X- _ I-Organisation
pro-Russian -X- _ I-Organisation
hacking -X- _ I-Organisation
group -X- _ I-Organisation
Killnet -X- _ I-Organisation
said -X- _ O
he -X- _ O
" -X- _ O
agrees -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
terms -X- _ O
and -X- _ O
rules -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
Red -X- _ B-Organisation
Cross -X- _ I-Organisation
, -X- _ O
let -X- _ O
this -X- _ O
be -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
first -X- _ O
step -X- _ O
from -X- _ O
Killnet -X- _ B-Organisation
to -X- _ O
peace -X- _ O
" -X- _ O
. -X- _ O

Killmilk -X- _ B-Person
, -X- _ O
as -X- _ O
he -X- _ O
is -X- _ O
known -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
started -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
Telegram -X- _ B-Organisation
group -X- _ I-Organisation
for -X- _ O
Killnet -X- _ B-Organisation
shortly -X- _ O
after -X- _ O
his -X- _ O
country -X- _ O
invaded -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
and -X- _ O
now -X- _ O
has -X- _ O
90,000 -X- _ O
followers. -X- _ O
Killmilk -X- _ B-Organisation
has -X- _ O
posted -X- _ O
videos -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
himself -X- _ O
urinating -X- _ O
on -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
flags -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
Ukraine -X- _ B-Location
and -X- _ O
Nato -X- _ B-Organisation
, -X- _ O
and -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
group -X- _ O
was -X- _ O
highlighted -X- _ O
as -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
persistent -X- _ O
source -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
low-level -X- _ O
disruptive -X- _ O
attacks -X- _ O
on -X- _ O
Ukrainian -X- _ O
targets -X- _ O
. -X- _ O

Image -X- _ O
caption -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
Killnet -X- _ B-Organisation
's -X- _ I-Organisation
leader -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
Killmilk -X- _ B-Person
, -X- _ O
says -X- _ O
he -X- _ O
" -X- _ O
agrees -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
terms -X- _ O
and -X- _ O
rules -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
Red -X- _ B-Organisation
Cross -X- _ I-Organisation
" -X- _ O
The -X- _ O
group -X- _ O
has -X- _ O
been -X- _ O
accused -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
having -X- _ O
close -X- _ O
links -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
the -X- _ B-Organisation
Kremlin -X- _ I-Organisation
, -X- _ O
but -X- _ O
has -X- _ O
always -X- _ O
denied -X- _ O
this -X- _ O
. -X- _ O

In -X- _ O
April -X- _ B-Temporal
, -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
UK -X- _ B-Organisation
's -X- _ I-Organisation
National -X- _ I-Organisation
Cyber -X- _ I-Organisation
Security -X- _ I-Organisation
Centre -X- _ I-Organisation
highlighted -X- _ O
groups -X- _ O
like -X- _ O
Killnet -X- _ B-Organisation
as -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
new -X- _ O
threat -X- _ O
facing -X- _ O
Ukraine -X- _ B-Location
allies -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
warning -X- _ O
UK -X- _ B-Organisation
businesses -X- _ O
that -X- _ O
attacks -X- _ O
from -X- _ O
them -X- _ O
on -X- _ O
are -X- _ O
on -X- _ O
rise -X- _ O
. -X- _ O

If -X- _ O
Killnet -X- _ B-Organisation
keeps -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
its -X- _ O
word -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
then -X- _ O
cyber-attacks -X- _ O
on -X- _ O
civilian -X- _ O
targets -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
including -X- _ O
those -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
Ukraine -X- _ B-Location
's -X- _ I-Location
allies -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
will -X- _ O
stop -X- _ O
. -X- _ O

The -X- _ B-Organisation
IT -X- _ I-Organisation
Army -X- _ I-Organisation
of -X- _ I-Organisation
Ukraine -X- _ I-Organisation
also -X- _ O
said -X- _ O
it -X- _ O
would -X- _ O
be -X- _ O
following -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
ICRC -X- _ B-Organisation
's -X- _ I-Organisation
eight -X- _ O
rules -X- _ O
. -X- _ O

The -X- _ O
group -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
which -X- _ O
has -X- _ O
160,000 -X- _ O
members -X- _ O
on -X- _ O
its -X- _ O
Telegram -X- _ B-Organisation
channel -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
also -X- _ O
targets -X- _ O
public -X- _ O
services -X- _ O
such -X- _ O
as -X- _ O
railway -X- _ O
systems -X- _ O
and -X- _ O
banks -X- _ O
. -X- _ O

Its -X- _ O
spokesman -X- _ O
told -X- _ O
BBC -X- _ B-Organisation
News -X- _ O
that -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
group -X- _ O
will -X- _ O
" -X- _ O
make -X- _ O
best -X- _ O
efforts -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
follow -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
rules -X- _ O
" -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
even -X- _ O
though -X- _ O
it -X- _ O
may -X- _ O
place -X- _ O
them -X- _ O
at -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
disadvantage -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
their -X- _ O
adversaries. -X- _ O
The -X- _ O
spokesman -X- _ O
added -X- _ O
that -X- _ O
attacks -X- _ O
on -X- _ O
healthcare -X- _ O
targets -X- _ O
have -X- _ O
been -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
long-standing -X- _ O
red -X- _ O
line -X- _ O
already -X- _ O
. -X- _ O

The -X- _ O
news -X- _ O
means -X- _ O
that -X- _ O
there -X- _ O
will -X- _ O
likely -X- _ O
be -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
major -X- _ O
reduction -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
number -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
cyber -X- _ O
attacks -X- _ O
as -X- _ O
groups -X- _ O
restrict -X- _ O
their -X- _ O
activities -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
official -X- _ O
or -X- _ O
military -X- _ O
targets -X- _ O
. -X- _ O

But -X- _ O
other -X- _ O
hacktivist -X- _ O
groups -X- _ O
working -X- _ O
for -X- _ O
other -X- _ O
patriotic -X- _ O
or -X- _ O
ethical -X- _ O
causes -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
world -X- _ O
told -X- _ O
the -X- _ B-Organisation
BBC -X- _ I-Organisation
they -X- _ O
would -X- _ O
not -X- _ O
be -X- _ O
following -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
rules -X- _ O
at -X- _ O
all -X- _ O
. -X- _ O

The -X- _ B-Organisation
ICRC -X- _ I-Organisation
issued -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
eight -X- _ O
rules -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
engagement -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
an -X- _ O
attempt -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
end -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
free-for-all -X- _ O
that -X- _ O
has -X- _ O
accelerated -X- _ O
during -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
Ukraine -X- _ B-Location
cyber-conflict -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
warning -X- _ O
that -X- _ O
unprecedented -X- _ O
numbers -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
people -X- _ O
are -X- _ O
joining -X- _ O
patriotic -X- _ O
cyber-gangs -X- _ O
. -X- _ O

The -X- _ O
unusually -X- _ O
large -X- _ O
collection -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
vehicles -X- _ O
and -X- _ O
people -X- _ O
tells -X- _ O
you -X- _ O
something -X- _ O
significant -X- _ O
has -X- _ O
happened -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
the -X- _ B-Location
tiny -X- _ I-Location
village -X- _ I-Location
of -X- _ I-Location
Hroza -X- _ I-Location
. -X- _ O

After -X- _ O
driving -X- _ O
for -X- _ O
hours -X- _ O
through -X- _ O
Ukraine -X- _ B-Location
's -X- _ I-Location
endless -X- _ O
rural -X- _ O
expanse -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
it -X- _ O
is -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
jarring -X- _ O
sight -X- _ O
. -X- _ O

Such -X- _ O
is -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
force -X- _ O
from -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
ballistic -X- _ B-MilitaryPlatform
missile -X- _ I-MilitaryPlatform
, -X- _ O
it -X- _ O
is -X- _ O
not -X- _ O
always -X- _ O
immediately -X- _ O
obvious -X- _ O
where -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
missile -X- _ B-MilitaryPlatform
hit -X- _ O
. -X- _ O

But -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
as -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
odour -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
burning -X- _ O
still -X- _ O
taints -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
air -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
you -X- _ O
turn -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
corner -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
find -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
remaining -X- _ O
walls -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
what -X- _ O
was -X- _ O
once -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
café -X- _ O
and -X- _ O
grocery -X- _ O
shop. -X- _ O
The -X- _ O
missile -X- _ B-MilitaryPlatform
struck -X- _ O
during -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
wake -X- _ O
attended -X- _ O
by -X- _ O
many -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
the -X- _ B-Location
village -X- _ I-Location
- -X- _ O
for -X- _ O
what -X- _ O
this -X- _ O
also -X- _ O
was -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
was -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
son -X- _ O
's -X- _ O
attempt -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
rebury -X- _ O
his -X- _ O
father -X- _ O
after -X- _ O
he -X- _ O
was -X- _ O
killed -X- _ O
and -X- _ O
buried -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
occupied -X- _ B-Location
territory -X- _ I-Location
last -X- _ O
year. -X- _ O
Now -X- _ O
he -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
his -X- _ O
wife -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
and -X- _ O
49 -X- _ O
others -X- _ O
are -X- _ O
gone -X- _ O
too -X- _ O
- -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
fifth -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
Hroza -X- _ B-Location
's -X- _ I-Location
population -X- _ O
killed -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
one -X- _ O
go -X- _ O
. -X- _ O

Every -X- _ O
family -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
the -X- _ B-Location
village -X- _ I-Location
in -X- _ I-Location
north-eastern -X- _ I-Location
Kharkiv -X- _ I-Location
region -X- _ I-Location
has -X- _ O
been -X- _ O
affected -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
Interior -X- _ B-Person
Minister -X- _ I-Person
Ihor -X- _ I-Person
Klymenko -X- _ I-Person
says -X- _ O
. -X- _ O

Blood -X- _ O
stains -X- _ O
are -X- _ O
still -X- _ O
visible -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
soil. -X- _ O
Eerily -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
swings -X- _ O
and -X- _ O
slide -X- _ O
are -X- _ O
still -X- _ O
there. -X- _ O
Symbols -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
innocence -X- _ O
against -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
desperate -X- _ O
backdrop -X- _ O
. -X- _ O

A -X- _ O
covered -X- _ O
body -X- _ O
lies -X- _ O
next -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
collection -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
candles -X- _ O
on -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
tractor -X- _ O
tyre. -X- _ O
A -X- _ O
memorial -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
52 -X- _ O
lives -X- _ O
taken -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
an -X- _ O
instant -X- _ O
yesterday. -X- _ O
Down -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
neighbouring -X- _ O
bumpy -X- _ O
road -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
we -X- _ O
meet -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
imposing -X- _ O
frame -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
Andriy. -X- _ B-Person
He -X- _ O
tells -X- _ O
us -X- _ O
his -X- _ O
wife -X- _ O
Lyubov -X- _ B-Person
was -X- _ O
at -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
funeral -X- _ O
wake -X- _ O
yesterday -X- _ O
afternoon -X- _ O
and -X- _ O
that -X- _ O
he -X- _ O
does -X- _ O
n't -X- _ O
know -X- _ O
what -X- _ O
's -X- _ O
happened -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
her -X- _ O
. -X- _ O

Andriy -X- _ B-Person
was -X- _ O
out -X- _ O
at -X- _ O
work -X- _ O
at -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
same -X- _ O
time -X- _ O
. -X- _ O

" -X- _ O
We -X- _ O
ca -X- _ O
n't -X- _ O
find -X- _ O
her -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
" -X- _ O
he -X- _ O
says. -X- _ O
" -X- _ O
We -X- _ O
have -X- _ O
n't -X- _ O
seen -X- _ O
her -X- _ O
dead -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
we -X- _ O
have -X- _ O
n't -X- _ O
seen -X- _ O
her -X- _ O
alive -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
we -X- _ O
just -X- _ O
do -X- _ O
n't -X- _ O
know -X- _ O
what -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
do -X- _ O
. -X- _ O

" -X- _ O
Lyubov -X- _ B-Person
's -X- _ I-Person
father -X- _ O
went -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
police -X- _ O
station -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
give -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
DNA -X- _ O
sample -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
hope -X- _ O
she -X- _ O
might -X- _ O
at -X- _ O
least -X- _ O
be -X- _ O
identified -X- _ O
. -X- _ O

What -X- _ O
also -X- _ O
backs -X- _ O
that -X- _ O
up -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
is -X- _ O
how -X- _ O
locals -X- _ O
say -X- _ O
the -X- _ B-Location
village -X- _ I-Location
is -X- _ O
typically -X- _ O
spared -X- _ O
from -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
frequent -X- _ O
shelling -X- _ O
other -X- _ O
settlements -X- _ O
must -X- _ O
endure. -X- _ O
Russia -X- _ B-Location
has -X- _ O
not -X- _ O
directly -X- _ O
commented -X- _ O
on -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
strike -X- _ O
. -X- _ O

But -X- _ O
Ukraine -X- _ B-Organisation
's -X- _ I-Organisation
defence -X- _ I-Organisation
ministry -X- _ I-Organisation
blames -X- _ O
Russia -X- _ B-Location
for -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
attack -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
adding -X- _ O
there -X- _ O
were -X- _ O
no -X- _ O
military -X- _ O
targets -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
area -X- _ O
. -X- _ O

When -X- _ O
Canada -X- _ B-Organisation
's -X- _ I-Organisation
parliament -X- _ I-Organisation
praised -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
Ukrainian -X- _ O
war -X- _ O
veteran -X- _ O
who -X- _ O
fought -X- _ O
with -X- _ O
Nazi -X- _ B-Organisation
Germany -X- _ I-Organisation
, -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
renewed -X- _ O
spotlight -X- _ O
was -X- _ O
put -X- _ O
on -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
controversial -X- _ O
part -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
Ukraine -X- _ B-Location
's -X- _ I-Location
history -X- _ O
and -X- _ O
its -X- _ O
memorialisation -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
Canada. -X- _ B-Location
Yaroslav -X- _ B-Person
Hunka -X- _ I-Person
, -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
Ukrainian -X- _ O
veteran -X- _ O
who -X- _ O
was -X- _ O
applauded -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
parliament -X- _ O
this -X- _ O
week -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
served -X- _ O
with -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
Nazi -X- _ B-Organisation
unit -X- _ O
called -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
14th -X- _ B-Organisation
Waffen -X- _ I-Organisation
Grenadier -X- _ I-Organisation
Division -X- _ I-Organisation
of -X- _ I-Organisation
the -X- _ I-Organisation
SS -X- _ I-Organisation
- -X- _ O
also -X- _ O
known -X- _ O
as -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
Galicia -X- _ B-Organisation
Division -X- _ I-Organisation
- -X- _ O
that -X- _ O
was -X- _ O
formed -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
1943. -X- _ B-Temporal
His -X- _ O
appearance -X- _ O
was -X- _ O
criticised -X- _ O
by -X- _ O
Jewish -X- _ O
groups -X- _ O
and -X- _ O
other -X- _ O
parliamentarians -X- _ O
alike. -X- _ O
MP -X- _ B-Person
Anthony -X- _ I-Person
Rota -X- _ I-Person
, -X- _ O
who -X- _ O
invited -X- _ O
him -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
has -X- _ O
since -X- _ O
resigned -X- _ O
as -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
Speaker -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
the -X- _ B-Organisation
House -X- _ I-Organisation
of -X- _ I-Organisation
Commons -X- _ I-Organisation
, -X- _ O
saying -X- _ O
he -X- _ O
deeply -X- _ O
regretted -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
mistake -X- _ O

Praise -X- _ O
for -X- _ O
Nazi -X- _ B-Organisation
veteran -X- _ O
'embarrassing -X- _ O
' -X- _ O
- -X- _ O
Trudeau. -X- _ O
But -X- _ O
this -X- _ O
is -X- _ O
not -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
first -X- _ O
time -X- _ O
that -X- _ O
Ukraine -X- _ B-Location
's -X- _ I-Location
role -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
WWII -X- _ O
has -X- _ O
sparked -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
debate -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
Canada -X- _ B-Location
, -X- _ O
which -X- _ O
is -X- _ O
home -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
largest -X- _ O
Ukrainian -X- _ O
diaspora -X- _ O
outside -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
Europe -X- _ B-Location
. -X- _ O

Several -X- _ O
monuments -X- _ O
dedicated -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
Ukrainian -X- _ O
WWII -X- _ O
veterans -X- _ O
who -X- _ O
served -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
Galicia -X- _ B-Organisation
Division -X- _ I-Organisation
exist -X- _ O
across -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
country. -X- _ O
Jewish -X- _ O
groups -X- _ O
have -X- _ O
long -X- _ O
denounced -X- _ O
these -X- _ O
dedications -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
arguing -X- _ O
soldiers -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
Galicia -X- _ B-Organisation
Division -X- _ I-Organisation
swore -X- _ O
allegiance -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
Adolf -X- _ B-Person
Hitler -X- _ I-Person
, -X- _ O
and -X- _ O
were -X- _ O
either -X- _ O
complicit -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
Nazi -X- _ B-Organisation
Germany -X- _ I-Organisation
's -X- _ I-Organisation
crimes -X- _ O
or -X- _ O
had -X- _ O
committed -X- _ O
crimes -X- _ O
themselves. -X- _ O
But -X- _ O
for -X- _ O
some -X- _ O
Ukrainians -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
these -X- _ O
veterans -X- _ O
are -X- _ O
viewed -X- _ O
as -X- _ O
freedom -X- _ O
fighters -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
who -X- _ O
only -X- _ O
fought -X- _ O
alongside -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
Nazis -X- _ B-Organisation
to -X- _ O
resist -X- _ O
the -X- _ B-Organisation
Soviets -X- _ I-Organisation
in -X- _ O
their -X- _ O
quest -X- _ O
for -X- _ O
an -X- _ O
independent -X- _ O
Ukraine -X- _ B-Location

During -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
war -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
more -X- _ O
than -X- _ O
one -X- _ O
million -X- _ O
Jews -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
Ukraine -X- _ B-Location
were -X- _ O
killed -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
mostly -X- _ O
between -X- _ O
1941 -X- _ B-Temporal
and -X- _ O
1942. -X- _ B-Temporal
Most -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
them -X- _ O
were -X- _ O
shot -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
death -X- _ O
near -X- _ O
their -X- _ O
homes -X- _ O
by -X- _ O
Nazi -X- _ B-Organisation
Germans -X- _ I-Organisation
and -X- _ O
their -X- _ O
collaborators. -X- _ O
The -X- _ B-Organisation
Galicia -X- _ I-Organisation
Division -X- _ I-Organisation
has -X- _ O
been -X- _ O
accused -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
committing -X- _ O
war -X- _ O
crimes -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
but -X- _ O
its -X- _ O
members -X- _ O
have -X- _ O
never -X- _ O
been -X- _ O
found -X- _ O
guilty -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
court -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
law -X- _ O
. -X- _ O

Jewish -X- _ O
groups -X- _ O
have -X- _ O
condemned -X- _ O
Canadian -X- _ O
monuments -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
Ukrainian -X- _ O
veterans -X- _ O
who -X- _ O
fought -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
Waffen-SS -X- _ B-Organisation
, -X- _ O
saying -X- _ O
they -X- _ O
are -X- _ O
" -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
glorification -X- _ O
and -X- _ O
celebration -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
those -X- _ O
who -X- _ O
actively -X- _ O
participated -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
Holocaust -X- _ O
crimes -X- _ O
" -X- _ O
. -X- _ O
Image -X- _ O
source -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
Getty -X- _ O
ImagesImage -X- _ O
caption -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
A -X- _ O
controversial -X- _ O
sculpture -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
Ukrainian -X- _ O
soldier -X- _ O
Roman -X- _ B-Person
Shukhevych -X- _ I-Person
, -X- _ O
located -X- _ O
near -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
Ukrainian -X- _ B-Location
Youth -X- _ I-Location
Association -X- _ I-Location
in -X- _ I-Location
Edmonton. -X- _ I-Location
One -X- _ O
such -X- _ O
monument -X- _ O
sits -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
private -X- _ O
Ukrainian -X- _ O
cemetery -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
Oakville -X- _ B-Location
, -X- _ I-Location
Ontario -X- _ I-Location
, -X- _ O
and -X- _ O
features -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
insignia -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
the -X- _ B-Organisation
Galicia -X- _ I-Organisation
Division. -X- _ I-Organisation
Another -X- _ O
was -X- _ O
put -X- _ O
up -X- _ O
by -X- _ O
Ukrainian -X- _ O
WWII -X- _ O
veterans -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
Edmonton -X- _ B-Location
, -X- _ I-Location
Alberta. -X- _ I-Location
A -X- _ O
third -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
also -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
Edmonton -X- _ B-Location
, -X- _ O
depicts -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
bust -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
Roman -X- _ B-Person
Shukhevych -X- _ I-Person
, -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
Ukrainian -X- _ O
nationalist -X- _ O
leader -X- _ O
and -X- _ O
Nazi -X- _ B-Organisation
collaborator -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
whose -X- _ O
units -X- _ O
are -X- _ O
accused -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
massacring -X- _ O
Jews -X- _ O
and -X- _ O
Poles. -X- _ O
Shukhevych -X- _ B-Person
's -X- _ I-Person
involvement -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
however -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
is -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
matter -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
debate -X- _ O
and -X- _ O
he -X- _ O
was -X- _ O
not -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
member -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
the -X- _ B-Organisation
Galicia -X- _ I-Organisation
Division. -X- _ I-Organisation
The -X- _ O
monuments -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
which -X- _ O
date -X- _ O
back -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
1970s -X- _ B-Temporal
and -X- _ I-Temporal
80s -X- _ I-Temporal
, -X- _ O
have -X- _ O
all -X- _ O
been -X- _ O
vandalised -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
recent -X- _ O
years -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
with -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
word -X- _ O
" -X- _ O
Nazi -X- _ B-Organisation
" -X- _ I-Organisation
painted -X- _ O
across -X- _ O
them -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
red -X- _ O
. -X- _ O

Why -X- _ O
is -X- _ O
there -X- _ O
disagreement -X- _ O
on -X- _ O
what -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
monuments -X- _ O
stand -X- _ O
for -X- _ O
? -X- _ O
It -X- _ O
goes -X- _ O
back -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
Ukraine -X- _ B-Location
's -X- _ I-Location
history -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
war -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
as -X- _ O
well -X- _ O
as -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
make-up -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
Canada -X- _ B-Location
's -X- _ I-Location
large -X- _ O
Ukrainian -X- _ O
diaspora -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
said -X- _ O
David -X- _ B-Person
Marples -X- _ I-Person
, -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
professor -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
eastern -X- _ O
European -X- _ O
history -X- _ O
at -X- _ O
the -X- _ B-Location
University -X- _ I-Location
of -X- _ I-Location
Alberta. -X- _ I-Location
During -X- _ O
WWII -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
millions -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
Ukrainians -X- _ O
served -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
Soviet -X- _ B-Organisation
Red -X- _ I-Organisation
Army -X- _ I-Organisation
, -X- _ O
but -X- _ O
thousands -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
others -X- _ O
fought -X- _ O
on -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
German -X- _ O
side -X- _ O
under -X- _ O
the -X- _ B-Organisation
Galicia -X- _ I-Organisation
Division. -X- _ I-Organisation
Those -X- _ O
who -X- _ O
fought -X- _ O
with -X- _ O
Germany -X- _ B-Location
believed -X- _ O
it -X- _ O
would -X- _ O
grant -X- _ O
them -X- _ O
an -X- _ O
independent -X- _ O
state -X- _ O
free -X- _ O
from -X- _ O
Soviet -X- _ O
rule -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
Prof -X- _ B-Person
Marples -X- _ I-Person
said. -X- _ O
At -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
time -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
Ukrainians -X- _ O
resented -X- _ O
the -X- _ B-Organisation
Soviets -X- _ I-Organisation
for -X- _ O
their -X- _ O
role -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
Great -X- _ O
Ukrainian -X- _ O
Famine -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
1932-33 -X- _ B-Temporal
, -X- _ O
also -X- _ O
known -X- _ O
as -X- _ O
Holodomor -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
which -X- _ O
killed -X- _ O
an -X- _ O
estimated -X- _ O
five -X- _ O
million -X- _ O
Ukrainians -X- _ O
. -X- _ O

Far-right -X- _ O
ideologies -X- _ O
were -X- _ O
also -X- _ O
gaining -X- _ O
traction -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
most -X- _ O
European -X- _ O
countries -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
1930s -X- _ B-Temporal
- -X- _ O
including -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
UK -X- _ B-Location
- -X- _ O
and -X- _ O
Ukraine -X- _ B-Location
was -X- _ O
no -X- _ O
exception -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
said -X- _ O
Prof -X- _ B-Person
Marples -X- _ I-Person
. -X- _ O

Following -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
defeat -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
Germany -X- _ B-Location
, -X- _ O
some -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
the -X- _ B-Organisation
Galicia -X- _ I-Organisation
Division -X- _ I-Organisation
soldiers -X- _ O
were -X- _ O
allowed -X- _ O
entry -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
Canada -X- _ B-Location
after -X- _ O
surrendering -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
Allied -X- _ B-Organisation
forces -X- _ I-Organisation
- -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
move -X- _ O
that -X- _ O
was -X- _ O
resisted -X- _ O
by -X- _ O
Jewish -X- _ O
groups -X- _ O
at -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
time -X- _ O
. -X- _ O

Some -X- _ O
Canadians -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
Ukrainian -X- _ O
descent -X- _ O
view -X- _ O
these -X- _ O
soldiers -X- _ B-MilitaryPlatform
and -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
broader -X- _ O
Galicia -X- _ B-Organisation
Division -X- _ I-Organisation
as -X- _ O
" -X- _ O
national -X- _ O
heroes -X- _ O
" -X- _ O
who -X- _ O
fought -X- _ O
for -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
country -X- _ O
's -X- _ O
independence. -X- _ O
They -X- _ O
also -X- _ O
argue -X- _ O
that -X- _ O
their -X- _ O
collaboration -X- _ O
with -X- _ O
Nazi -X- _ B-Organisation
Germany -X- _ I-Organisation
was -X- _ O
short-lived -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
and -X- _ O
that -X- _ O
they -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
including -X- _ O
Shukhevych -X- _ B-Person
, -X- _ O
had -X- _ O
eventually -X- _ O
fought -X- _ O
both -X- _ O
the -X- _ B-Organisation
Soviets -X- _ I-Organisation
and -X- _ O
the -X- _ B-Organisation
Germans -X- _ I-Organisation
for -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
free -X- _ O
Ukraine. -X- _ B-Location
But -X- _ O
the -X- _ B-Organisation
Jewish -X- _ I-Organisation
community -X- _ I-Organisation
views -X- _ O
this -X- _ O
differently. -X- _ O
" -X- _ O
The -X- _ O
bottom -X- _ O
line -X- _ O
is -X- _ O
that -X- _ O
this -X- _ O
unit -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
the -X- _ B-Organisation
14th -X- _ I-Organisation
SS -X- _ I-Organisation
unit -X- _ I-Organisation
, -X- _ O
were -X- _ O
Nazis -X- _ B-Organisation
, -X- _ O
" -X- _ O
B'nai -X- _ O
Brith -X- _ O
Canada -X- _ B-Location
leader -X- _ O
Michael -X- _ B-Person
Mostyn -X- _ I-Person
told -X- _ O
the -X- _ B-Organisation
BBC -X- _ I-Organisation
. -X- _ O

Canada -X- _ B-Location
has -X- _ O
reckoned -X- _ O
with -X- _ O
this -X- _ O
history -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
past -X- _ O
through -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
commission -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
1985 -X- _ B-Temporal
, -X- _ O
which -X- _ O
was -X- _ O
tasked -X- _ O
with -X- _ O
investigating -X- _ O
allegations -X- _ O
that -X- _ O
Canada -X- _ B-Location
had -X- _ O
become -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
haven -X- _ O
for -X- _ O
Nazi -X- _ B-Organisation
war -X- _ O
criminals -X- _ O

A -X- _ O
report -X- _ O
released -X- _ O
by -X- _ O
the -X- _ B-Organisation
commission -X- _ I-Organisation
the -X- _ O
following -X- _ O
year -X- _ O
concluded -X- _ O
that -X- _ O
there -X- _ O
is -X- _ O
no -X- _ O
evidence -X- _ O
tying -X- _ O
Ukrainians -X- _ O
who -X- _ O
fought -X- _ O
with -X- _ O
Nazi -X- _ B-Organisation
Germany -X- _ I-Organisation
to -X- _ O
specific -X- _ O
war -X- _ O
crimes. -X- _ O
And -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
" -X- _ O
mere -X- _ O
membership -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
the -X- _ B-Organisation
Galicia -X- _ I-Organisation
Division -X- _ I-Organisation
is -X- _ O
insufficient -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
justify -X- _ O
prosecution -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
" -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
report -X- _ O
added. -X- _ O
The -X- _ O
report -X- _ O
's -X- _ O
findings -X- _ O
have -X- _ O
since -X- _ O
been -X- _ O
contested -X- _ O
by -X- _ O
Jewish -X- _ B-Organisation
groups -X- _ I-Organisation
and -X- _ O
some -X- _ O
historians -X- _ O
. -X- _ O

Russian -X- _ O
disinformation -X- _ O
targets -X- _ O
Ukraine -X- _ B-Location
's -X- _ I-Location
history. -X- _ O
As -X- _ O
this -X- _ O
historical -X- _ O
debate -X- _ O
entered -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
21st -X- _ O
century -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
it -X- _ O
was -X- _ O
made -X- _ O
more -X- _ O
complicated -X- _ O
by -X- _ O
modern -X- _ O
Russian -X- _ O
propaganda -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
which -X- _ O
falsely -X- _ O
labelled -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
Ukrainian -X- _ B-Organisation
government -X- _ I-Organisation
as -X- _ O
Nazis -X- _ B-Organisation
to -X- _ O
justify -X- _ O
its -X- _ O
invasion -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
country. -X- _ O
Prof -X- _ B-Person
Marples -X- _ I-Person
said -X- _ O
that -X- _ O
while -X- _ O
far-right -X- _ O
extremism -X- _ O
still -X- _ O
exists -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
Ukraine -X- _ B-Location
, -X- _ O
it -X- _ O
is -X- _ O
much -X- _ O
smaller -X- _ O
than -X- _ O
what -X- _ O
Russian -X- _ O
propaganda -X- _ O
tries -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
make -X- _ O
people -X- _ O
believe -X- _ O
. -X- _ O

And -X- _ O
Ukrainian -X- _ O
elected -X- _ O
officials -X- _ O
are -X- _ O
not -X- _ O
tied -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
any -X- _ O
far-right -X- _ O
group -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
country. -X- _ O
" -X- _ O
Russia -X- _ B-Location
has -X- _ O
greatly -X- _ O
simplified -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
narrative -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
" -X- _ O
Prof -X- _ B-Person
Marples -X- _ I-Person
said -X- _ O
. -X- _ O

Ukrainian -X- _ O
groups -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
Canada -X- _ B-Location
say -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
row -X- _ O
over -X- _ O
monuments -X- _ O
and -X- _ O
Mr -X- _ B-Person
Hunka -X- _ I-Person
's -X- _ I-Person
appearance -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
parliament -X- _ O
is -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
result -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
this -X- _ O
propaganda -X- _ O
. -X- _ O

As -X- _ O
far -X- _ O
back -X- _ O
as -X- _ O
2017 -X- _ B-Temporal
, -X- _ O
before -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
invasion -X- _ O
but -X- _ O
when -X- _ O
Russia-Ukraine -X- _ B-Location
tensions -X- _ O
were -X- _ O
high -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
the -X- _ B-Organisation
Russian -X- _ I-Organisation
embassy -X- _ I-Organisation
in -X- _ O
Canada -X- _ B-Location
criticized -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
existence -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
Ukrainian -X- _ O
monuments -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
Canada -X- _ B-Location
, -X- _ O
accusing -X- _ O
them -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
paying -X- _ O
tribute -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
" -X- _ O
Nazi -X- _ B-Organisation
collaborators -X- _ I-Organisation
" -X- _ O
. -X- _ O
Taras -X- _ B-Person
Podilsky -X- _ I-Person
, -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
spokesperson -X- _ O
for -X- _ O
the -X- _ B-Organisation
Ukrainian -X- _ I-Organisation
Youth -X- _ I-Organisation
Unity -X- _ I-Organisation
Complex -X- _ I-Organisation
in -X- _ O
Edmonton -X- _ B-Location
that -X- _ O
houses -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
bust -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
Shukhevych -X- _ B-Person
, -X- _ O
said -X- _ O
Mr -X- _ B-Person
Hunka -X- _ I-Person
's -X- _ I-Person
swift -X- _ O
renunciation -X- _ O
by -X- _ O
Canadian -X- _ O
politicians -X- _ O
is -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
latest -X- _ O
effect -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
Russia -X- _ O
's -X- _ O
disinformation -X- _ O
campaign -X- _ O

Mr -X- _ B-Person
Mostyn -X- _ I-Person
of -X- _ O
B'nai -X- _ O
Brith -X- _ O
said -X- _ O
he -X- _ O
acknowledged -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
complicated -X- _ O
nature -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
this -X- _ O
history -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
especially -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
some -X- _ O
within -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
Ukrainian -X- _ O
diaspora. -X- _ O
But -X- _ O
he -X- _ O
said -X- _ O
any -X- _ O
ties -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
Nazism -X- _ O
" -X- _ O
is -X- _ O
not -X- _ O
something -X- _ O
that -X- _ O
we -X- _ O
can -X- _ O
allow -X- _ O
future -X- _ O
generations -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
celebrate -X- _ O
or -X- _ O
whitewash -X- _ O
" -X- _ O
. -X- _ O

More -X- _ O
broadly -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
Holocaust -X- _ O
scholars -X- _ O
have -X- _ O
called -X- _ O
out -X- _ O
several -X- _ O
eastern -X- _ O
European -X- _ O
countries -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
recent -X- _ O
years -X- _ O
for -X- _ O
downplaying -X- _ O
their -X- _ O
role -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
massacre -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
Jewish -X- _ B-Organisation
people -X- _ I-Organisation
during -X- _ O
WWII -X- _ O

Both -X- _ O
Jewish -X- _ B-Organisation
groups -X- _ I-Organisation
in -X- _ O
Canada -X- _ B-Location
and -X- _ O
Canadians -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
Ukrainian -X- _ O
descent -X- _ O
behind -X- _ O
these -X- _ O
monuments -X- _ O
said -X- _ O
they -X- _ O
have -X- _ O
had -X- _ O
conversations -X- _ O
about -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
issue. -X- _ O
However -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
both -X- _ O
said -X- _ O
they -X- _ O
were -X- _ O
unable -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
agree -X- _ O
on -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
path -X- _ O
forward. -X- _ O
" -X- _ O
It -X- _ O
is -X- _ O
on -X- _ O
our -X- _ O
own -X- _ O
private -X- _ O
property -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
it -X- _ O
is -X- _ O
not -X- _ O
on -X- _ O
public -X- _ O
property -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
and -X- _ O
it -X- _ O
is -X- _ O
for -X- _ O
us -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
have -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
symbol -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
Ukrainian -X- _ O
freedom -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
" -X- _ O
Mr -X- _ B-Person
Podilsky -X- _ I-Person
said -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
Shukhevych -X- _ B-Location
bust -X- _ I-Location
in -X- _ I-Location
Edmonton. -X- _ I-Location
" -X- _ O
We -X- _ O
know -X- _ O
there -X- _ O
was -X- _ O
no -X- _ O
wrongdoing -X- _ O
. -X- _ O

" -X- _ O
Mr -X- _ B-Person
Mostyn -X- _ I-Person
said -X- _ O
that -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
him -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
recent -X- _ O
episode -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
Canada -X- _ B-Organisation
's -X- _ I-Organisation
House -X- _ I-Organisation
of -X- _ I-Organisation
Commons -X- _ I-Organisation
shows -X- _ O
that -X- _ O
there -X- _ O
are -X- _ O
gaps -X- _ O
when -X- _ O
it -X- _ O
comes -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
Canada -X- _ B-Location
's -X- _ I-Location
knowledge -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
Nazi -X- _ B-Organisation
history. -X- _ O
" -X- _ O
We -X- _ O
have -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
situation -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
Canada -X- _ B-Location
where -X- _ O
we -X- _ O
do -X- _ O
n't -X- _ O
know -X- _ O
our -X- _ O
own -X- _ O
history -X- _ O
when -X- _ O
it -X- _ O
comes -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
Nazi -X- _ B-Organisation
perpetrators -X- _ I-Organisation
that -X- _ O
made -X- _ O
their -X- _ O
way -X- _ O
into -X- _ O
this -X- _ O
country -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
" -X- _ O
he -X- _ O
said -X- _ O
. -X- _ O

He -X- _ O
and -X- _ O
others -X- _ O
within -X- _ O
the -X- _ B-Organisation
Jewish -X- _ I-Organisation
community -X- _ I-Organisation
in -X- _ O
Canada -X- _ B-Location
have -X- _ O
called -X- _ O
for -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
renewed -X- _ O
examination -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
this -X- _ O
history. -X- _ O
" -X- _ O
It -X- _ O
really -X- _ O
is -X- _ O
important -X- _ O
that -X- _ O
leadership -X- _ O
be -X- _ O
shown -X- _ O
at -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
highest -X- _ O
level -X- _ O
by -X- _ O
our -X- _ O
prime -X- _ O
minister -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
finally -X- _ O
open -X- _ O
this -X- _ O
up -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
because -X- _ O
this -X- _ O
is -X- _ O
something -X- _ O
that -X- _ O
Jewish -X- _ B-Organisation
community -X- _ I-Organisation
has -X- _ O
been -X- _ O
demanding -X- _ O
for -X- _ O
decades -X- _ O
. -X- _ O

President -X- _ B-Person
Joe -X- _ I-Person
Biden -X- _ I-Person
has -X- _ O
vowed -X- _ O
continued -X- _ O
US -X- _ B-Organisation
support -X- _ O
for -X- _ O
Ukraine -X- _ B-Location
, -X- _ O
after -X- _ O
further -X- _ O
military -X- _ O
funding -X- _ O
was -X- _ O
excluded -X- _ O
from -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
last-minute -X- _ O
congressional -X- _ O
budget -X- _ O
deal -X- _ O
. -X- _ O

The -X- _ O
temporary -X- _ O
measure -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
pushed -X- _ O
through -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
avert -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
government -X- _ O
shutdown -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
did -X- _ O
not -X- _ O
include -X- _ O
$ -X- _ B-Money
6bn -X- _ I-Money
( -X- _ O
£4.92bn -X- _ B-Money
) -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
military -X- _ O
aid -X- _ O
for -X- _ O
Kyiv -X- _ B-Location
- -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
top -X- _ O
White -X- _ B-Organisation
House -X- _ I-Organisation
priority -X- _ O

Hardline -X- _ B-Organisation
Republicans -X- _ I-Organisation
oppose -X- _ O
further -X- _ O
military -X- _ O
aid -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
with -X- _ O
many -X- _ O
openly -X- _ O
opposing -X- _ O
Mr -X- _ B-Person
Biden -X- _ I-Person
's -X- _ I-Person
approach -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
war -X- _ O
. -X- _ O

But -X- _ O
on -X- _ O
Sunday -X- _ O
Mr -X- _ B-Person
Biden -X- _ I-Person
said -X- _ O
Ukraine -X- _ B-Location
could -X- _ O
" -X- _ O
count -X- _ O
on -X- _ O
" -X- _ O
US -X- _ B-Organisation
support -X- _ O
. -X- _ O

" -X- _ O
We -X- _ O
can -X- _ O
not -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
under -X- _ O
any -X- _ O
circumstances -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
allow -X- _ O
US -X- _ B-Organisation
support -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
Ukraine -X- _ B-Location
to -X- _ O
be -X- _ O
interrupted -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
" -X- _ O
Mr -X- _ B-Person
Biden -X- _ I-Person
said. -X- _ O
" -X- _ O
I -X- _ O
can -X- _ O
reassure -X- _ O
[ -X- _ O
Ukraine -X- _ B-Location
] -X- _ O
we -X- _ O
'll -X- _ O
get -X- _ O
there -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
that -X- _ O
we -X- _ O
're -X- _ O
going -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
get -X- _ O
it -X- _ O
done -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
" -X- _ O
he -X- _ O
said -X- _ O
on -X- _ O
restoring -X- _ O
funding -X- _ O
for -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
war. -X- _ O
" -X- _ O
I -X- _ O
want -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
assure -X- _ O
our -X- _ O
American -X- _ B-Organisation
allies -X- _ I-Organisation
... -X- _ O
that -X- _ O
you -X- _ O
can -X- _ O
count -X- _ O
on -X- _ O
our -X- _ O
support -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
we -X- _ O
will -X- _ O
not -X- _ O
walk -X- _ O
away. -X- _ O
" -X- _ O
The -X- _ B-Organisation
US -X- _ I-Organisation
has -X- _ O
already -X- _ O
supplied -X- _ O
some -X- _ O
$ -X- _ B-Money
46bn -X- _ I-Money
( -X- _ O
£37bn -X- _ B-Money
) -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
military -X- _ O
aid -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
Ukraine -X- _ B-Location
since -X- _ O
Russian -X- _ O
launched -X- _ O
its -X- _ O
full -X- _ O
scale -X- _ O
invasion -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
February -X- _ B-Temporal
2022 -X- _ I-Temporal
. -X- _ O

President -X- _ B-Person
Biden -X- _ I-Person
has -X- _ O
requested -X- _ O
another -X- _ O
$ -X- _ B-Money
24bn -X- _ I-Money
( -X- _ O
£19bn -X- _ B-Money
) -X- _ O
. -X- _ O

And -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
recent -X- _ O
months -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
US -X- _ B-Organisation
has -X- _ O
sent -X- _ O
state -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
art -X- _ O
equipment -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
Kyiv -X- _ B-Location
- -X- _ O
including -X- _ O
long-range -X- _ B-MilitaryPlatform
missiles -X- _ I-MilitaryPlatform
and -X- _ O
Abrams -X- _ B-MilitaryPlatform
tanks. -X- _ I-MilitaryPlatform
It -X- _ O
comes -X- _ O
as -X- _ O
Kyiv -X- _ B-Location
's -X- _ I-Location
forces -X- _ B-MilitaryPlatform
continue -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
launch -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
slow -X- _ O
moving -X- _ O
counter-offensive -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
south -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
country. -X- _ O
US -X- _ B-Organisation
Congress -X- _ I-Organisation
avoids -X- _ O
government -X- _ O
shutdown -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
last-minute -X- _ O
dealRussian -X- _ O
video -X- _ O
'shows -X- _ O
Black -X- _ B-Organisation
Sea -X- _ I-Organisation
fleet -X- _ I-Organisation
commander -X- _ O
alive'. -X- _ O
How -X- _ O
Zelensky -X- _ B-Person
is -X- _ O
grappling -X- _ O
with -X- _ O
Western -X- _ O
war -X- _ O
fatigue. -X- _ O
But -X- _ O
Saturday -X- _ O
's -X- _ O
temporary -X- _ O
budget -X- _ O
agreement -X- _ O
- -X- _ O
which -X- _ O
will -X- _ O
fund -X- _ O
the -X- _ B-Organisation
US -X- _ I-Organisation
federal -X- _ I-Organisation
government -X- _ I-Organisation
for -X- _ O
45 -X- _ O
days -X- _ O
- -X- _ O
stripped -X- _ O
out -X- _ O
continued -X- _ O
military -X- _ O
funding -X- _ O
for -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
time -X- _ O
being -X- _ O
. -X- _ O

Senior -X- _ O
Senate -X- _ O
leaders -X- _ O
from -X- _ O
both -X- _ O
parties -X- _ O
released -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
joint -X- _ O
statement -X- _ O
signalling -X- _ O
their -X- _ O
intention -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
" -X- _ O
ensure -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
US -X- _ B-Organisation
government -X- _ I-Organisation
continues -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
provide -X- _ O
" -X- _ O
support -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
Ukraine -X- _ B-Location
in -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
coming -X- _ O
weeks -X- _ O

But -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
move -X- _ O
- -X- _ O
which -X- _ O
came -X- _ O
just -X- _ O
nine -X- _ O
days -X- _ O
after -X- _ O
President -X- _ B-Person
Volodymyr -X- _ I-Person
Zelensky -X- _ I-Person
flew -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
Washington -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
plead -X- _ O
for -X- _ O
further -X- _ O
support -X- _ O
- -X- _ O
reflects -X- _ O
increasing -X- _ O
opposition -X- _ O
from -X- _ O
hard-right -X- _ B-Organisation
Republicans -X- _ I-Organisation
in -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
House -X- _ B-Organisation
of -X- _ I-Organisation
Representatives -X- _ I-Organisation
to -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
war -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
recent -X- _ O
months. -X- _ O
Republicans -X- _ B-Organisation
control -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
House -X- _ B-Organisation
of -X- _ I-Organisation
Representatives -X- _ I-Organisation
, -X- _ O
with -X- _ O
Democrats -X- _ B-Organisation
enjoying -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
wafer-thin -X- _ O
majority -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
Senate. -X- _ B-Organisation
Both -X- _ O
need -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
approve -X- _ O
legislation -X- _ O
on -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
budget -X- _ O
before -X- _ O
it -X- _ O
is -X- _ O
signed -X- _ O
into -X- _ O
law -X- _ O
. -X- _ O

Florida -X- _ B-Person
congressman -X- _ I-Person
Matt -X- _ I-Person
Gaetz -X- _ I-Person
told -X- _ O
reporters -X- _ O
on -X- _ O
Saturday -X- _ O
that -X- _ O
funding -X- _ O
" -X- _ O
already -X- _ O
authorised -X- _ O
out -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
this -X- _ O
Congress -X- _ B-Organisation
is -X- _ O
somewhere -X- _ O
between -X- _ O
more -X- _ O
than -X- _ O
enough -X- _ O
and -X- _ O
way -X- _ O
too -X- _ O
much -X- _ O
" -X- _ O

And -X- _ O
Georgia -X- _ B-Person
Representative -X- _ I-Person
Marjorie -X- _ I-Person
Taylor-Green -X- _ I-Person
said -X- _ O
far -X- _ O
too -X- _ O
much -X- _ O
aid -X- _ O
had -X- _ O
already -X- _ O
been -X- _ O
allocated -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
Kyiv -X- _ B-Location
, -X- _ O
saying -X- _ O
" -X- _ O
Ukraine -X- _ B-Location
is -X- _ O
not -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
51st -X- _ O
state -X- _ O
" -X- _ O
. -X- _ O

Their -X- _ O
approach -X- _ O
provoked -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
furious -X- _ O
reaction -X- _ O
from -X- _ O
Democratic -X- _ B-Organisation
Party -X- _ I-Organisation
senators. -X- _ O
" -X- _ O
I -X- _ O
ca -X- _ O
n't -X- _ O
believe -X- _ O
people -X- _ O
are -X- _ O
going -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
walk -X- _ O
away -X- _ O
from -X- _ O
Ukraine -X- _ B-Location
at -X- _ O
this -X- _ O
moment -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
time -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
" -X- _ O
Senator -X- _ B-Person
Mark -X- _ I-Person
Warner -X- _ I-Person
said. -X- _ O
Despite -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
row -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
officials -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
Kyiv -X- _ B-Location
have -X- _ O
sought -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
frame -X- _ O
this -X- _ O
new -X- _ O
45-day -X- _ O
funding -X- _ O
agreement -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
the -X- _ B-Organisation
US -X- _ I-Organisation
as -X- _ O
an -X- _ O
" -X- _ O
opportunity -X- _ O
" -X- _ O
for -X- _ O
its -X- _ O
diplomats -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
secure -X- _ O
longer-term -X- _ O
support. -X- _ O
It -X- _ O
's -X- _ O
more -X- _ O
like -X- _ O
an -X- _ O
unwanted -X- _ O
deadline -X- _ O
. -X- _ O

Ukraine -X- _ B-Organisation
's -X- _ I-Organisation
foreign -X- _ I-Organisation
ministry -X- _ I-Organisation
says -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
" -X- _ O
flow -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
US -X- _ B-Organisation
aid -X- _ O
wo -X- _ O
n't -X- _ O
change -X- _ O
" -X- _ O
with -X- _ O
$ -X- _ B-Money
3bn -X- _ I-Money
of -X- _ O
humanitarian -X- _ O
and -X- _ O
military -X- _ O
support -X- _ O
set -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
still -X- _ O
arrive -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
but -X- _ O
it -X- _ O
concedes -X- _ O
" -X- _ O
ongoing -X- _ O
programmes -X- _ O
" -X- _ O
might -X- _ O
be -X- _ O
affected -X- _ O

But -X- _ O
one -X- _ O
Ukrainian -X- _ O
MP -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
Oleksi -X- _ B-Person
Goncharenko -X- _ I-Person
, -X- _ O
admitted -X- _ O
that -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
suspended -X- _ O
funding -X- _ O
was -X- _ O
causing -X- _ O
concern -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
Kyiv. -X- _ B-Location
" -X- _ O
The -X- _ O
vote -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
US -X- _ B-Organisation
Congress -X- _ I-Organisation
is -X- _ O
disturbing. -X- _ O
The -X- _ B-Organisation
US -X- _ I-Organisation
said -X- _ O
they -X- _ O
would -X- _ O
be -X- _ O
with -X- _ O
Ukraine -X- _ B-Location
as -X- _ O
long -X- _ O
as -X- _ O
it -X- _ O
takes -X- _ O
and -X- _ O
now -X- _ O
see -X- _ O
how -X- _ O
support -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
Ukraine -X- _ B-Location
is -X- _ O
excluded -X- _ O
from -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
stop-gap -X- _ O
deal. -X- _ O
This -X- _ O
is -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
sign -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
alarm -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
not -X- _ O
only -X- _ O
for -X- _ O
Ukraine -X- _ B-Location
, -X- _ O
but -X- _ O
for -X- _ O
Europe -X- _ B-Location
, -X- _ O
too -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
" -X- _ O
he -X- _ O
told -X- _ O
the -X- _ B-Organisation
BBC. -X- _ I-Organisation
This -X- _ O
political -X- _ O
turmoil -X- _ O
is -X- _ O
one -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
several -X- _ O
symptoms -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
Western -X- _ O
fatigue. -X- _ O
The -X- _ O
growing -X- _ O
scepticism -X- _ O
from -X- _ O
some -X- _ O
Republicans -X- _ B-Organisation
and -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
recent -X- _ O
election -X- _ O
victory -X- _ O
for -X- _ O
a -X- _ O
populist -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
pro-Moscow -X- _ O
party -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
Slovakia -X- _ B-Location
are -X- _ O
concerning -X- _ O
for -X- _ O
both -X- _ O
Ukraine -X- _ B-Location
and -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
European -X- _ B-Organisation
Union -X- _ I-Organisation
. -X- _ O

In -X- _ O
an -X- _ O
interview -X- _ O
with -X- _ O
the -X- _ B-Organisation
BBC -X- _ I-Organisation
in -X- _ O
Kyiv -X- _ B-Location
, -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
EU -X- _ B-Organisation
's -X- _ I-Organisation
most -X- _ O
senior -X- _ O
diplomat -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
Josep -X- _ B-Person
Borrell -X- _ I-Person
, -X- _ O
said -X- _ O
he -X- _ O
was -X- _ O
" -X- _ O
worried -X- _ O
" -X- _ O
by -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
latest -X- _ O
decision -X- _ O
on -X- _ O
funding -X- _ O
for -X- _ O
Ukraine -X- _ B-Location
by -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
US -X- _ B-Organisation
Congress -X- _ I-Organisation
. -X- _ O

" -X- _ O
I -X- _ O
do -X- _ O
n't -X- _ O
know -X- _ O
what -X- _ O
's -X- _ O
going -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
happen -X- _ O
in -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
future -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
" -X- _ O
he -X- _ O
told -X- _ O
the -X- _ B-Organisation
BBC. -X- _ I-Organisation
" -X- _ O
One -X- _ O
thing -X- _ O
is -X- _ O
clear -X- _ O
: -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
us -X- _ O
Europeans -X- _ B-Organisation
the -X- _ O
war -X- _ O
of -X- _ O
Russia -X- _ B-Location
against -X- _ O
Ukraine -X- _ B-Location
is -X- _ O
an -X- _ O
existential -X- _ O
threat -X- _ O
, -X- _ O
and -X- _ O
we -X- _ O
must -X- _ O
react -X- _ O
accordingly -X- _ O
. -X- _ O

" -X- _ O
In -X- _ O
his -X- _ O
daily -X- _ O
address -X- _ O
from -X- _ O
Kyiv -X- _ B-Location
, -X- _ O
President -X- _ B-Person
Zelensky -X- _ I-Person
said -X- _ O
no-one -X- _ O
should -X- _ O
be -X- _ O
able -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
" -X- _ O
turn -X- _ O
off -X- _ O
Ukraine -X- _ B-Location
's -X- _ I-Location
resilience -X- _ O
" -X- _ O
. -X- _ O
It -X- _ O
is -X- _ O
clear -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
country -X- _ O
will -X- _ O
continue -X- _ O
to -X- _ O
fight -X- _ O
with -X- _ O
or -X- _ O
without -X- _ O
help -X- _ O
from -X- _ O
the -X- _ O
West. -X- _ O
Ukraine -X- _ B-Location
knows -X- _ O
what -X- _ O
it -X- _ O
would -X- _ O
overwhelmingly -X- _ O
prefer -X- _ O
. -X- _ O

