-DOCSTART-	O
ABU	B-Location
DHABI	I-Location
–	O
Intrepid	O
Maven	O
23.3	O
concluded	O
in	O
the	O
United	B-Location
Arab	I-Location
Emirates	I-Location
on	O
May	B-Temporal
22.	I-Temporal
The	O
exercise	O
included	O
more	O
than	O
100	B-MilitaryPlatform
U.S.	I-MilitaryPlatform
Marines	I-MilitaryPlatform
and	I-MilitaryPlatform
Sailors	I-MilitaryPlatform
,	O
alongside	O
partnering	O
elements	O
of	O
the	O
United	B-Location
Arab	I-Location
Emirates	I-Location
Armed	B-MilitaryPlatform
Forces	I-MilitaryPlatform
,	O
who	O
conducted	O
infantry-based	O
close-quarters	O
combat	O
training	O
,	O
live-fire	O
close-air	O
support	O
exercises	O
,	O
and	O
expeditionary	O
airfield	O
operations	O
at	O
several	O
training	O
locations	O
throughout	O
the	O
country	O
.	O

“Planning	O
and	O
training	O
with	O
the	O
Emiratis	O
in	O
their	O
country	O
during	O
Intrepid	O
Maven	O
definitely	O
made	O
both	O
of	O
our	O
teams	O
better	O
,	O
and	O
I	O
think	O
it	O
made	O
our	O
partnership	O
stronger”	O
said	O
Maj.	B-Person
Dan	I-Person
Ealy	I-Person
,	O
Officer-in-Charge	O
of	O
Task	B-MilitaryPlatform
Force	I-MilitaryPlatform
51	I-MilitaryPlatform
/	I-MilitaryPlatform
5th	I-MilitaryPlatform
Marine	B-Organisation
Expeditionary	I-Organisation
Brigade’s	I-Organisation
Exercise	I-Organisation
Control	I-Organisation
Group	I-Organisation
(	O
ECG	O
)	O
.	O
“It	O
was	O
really	O
great	O
getting	O
to	O
work	O
with	O
such	O
a	O
professional	O
partner	O
,	O
and	O
it	O
gave	O
us	O
a	O
chance	O
to	O
practice	O
skills	O
that	O
are	O
vital	O
to	O
our	O
preparedness	O
as	O
a	O
crisis-response	B-MilitaryPlatform
task	I-MilitaryPlatform
force	I-MilitaryPlatform
,	O
like	O
planning	O
and	O
operating	O
in	O
a	O
foreign	O
and	O
expeditionary	O
environment	O
,	O
”	O
Ealy	B-Person
concluded.	O
“The	O
level	O
of	O
professionalism	O
the	O
Emiratis	O
displayed	O
made	O
our	O
bilateral	O
operations	O
smooth	O
and	O
maximized	O
the	O
time	O
we	O
had	O
to	O
train”	O
.	O

Task	B-MilitaryPlatform
Force	I-MilitaryPlatform
51	I-MilitaryPlatform
/	I-MilitaryPlatform
5’s	I-MilitaryPlatform
ECG	B-Organisation
provided	O
overall	O
command-and-control	O
of	O
the	O
exercise	O
,	O
while	O
also	O
managing	O
the	O
logistical	O
and	O
administrative	O
actions	O
required	O
to	O
support	O
multiple	O
subordinate	O
elements	O
–	O
these	O
included	O
elements	O
from	O
the	O
task	B-MilitaryPlatform
force’s	I-MilitaryPlatform
administrative	O
,	O
logistics	O
,	O
communications	O
,	O
force	O
protection	O
,	O
and	O
operations	O
directorates.	O
The	O
larger	O
force	B-MilitaryPlatform
of	I-MilitaryPlatform
U.S.	I-MilitaryPlatform
Marines	I-MilitaryPlatform
supporting	O
Intrepid	O
Maven	O
23.3	O
consisted	O
of	O
a	O
detachment	O
of	O
active-duty	B-MilitaryPlatform
Marines	I-MilitaryPlatform
from	O
Marine	B-Organisation
Corps	I-Organisation
Forces	I-Organisation
Command	I-Organisation
(	O
MARFORCOM	O
)	O
,	O
as	O
well	O
as	O
detachments	O
of	O
Marine	B-MilitaryPlatform
reservists	I-MilitaryPlatform
from	O
3rd	B-Organisation
Air	I-Organisation
Naval	I-Organisation
Gunfire	I-Organisation
Liaison	I-Organisation
Company	I-Organisation
and	O
Marine	B-Organisation
Air	I-Organisation
Control	I-Organisation
Group	I-Organisation
48.	I-Organisation
Partnering	O
elements	O
of	O
the	O
United	B-Location
Arab	I-Location
Emirates	I-Location
Armed	B-MilitaryPlatform
Forces	I-MilitaryPlatform
included	O
the	O
Presidential	B-MilitaryPlatform
Guard	I-MilitaryPlatform
and	O
Joint	B-MilitaryPlatform
Aviation	I-MilitaryPlatform
Command	I-MilitaryPlatform
.	O

Intrepid	O
Maven	O
23.3	O
marks	O
the	O
second	O
time	O
USCENTCOM	B-Organisation
has	O
conducted	O
an	O
Intrepid	O
Maven	O
exercise	O
in	O
the	O
United	B-Location
Arab	I-Location
Emirates	I-Location
,	O
and	O
the	O
seventh	O
time	O
Marines	B-MilitaryPlatform
have	O
held	O
the	O
exercise	O
in	O
the	O
Middle	B-Location
East.	I-Location
Exercise	O
Intrepid	O
Maven	O
is	O
a	O
U.S.	B-Organisation
Marine	I-Organisation
Corps	I-Organisation
Forces	I-Organisation
Central	I-Organisation
Command-conceptualized	I-Organisation
and	O
-implemented	O
exercise	O
series	O
,	O
designed	O
in	O
late	O
2021	B-Temporal
,	O
with	O
the	O
first	O
iteration	O
having	O
occurred	O
in	O
Jordan	B-Location
in	O
March	B-Temporal
2022.	I-Temporal
The	O
series	O
,	O
to	O
include	O
IM	O
23.3	O
,	O
is	O
designed	O
to	O
strengthen	O
partnerships	O
,	O
produce	O
training	O
opportunities	O
,	O
contribute	O
to	O
interoperability	O
,	O
and	O
to	O
improve	O
conditions	O
for	O
regional	O
security.	O
Episodic	O
in	O
nature	O
,	O
Intrepid	O
Maven	O
,	O
which	O
occurs	O
with	O
anywhere	O
from	O
one	O
to	O
any	O
of	O
a	O
number	O
of	O
partner	O
nations	O
during	O
each	O
iteration	O
,	O
is	O
a	O
force	O
deployment-tailored	O
training	O
series	O
designed	O
to	O
demonstrate	O
persistence	O
in	O
partnering	O
;	O
to	O
prepare	O
for	O
the	O
demands	O
of	O
a	O
volatile	O
and	O
fluid	O
AOR	O
;	O
to	O
conduct	O
unit-level	O
training	O
in	O
new	O
and	O
challenging	O
areas	O
,	O
spaces	O
and	O
facilities	O
;	O
and	O
to	O
demonstrate	O
service	O
ability	O
to	O
project	O
forces	O
to	O
meet	O
emergent	O
requirements	O
,	O
all	O
with	O
the	O
objective	O
of	O
gaining	O
and	O
maintaining	O
unit	O
readiness	O
,	O
deterring	O
malicious	O
adversary	O
intent	O
and	O
demonstrating	O
global	O
responsiveness	O
for	O
crisis-response	O
and	O
contingencies	O
.	O

U.S.	B-Organisation
Central	I-Organisation
Command	I-Organisation
named	O
U.S.	B-Person
Marine	I-Person
Corps	I-Person
Sgt.	I-Person
Steven	I-Person
Matsunaga	I-Person
as	O
the	O
winner	O
of	O
its	O
second	O
CENTCOM	B-Organisation
Innovation	O
Oasis	O
competition	O
on	O
May	B-Temporal
25	I-Temporal
,	I-Temporal
2023	I-Temporal
,	O
at	O
CENTCOM	B-Organisation
headquarters	O
in	O
Tampa.	B-Location
Matsunaga	B-Person
was	O
also	O
awarded	O
the	O
Defense	O
Meritorious	O
Service	O
Medal	O
for	O
his	O
development	O
of	O
a	O
total	O
force	O
deployment	O
dashboard	O
(	O
TFDD	O
)	O
that	O
will	O
help	O
to	O
fill	O
a	O
capability	O
gap	O
to	O
expedite	O
the	O
analysis	O
and	O
quality	O
control	O
of	O
large	O
quantities	O
of	O
records	O
instantaneously.	O
Matsunaga	B-Person
,	O
a	O
Marine	B-MilitaryPlatform
Air	I-MilitaryPlatform
Ground	I-MilitaryPlatform
Task	I-MilitaryPlatform
Force	I-MilitaryPlatform
planning	O
specialist	O
,	O
and	O
the	O
force	O
deployment	O
noncommissioned	O
officer	B-Person
in	O
charge	O
at	O
U.S.	B-Organisation
Marine	I-Organisation
Corps	I-Organisation
Forces	I-Organisation
,	O
Central	O
Command	O
,	O
crafted	O
the	O
TFDD	O
program	O
with	O
hopes	O
of	O
it	O
being	O
deployed	O
throughout	O
the	O
military	O
planning	O
and	O
execution	O
community	O
and	O
across	O
the	O
CENTCOM	B-Organisation
area	O
of	O
responsibility	O
.	O

“The	O
fact	O
that	O
I	O
was	O
able	O
to	O
take	O
a	O
program	O
,	O
bring	O
it	O
here	O
to	O
CENTCOM	B-Organisation
,	O
bring	O
it	O
to	O
General	B-Person
Kurilla	I-Person
's	I-Person
attention	O
,	O
and	O
speak	O
to	O
a	O
wide	O
audience	O
and	O
have	O
them	O
really	O
grasp	O
that	O
problem	O
and	O
a	O
solution	O
for	O
it	O
...	O
That	O
's	O
HUGE	O
!	O
,	O
”	O
Matsunaga	B-Person
said.	O
“At	O
the	O
end	O
of	O
the	O
day	O
,	O
I	O
'm	O
really	O
just	O
trying	O
to	O
give	O
back	O
,	O
not	O
just	O
to	O
Marine	B-Organisation
Corps	I-Organisation
or	O
my	O
MOS	B-Organisation
,	O
but	O
to	O
anyone	O
that	O
might	O
benefit	O
with	O
the	O
application.	O
I	O
'd	O
rather	O
get	O
this	O
to	O
a	O
wider	O
audience	O
so	O
that	O
everyone	O
can	O
see	O
and	O
experience	O
the	O
benefit	O
of	O
it.”The	O
‘Shark	O
Tank’-like	O
innovation	O
competition	O
was	O
open	O
to	O
all	O
U.S.	B-Organisation
service	I-Organisation
members	I-Organisation
and	O
DoD	O
civilians	O
from	O
seven	O
USCENTCOM	B-Organisation
subordinate	O
and	O
component	O
commands	O
,	O
including	O
ARCENT	O
;	O
AFCENT	O
;	O
NAVCENT	O
;	O
MARCENT	O
;	O
SOCCENT	O
;	O
SPACECENT	O
;	O
and	O
CENTCOM.Each	O
component	O
command	O
conducted	O
their	O
own	O
individual	O
innovation	O
competitions	O
and	O
chose	O
their	O
top	O
innovators	O
to	O
compete	O
in	O
the	O
main	O
event	O
in	O
Tampa.These	B-Location
innovators	O
had	O
the	O
privilege	O
to	O
present	O
their	O
ideas	O
in	O
front	O
of	O
a	O
distinguished	O
panel	B-Organisation
of	I-Organisation
tech	I-Organisation
industry	I-Organisation
leaders	I-Organisation
and	I-Organisation
senior	I-Organisation
military	I-Organisation
officials	I-Organisation
,	O
including	O
:	O
•	O
Dr.	B-Person
Andrew	I-Person
Moore	I-Person
,	O
Founder	O
of	O
Lovelace	O
AI	O
and	O
former	O
VP	O
of	O
Google	B-Organisation
AI	O
Cloud•	O
Kevin	B-Person
Harrington	I-Person
,	O
Entrepreneur	O
,	O
and	O
original	O
‘Shark’	O
on	O
Shark	O
Tank•	O
Honorable	O
Sue	B-Person
Gordon	I-Person
,	O
former	O
Deputy	O
Director	O
of	O
National	O
Intelligence•	O
Honorable	O
Mac	B-Person
Thornberry	I-Person
,	O
former	O
Chair	B-Organisation
House	I-Organisation
Armed	I-Organisation
Services	I-Organisation
Committee•	I-Organisation
General	B-Person
Michael	I-Person
“Erik”	I-Person
Kurilla	I-Person
,	O
commander	O
of	O
CENTCOM•	B-Organisation
Fleet	B-Person
Master	I-Person
Chief	I-Person
Derrick	I-Person
Walters	I-Person
,	O
senior	O
enlisted	O
leader	O
CENTCOM•	B-Organisation
Colonel	B-Person
Khaled	I-Person
Alrubaian	I-Person
,	O
Kuwait	B-Location
senior	O
national	O
representative	O
at	O
CENTCOM•	B-Organisation
Schuyler	B-Person
Moore	I-Person
,	O
chief	O
technology	O
officer	O
CENTCOM	B-Organisation

Each	O
finalist	O
had	O
ten	O
minutes	O
to	O
present	O
their	O
innovation	O
,	O
followed	O
by	O
15	O
minutes	O
of	O
questions	O
and	O
answers	O
from	O
the	O
panel.	O
Each	O
presenter	O
was	O
evaluated	O
along	O
a	O
set	O
of	O
criteria	O
that	O
included	O
originality	O
,	O
scalability	O
of	O
concept	O
and	O
the	O
overall	O
presentation	O
.	O

The	O
presentations	O
ranged	O
from	O
an	O
electronic	O
warfare	O
virtual	O
training	O
environment	O
to	O
an	O
AI	O
prototype	O
passenger	O
tracker	O
for	O
noncombatant	O
evacuation	O
operations.	O
The	O
finalists	O
chosen	O
to	O
present	O
their	O
innovation	O
were	O
selected	O
from	O
every	O
U.S	B-Organisation
military	I-Organisation
service	O
branch	O
.	O

“Innovation	O
Oasis	O
2023	O
has	O
enabled	O
us	O
to	O
spread	O
the	O
spirit	O
of	O
innovation	O
across	O
the	O
command	O
,	O
encouraging	O
all	O
our	O
team	O
members	O
to	O
think	O
of	O
creative	O
solutions	O
to	O
real-world	O
problems	O
,	O
”	O
said	O
Schuyler	B-Person
Moore	I-Person
,	O
CENTCOM	B-Organisation
chief	O
technology	O
officer.	O
“The	O
next	O
great	O
idea	O
can	O
come	O
from	O
a	O
civilian	O
or	O
service	O
member	O
,	O
a	O
sergeant	O
or	O
a	O
general.	O
Innovation	O
is	O
agnostic	O
of	O
position	O
or	O
rank	O
,	O
and	O
here	O
at	O
CENTCOM	B-Organisation
we	O
will	O
always	O
encourage	O
and	O
elevate	O
that	O
kind	O
of	O
thinking	O
and	O
problem-solving	O
.	O

"	O
Through	O
just	O
two	O
iterations	O
of	O
the	O
Innovation	O
Oasis	O
,	O
CENTCOM	B-Organisation
has	O
received	O
hundreds	O
of	O
submissions	O
from	O
across	O
the	O
Department	B-Organisation
of	I-Organisation
Defense.	I-Organisation
The	O
competition	O
has	O
provided	O
a	O
platform	O
for	O
service	O
members	O
to	O
present	O
ideas	O
and	O
to	O
higher	O
echelons	O
of	O
leadership	O
.	O

“A	O
lot	O
of	O
the	O
times	O
if	O
you	O
present	O
something	O
to	O
your	O
leadership	O
,	O
it	O
can	O
come	O
across	O
as	O
presenting	O
a	O
problem	O
but	O
if	O
you	O
take	O
the	O
time	O
to	O
fully	O
understand	O
the	O
problem	O
,	O
come	O
up	O
with	O
a	O
solution	O
,	O
and	O
you	O
're	O
willing	O
to	O
advocate	O
for	O
that	O
idea	O
,	O
whether	O
it	O
's	O
a	O
product	O
or	O
it	O
's	O
a	O
policy	O
change	O
...	O
I	O
've	O
never	O
met	O
a	O
leader	O
that	O
is	O
n't	O
willing	O
to	O
embrace	O
change	O
for	O
the	O
sake	O
of	O
improvement	O
,	O
”	O
Matsunaga	B-Person
said.	O
“So	O
,	O
if	O
you	O
are	O
willing	O
to	O
take	O
the	O
time	O
to	O
develop	O
that	O
situation	O
and	O
advocate	O
,	O
I	O
guarantee	O
a	O
good	O
leader	O
is	O
going	O
to	O
be	O
willing	O
to	O
grab	O
on	O
to	O
it.	O
They	O
're	O
going	O
to	O
listen.	O
There	O
're	O
going	O
to	O
elevate	O
it.	O
And	O
it	O
does	O
n't	O
matter	O
what	O
rank	O
you	O
are	O
,	O
it	O
does	O
n't	O
matter	O
your	O
experience	O
level	O
in	O
your	O
career	O
field	O
,	O
if	O
you’re	O
willing	O
to	O
put	O
forth	O
the	O
effort	O
,	O
you	O
can	O
take	O
that	O
solution	O
anywhere	O
you	O
need	O
to.”	O

The	O
resonating	O
roar	O
of	O
an	O
F-22	B-MilitaryPlatform
Raptor	I-MilitaryPlatform
or	O
the	O
sky-ripping	O
sound	O
of	O
an	O
A-10C	B-MilitaryPlatform
Thunderbolt	I-MilitaryPlatform
II	I-MilitaryPlatform
minigun	B-Weapon
ignites	O
visions	O
of	O
air	O
superiority.	O
Though	O
,	O
amidst	O
the	O
awe-inspiring	O
might	O
of	O
these	O
multi-million	B-Money
dollar	I-Money
aircraft	O
,	O
lies	O
an	O
unsung	O
hero	O
:	O
the	O
diligent	O
ground	O
equipment	O
Airmen	B-MilitaryPlatform
who	O
work	O
behind	O
the	O
scenes	O
.	O

Aerospace	O
ground	O
equipment	O
(	O
AGE	O
)	O
is	O
one	O
of	O
the	O
first	O
building	O
blocks	O
making	O
up	O
the	O
pyramid	O
aimed	O
at	O
the	O
air	O
domain	O
and	O
the	O
379th	O
Expeditionary	O
Maintenance	O
Squadron	O
(	O
EMXS	O
)	O
Airmen	B-MilitaryPlatform
at	I-MilitaryPlatform
Al	I-MilitaryPlatform
Udeid	I-MilitaryPlatform
Air	I-MilitaryPlatform
Base	I-MilitaryPlatform
(	O
AUAB	O
)	O
,	O
Qatar	B-Location
,	O
form	O
this	O
essential	O
building	O
block	O
for	O
Central	O
Command’s	O
area	O
of	O
responsibility	O
(	O
AOR	O
)	O
.	O

The	B-Organisation
AGE	I-Organisation
team	I-Organisation
is	O
responsible	O
for	O
maintaining	O
more	O
than	O
350	O
pieces	O
of	O
equipment	O
ranging	O
from	O
hydraulic	O
maintenance	O
stands	O
to	O
jet	O
engine	O
generators	O
that	O
provide	O
power	O
to	O
aircraft	O
on	O
the	O
flight	O
line.	O
Aircraft	O
maintainers	O
and	O
crew	O
chiefs	O
rely	O
on	O
these	O
assets	O
every	O
day	O
to	O
sustain	O
the	O
379th	B-MilitaryPlatform
Air	I-MilitaryPlatform
Expeditionary	I-MilitaryPlatform
Wing’s	I-MilitaryPlatform
fleet	I-MilitaryPlatform
to	O
include	O
the	O
KC-135	B-MilitaryPlatform
Stratotanker	I-MilitaryPlatform
and	O
C-17	B-MilitaryPlatform
Globemaster	I-MilitaryPlatform
III	I-MilitaryPlatform
,	O
or	O
even	O
transient	O
aircraft	O
like	O
the	O
KC-46A	B-MilitaryPlatform
Pegasus	I-MilitaryPlatform
.	O

“It’s	O
the	O
strength	O
of	O
an	O
AGE	B-Organisation
maintainer	O
to	O
remain	O
flexible	O
,	O
”	O
said	O
U.S.	B-Person
Air	I-Person
Force	I-Person
Staff	I-Person
Sgt.	I-Person
Brandon	I-Person
Huff	I-Person
,	I-Person
379th	I-Person
EMXS	I-Person
AGE	I-Person
craftsman.	I-Person
“Inspections	O
one	O
day	O
,	O
heavy	O
maintenance	O
the	O
next	O
,	O
AGE	B-Organisation
touches	O
all	O
aircraft	O
and	O
misses	O
none.	O
With	O
our	O
capabilities	O
,	O
not	O
only	O
can	O
we	O
power	O
older	O
generation	O
aircraft	O
like	O
the	O
KC-135	B-MilitaryPlatform
with	O
newer	O
equipment	O
built	O
in	O
the	O
late	O
2010s	B-Temporal
,	O
but	O
we	O
can	O
extend	O
the	O
lifespan	O
of	O
Vietnam	B-Location
War-era	O
equipment	O
to	O
work	O
on	O
new	O
aircraft	O
such	O
as	O
the	O
KC-46.”	B-MilitaryPlatform

At	O
AUAB	B-Organisation
,	O
the	O
in-flight	O
refuel	O
capabilities	O
enable	O
other	O
aircraft	O
to	O
conduct	O
security	O
in	O
the	O
AOR	O
without	O
needing	O
to	O
land.	O
With	O
every	O
piece	O
of	O
equipment	O
the	O
AGE	B-Organisation
Airmen	I-Organisation
provide	O
,	O
their	O
hardworking	O
hours	O
directly	O
contribute	O
to	O
the	O
mission	O
overhead	O
.	O

“AGE	B-Organisation
is	O
critical	O
to	O
the	O
execution	O
of	O
our	O
tanker	O
mission	O
at	O
AUAB	B-Organisation
especially	O
due	O
to	O
hot	O
weather	O
operations	O
,	O
”	O
said	O
Maj.	B-Person
Matthew	I-Person
Woods	I-Person
,	I-Person
912th	I-Person
Expeditionary	I-Person
Air	I-Person
Refueling	I-Person
Squadron	I-Person
assistant	I-Person
director	I-Person
of	I-Person
operations.	I-Person
“Air	O
conditioning	O
carts	O
maintained	O
and	O
provided	O
by	O
AGE	B-Organisation
allow	O
our	O
crews	O
to	O
perform	O
pre-flight	O
measures	O
in	O
extremely	O
high	O
temperatures.	O
Because	O
the	O
crews	O
are	O
able	O
to	O
be	O
in	O
the	O
jet	O
with	O
a	O
cooler	O
temperature	O
,	O
they	O
are	O
able	O
to	O
be	O
more	O
flexible	O
with	O
dynamic	O
taskings	O
that	O
may	O
require	O
ground	O
delays.”	O

Certified	O
on	O
jet	O
engines	O
,	O
air	O
conditioning	O
,	O
high	O
purity	O
nitrogen	O
and	O
more	O
,	O
AGE	B-Organisation
Airmen	I-Organisation
are	O
multi-capable	O
and	O
ready	O
to	O
solve	O
problems	O
in	O
an	O
unpredictable	O
environment	O
,	O
protecting	O
the	O
longevity	O
of	O
the	O
fleet	O
.	O

“Air	O
conditioning	O
carts	O
allow	O
the	O
KC-135	B-MilitaryPlatform
to	O
operate	O
electronic	O
upgraded	O
variants	O
in	O
the	O
desert	O
by	O
cooling	O
the	O
circuit	O
breaker	O
panels	O
,	O
minimizing	O
maintenance	O
issues	O
,	O
”	O
Woods	B-Person
said.	O
“AGE	B-Organisation
is	O
also	O
crucial	O
to	O
our	O
operations	O
by	O
providing	O
units	O
that	O
supply	O
ground	O
power	O
to	O
the	O
aircraft	O
in	O
lieu	O
of	O
using	O
the	O
aircraft	O
's	O
auxiliary	O
power	O
unit	O
(	O
APU	O
)	O
.	O
Minimizing	O
the	O
wear	O
and	O
tear	O
on	O
the	O
APUs	O
allows	O
us	O
to	O
increase	O
the	O
lifespan	O
of	O
a	O
critical	O
system.”	O

Not	O
only	O
does	O
AGE	B-Organisation
enable	O
air	O
power	O
for	O
U.S.	B-MilitaryPlatform
aircraft	I-MilitaryPlatform
,	O
but	O
it	O
also	O
extends	O
its	O
reach	O
to	O
coalition	O
forces	O
.	O

“We	O
had	O
a	O
French	O
KC-135	B-MilitaryPlatform
out	O
there	O
for	O
a	O
while	O
,	O
and	O
we	O
provided	O
our	O
AGE	B-Organisation
to	O
them	O
as	O
well	O
,	O
”	O
said	O
U.S.	B-Person
Air	I-Person
Force	I-Person
Senior	I-Person
Airman	I-Person
Marc	I-Person
Rose	I-Person
,	I-Person
379th	I-Person
EMXS	I-Person
AGE	I-Person
maintenance	I-Person
journeyman.	I-Person
“We	O
let	O
them	O
use	O
our	O
generator	O
carts	O
,	O
our	O
universal	O
maintenance	O
stands	O
,	O
hydraulic	O
carts	O
…	O
anything	O
they	O
needed	O
to	O
service	O
their	O
aircraft	O
as	O
well.”	O

Recognizing	O
the	O
interdependence	O
of	O
air	O
and	O
ground	O
support	O
,	O
Rose	B-Person
further	O
underscored	O
the	O
integral	O
nature	O
of	O
their	O
work	O
,	O
stating	O
,	O
"	O
There	O
's	O
no	O
air	O
support	O
without	O
ground	O
support.	O
It	O
all	O
works	O
together	O
;	O
we	O
're	O
just	O
one	O
link	O
in	O
that	O
chain.	O
Without	O
us	O
,	O
the	O
chain	O
is	O
broken	O
.	O
"	O

These	O
words	O
serve	O
as	O
a	O
powerful	O
reminder	O
that	O
the	O
seamless	O
synergy	O
between	O
air	O
and	O
ground	O
operations	O
is	O
essential	O
for	O
the	O
success	O
of	O
any	O
mission	O
.	O

A	B-MilitaryPlatform
French	I-MilitaryPlatform
warship	I-MilitaryPlatform
operating	O
in	O
support	O
of	O
Combined	B-Organisation
Task	I-Organisation
Force	I-Organisation
(	O
CTF	O
)	O
150	O
conducted	O
four	O
illegal	O
drug	O
seizures	O
between	O
April	B-Temporal
19	I-Temporal
and	O
May	B-Temporal
18	I-Temporal
worth	O
a	O
total	O
estimated	O
U.S.	B-Location
street	O
value	O
of	O
$	B-Money
108	I-Money
million	I-Money
from	O
fishing	O
vessels	O
transiting	O
international	O
waters	O
in	O
the	O
Indian	B-Location
Ocean	I-Location
.	O

The	B-MilitaryPlatform
warship	I-MilitaryPlatform
seized	O
2,265	O
kilograms	O
of	O
heroin	O
and	O
242	O
kilograms	O
of	O
methamphetamine	O
from	O
four	O
different	O
vessels	O
while	O
patrolling	O
regional	O
waters.	O
CTF	B-Organisation
150	I-Organisation
is	O
one	O
of	O
five	O
task	O
forces	O
under	O
Combined	B-Organisation
Maritime	I-Organisation
Forces	I-Organisation
,	O
the	O
largest	O
multinational	O
naval	O
partnership	O
in	O
the	O
world	O
.	O

In	O
2023	B-Temporal
,	O
maritime	O
forces	O
supporting	O
CTF	B-Organisation
150	I-Organisation
have	O
seized	O
illegal	O
drugs	O
worth	O
a	O
combined	O
estimated	O
U.S.	B-Location
street	O
value	O
of	O
$	B-Money
203	I-Money
million	I-Money
,	O
adding	O
to	O
record-breaking	O
drug	O
interdictions	O
by	O
U.S.	B-Location
and	O
international	O
naval	O
units	O
in	O
2021	B-Temporal
and	O
2022	B-Temporal
totaling	O
more	O
than	O
$	B-Money
1	I-Money
billion	I-Money
in	O
value	O
.	O

“It’s	O
been	O
a	O
pleasure	O
working	O
with	O
the	O
French	B-Organisation
sailors	I-Organisation
to	O
achieve	O
our	O
mission’s	O
aims	O
together	O
,	O
”	O
said	O
United	B-Location
Kingdom	I-Location
Royal	B-Organisation
Navy	I-Organisation
Lt.	B-Person
Francis	I-Person
Henry	I-Person
,	I-Person
a	I-Person
CTF	I-Person
150	I-Person
staff	I-Person
officer	I-Person
responsible	O
for	O
coordinating	O
the	O
task	O
force’s	O
counter-narcotics	O
efforts	O
.	O

CTF	B-Organisation
150	I-Organisation
conducts	O
maritime	O
security	O
operations	O
in	O
the	O
Gulf	B-Location
of	I-Location
Oman	I-Location
,	O
Arabian	B-Location
Sea	I-Location
and	O
Indian	B-Location
Ocean	I-Location
to	O
disrupt	O
destabilizing	O
activity	O
,	O
promote	O
international	O
rules-based	O
order	O
and	O
help	O
ensure	O
the	O
free	O
flow	O
of	O
commerce	O
.	O

The	O
task	B-MilitaryPlatform
force	I-MilitaryPlatform
is	O
headquartered	O
in	O
Bahrain	B-Location
with	O
Combined	B-Organisation
Maritime	I-Organisation
Forces	I-Organisation
,	O
which	O
is	O
led	O
by	O
the	O
commander	O
of	O
U.S.	B-Organisation
Naval	I-Organisation
Forces	I-Organisation
Central	I-Organisation
Command	I-Organisation
and	O
U.S.	B-Organisation
5th	I-Organisation
Fleet	O
.	O

The	O
U.S.-led	B-Location
multinational	O
partnership	O
,	O
Combined	B-Organisation
Maritime	I-Organisation
Forces	I-Organisation
(	O
CMF	O
)	O
,	O
established	O
a	O
new	O
task	B-MilitaryPlatform
force	I-MilitaryPlatform
May	B-Temporal
22	I-Temporal
that	O
will	O
train	O
partner	O
navies	O
and	O
improve	O
operational	O
capabilities	O
to	O
enhance	O
maritime	O
security	O
in	O
the	O
Middle	B-Location
East	I-Location
.	O

During	O
a	O
ceremony	O
at	O
U.S.	B-Organisation
5th	I-Organisation
Fleet	I-Organisation
headquarters	O
in	O
Bahrain	B-Location
,	O
leaders	O
commissioned	O
Combined	B-Organisation
Task	I-Organisation
Force	I-Organisation
(	I-Organisation
CTF	I-Organisation
)	I-Organisation
154.	I-Organisation
The	O
new	O
staff	O
is	O
CMF’s	B-MilitaryPlatform
fifth	I-MilitaryPlatform
task	I-MilitaryPlatform
force	I-MilitaryPlatform
after	O
standing	O
up	O
CTF	B-Organisation
153	I-Organisation
in	O
April	B-Temporal
2022	I-Temporal
for	O
maritime	O
security	O
in	O
the	O
Red	B-Location
Sea	I-Location
.	O

CTF	B-Organisation
154	I-Organisation
will	O
lead	O
multinational	O
maritime	O
training	O
at	O
locations	O
across	O
the	O
Middle	B-Location
East	I-Location
,	O
enabling	O
more	O
CMF	B-Organisation
partner-nations	O
to	O
participate	O
in	O
training	O
opportunities	O
without	O
ships	O
or	O
aircraft	O
,	O
particularly	O
during	O
courses	O
that	O
are	O
facilitated	O
ashore	O
.	O

“Our	O
navies	O
are	O
at	O
their	O
very	O
best	O
when	O
we	O
train	O
,	O
operate	O
and	O
work	O
together	O
,	O
”	O
said	O
Vice	B-Person
Adm.	I-Person
Brad	I-Person
Cooper	I-Person
,	I-Person
commander	I-Person
of	I-Person
U.S.	I-Person
Naval	I-Person
Forces	I-Person
Central	I-Person
Command	I-Person
,	I-Person
U.S.	I-Person
5th	I-Person
Fleet	I-Person
and	I-Person
CMF.	I-Person
“Establishing	O
CTF	B-Organisation
154	I-Organisation
demonstrates	O
our	O
deep	O
commitment	O
to	O
strengthening	O
and	O
expanding	O
partnerships	O
through	O
new	O
training	O
opportunities	O
that	O
will	O
enhance	O
regional	O
maritime	O
security.”	O

The	O
new	O
task	B-MilitaryPlatform
force	I-MilitaryPlatform
is	O
commanded	O
by	O
a	B-Person
U.S.	I-Person
Navy	I-Person
captain	I-Person
who	O
will	O
build	O
and	O
lead	O
a	O
multinational	O
staff.	O
Another	O
nation	O
will	O
assume	O
command	O
as	O
early	O
as	O
this	O
fall	O
.	O

CTF	B-Organisation
154’s	I-Organisation
core	O
staff	O
will	O
be	O
augmented	O
by	O
CMF	B-Organisation
partners	O
during	O
key	O
training	O
opportunities	O
such	O
as	O
the	O
task	B-MilitaryPlatform
force’s	I-MilitaryPlatform
inaugural	O
event	O
,	O
Compass	O
Rose.	O
This	O
week	O
,	O
CTF	B-Organisation
154	I-Organisation
is	O
hosting	O
Compass	O
Rose	O
in	O
the	O
Kingdom	B-Location
of	I-Location
Bahrain.	I-Location
More	O
than	O
50	O
participants	O
from	O
Bahrain	B-Location
,	O
Kuwait	B-Location
,	O
Oman	B-Location
,	O
Pakistan	B-Location
,	O
Saudi	B-Location
Arabia	I-Location
,	O
the	B-Location
United	I-Location
Kingdom	I-Location
and	O
United	B-Location
States	I-Location
began	O
arriving	O
Sunday	O
to	O
attend	O
courses	O
on	O
first	O
aid	O
and	O
vessel	O
boarding	O
procedures	O
.	O

“I	O
am	O
excited	O
to	O
lead	O
an	O
international	O
team	O
in	O
this	O
important	O
work	O
,	O
”	O
said	O
Capt.	B-Organisation
Oliver	I-Organisation
Herion	I-Organisation
,	I-Organisation
CTF	I-Organisation
154	I-Organisation
's	I-Organisation
first	I-Organisation
commander.	I-Organisation
“Collectively	O
,	O
CMF	B-Organisation
has	O
tremendous	O
experience	O
and	O
expertise	O
with	O
critical	O
skills	O
,	O
tools	O
and	O
relationships.”	O

CTF	B-Organisation
154	I-Organisation
will	O
frequently	O
organize	O
training	O
events	O
around	O
five	O
core	O
areas	O
:	O
maritime	O
awareness	O
,	O
maritime	O
law	O
,	O
maritime	O
interdiction	O
,	O
maritime	O
rescue	O
and	O
assistance	O
,	O
and	O
leadership	O
development.	O
Each	O
training	O
opportunity	O
will	O
be	O
tailored	O
to	O
meet	O
partner	O
requests	O
ranging	O
from	O
basic	O
to	O
advanced	O
levels	O
.	O

“Focusing	O
our	O
efforts	O
to	O
facilitate	O
training	O
for	O
the	O
multinational	O
partnership	O
will	O
refine	O
our	O
skillsets	O
and	O
reinforce	O
our	O
ability	O
to	O
operate	O
together	O
,	O
”	O
said	O
Herion.	B-Person
“We	O
are	O
‘Stronger	O
Together’	O
and	O
‘Ready	O
Together.’	O
That	O
is	O
what	O
CMF	B-Organisation
is	O
all	O
about.”	O

CMF	B-Organisation
is	O
the	O
largest	O
multinational	O
naval	O
partnership	O
in	O
the	O
world	O
,	O
with	O
38	O
nations	O
committed	O
to	O
upholding	O
the	O
international	O
rules-based	O
order	O
at	O
sea	O
.	O

CMF’s	B-Organisation
other	O
task	O
forces	O
include	O
CTF	B-Organisation
150	I-Organisation
that	O
focuses	O
on	O
maritime	O
security	O
in	O
the	O
Gulf	B-Location
of	I-Location
Oman	I-Location
and	O
Indian	B-Location
Ocean	I-Location
;	O
CTF	B-Organisation
151	I-Organisation
,	O
which	O
leads	O
regional	O
counter-piracy	O
efforts	O
;	O
CTF	B-Organisation
152	I-Organisation
,	O
dedicated	O
to	O
maritime	O
security	O
in	O
the	O
Arabian	B-Location
Gulf	I-Location
;	O
and	O
CTF	B-Organisation
153	I-Organisation
in	O
the	O
Red	B-Location
Sea	I-Location
.	O

Ships	O
from	O
the	O
South	O
Korean	O
and	O
Italian	O
navies	O
sailed	O
together	O
and	O
conducted	O
combined	O
training	O
in	O
the	O
Gulf	B-Location
of	I-Location
Aden	I-Location
,	O
May	B-Temporal
17	I-Temporal
,	O
while	O
operating	O
under	O
two	O
multinational	O
maritime	O
partnerships	O
,	O
Combined	B-Organisation
Maritime	I-Organisation
Forces	I-Organisation
and	O
European	B-Organisation
Union	I-Organisation
Naval	I-Organisation
Forces	I-Organisation
.	O

Republic	B-MilitaryPlatform
of	I-MilitaryPlatform
Korea	I-MilitaryPlatform
Navy	I-MilitaryPlatform
ship	I-MilitaryPlatform
ROKS	I-MilitaryPlatform
Chungmugong	I-MilitaryPlatform
Yi	I-MilitaryPlatform
Sun-sin	I-MilitaryPlatform
(	O
DDH	O
975	O
)	O
and	O
Italian	B-MilitaryPlatform
Navy	I-MilitaryPlatform
frigate	I-MilitaryPlatform
ITS	I-MilitaryPlatform
Luigi	I-MilitaryPlatform
Rizzo	I-MilitaryPlatform
(	O
F	O
595	O
)	O
rehearsed	O
ship	O
and	O
helicopter	O
maneuvers	O
while	O
sharing	O
best	O
practices	O
on	O
vessel	O
boarding	O
procedures	O
to	O
enhance	O
collaboration	O
on	O
combating	O
maritime	O
piracy	O
.	O

“The	O
Korean	O
and	O
Italian	O
ships	O
collaborated	O
,	O
from	O
the	O
planning	O
to	O
execution	O
making	O
this	O
a	O
very	O
successful	O
interaction	O
,	O
”	O
said	O
Capt.	B-Person
Yoon	I-Person
Sung-won	I-Person
,	I-Person
commanding	I-Person
officer	I-Person
for	I-Person
Chungmugong	I-Person
Yi	I-Person
Sun-sin.	I-Person
“We	O
have	O
demonstrated	O
seamless	O
teamwork	O
and	O
the	O
ability	O
to	O
respond	O
promptly	O
in	O
any	O
situation.”	O

During	O
the	O
training	O
,	O
Chungmugong	B-MilitaryPlatform
Yi	I-MilitaryPlatform
Sun-sin	I-MilitaryPlatform
operated	O
in	O
support	O
of	O
Combined	B-Organisation
Task	I-Organisation
Force	I-Organisation
(	I-Organisation
CTF	I-Organisation
)	I-Organisation
151	I-Organisation
,	O
one	O
of	O
four	O
operational	O
task	B-MilitaryPlatform
forces	I-MilitaryPlatform
under	O
Combined	B-Organisation
Maritime	I-Organisation
Forces	I-Organisation
,	O
which	O
includes	O
38	O
member-nations	O
and	O
partners.	O
CTF	B-Organisation
151	I-Organisation
conducts	O
counter-piracy	O
missions	O
led	O
by	O
Republic	B-Person
of	I-Person
Korea	I-Person
Navy	I-Person
Rear	I-Person
Adm.	I-Person
Ko	I-Person
Seung-bum	I-Person
.	O

“Our	O
warships	O
have	O
once	O
again	O
joined	O
forces.	O
Through	O
continuous	O
training	O
,	O
we	O
will	O
strengthen	O
the	O
combined	O
operational	O
capabilities	O
,	O
”	O
said	O
Ko	B-Person
.	O

Luigi	B-Person
Rizzo	I-Person
participated	O
while	O
operating	O
under	O
Task	B-Organisation
Force	I-Organisation
(	I-Organisation
TF	I-Organisation
)	I-Organisation
465	I-Organisation
,	O
a	O
multinational	O
naval	O
unit	O
from	O
European	B-Organisation
Union	I-Organisation
Naval	I-Organisation
Forces	I-Organisation
that	O
also	O
focuses	O
on	O
countering	O
piracy	O
in	O
the	O
Middle	B-Location
East	I-Location
.	O

Task	B-MilitaryPlatform
forces	I-MilitaryPlatform
from	O
Combined	B-Organisation
Maritime	I-Organisation
Forces	I-Organisation
and	O
European	B-Organisation
Union	I-Organisation
Naval	I-Organisation
Forces	I-Organisation
regularly	O
collaborate	O
to	O
enhance	O
interoperability	O
through	O
combined	O
patrols	O
and	O
joint	O
training.	O
Japanese	O
and	O
Italian	O
navy	O
warships	O
previously	O
conducted	O
combined	O
training	O
in	O
the	O
Gulf	B-Location
of	I-Location
Aden	I-Location
,	O
April	B-Temporal
8	I-Temporal
,	O
while	O
supporting	O
CTF	B-Organisation
151	I-Organisation
and	O
TF	B-Organisation
465	I-Organisation
respectively	O
.	O

Established	O
in	O
2009	B-Temporal
,	O
CTF	B-Organisation
151	I-Organisation
conducts	O
maritime	O
security	O
operations	O
to	O
deter	O
,	O
disrupt	O
and	O
suppress	O
piracy	O
and	O
armed	O
robbery	O
at	O
sea	O
,	O
outside	O
the	O
Horn	B-Location
of	I-Location
Africa.	I-Location
The	O
task	B-MilitaryPlatform
force	I-MilitaryPlatform
is	O
headquartered	O
in	O
Bahrain	B-Location
with	O
U.S.	B-Organisation
Naval	I-Organisation
Forces	I-Organisation
Central	I-Organisation
Command	I-Organisation
,	O
U.S.	B-Organisation
Fifth	I-Organisation
Fleet	I-Organisation
and	O
Combined	B-Organisation
Maritime	I-Organisation
Forces	I-Organisation
.	O

Vice	B-Person
Adm.	I-Person
Brad	I-Person
Cooper	I-Person
,	O
commander	O
of	O
U.S.	B-Organisation
Naval	I-Organisation
Forces	I-Organisation
Central	I-Organisation
Command	I-Organisation
(	O
NAVCENT	O
)	O
,	O
U.S.	B-Organisation
5th	I-Organisation
Fleet	I-Organisation
and	O
Combined	B-Organisation
Maritime	I-Organisation
Forces	I-Organisation
,	O
spoke	O
with	O
Joint	B-Person
Commander	I-Person
of	I-Person
the	I-Person
French	I-Person
Forces	I-Person
Deployed	I-Person
in	I-Person
the	I-Person
Indian	I-Person
Ocean	I-Person
(	I-Person
ALINDIEN	I-Person
)	I-Person
Vice	I-Person
Adm.	I-Person
Emmanuel	I-Person
Slaars	I-Person
during	O
a	O
video	O
call	O
,	O
May	B-Temporal
13	I-Temporal
.	O

The	O
leaders	O
discussed	O
opportunities	O
for	O
NAVCENT	B-Organisation
and	O
ALINDIEN	B-Organisation
joint	O
forces	O
to	O
enhance	O
regional	O
cooperation	O
together	O
,	O
as	O
NAVCENT	B-Organisation
works	O
with	O
allies	O
and	O
partners	O
to	O
bolster	O
maritime	O
security	O
collaboration	O
.	O

In	O
coordination	O
with	O
French	O
assets	O
operating	O
in	O
the	O
area	O
,	O
the	B-Location
United	I-Location
States	I-Location
is	O
increasing	O
the	O
rotation	O
of	O
ships	O
and	O
aircraft	O
patrolling	O
in	O
and	O
around	O
the	O
Strait	B-Location
of	I-Location
Hormuz	I-Location
after	O
Iran’s	B-Location
recent	O
unlawful	O
merchant	O
vessel	O
seizures	O
.	O

NAVCENT’s	B-Organisation
area	O
of	O
operations	O
encompasses	O
approximately	O
2.5	O
million	O
square	O
miles	O
of	O
water	O
area	O
and	O
includes	O
the	O
Arabian	B-Location
Gulf	I-Location
,	O
Gulf	B-Location
of	I-Location
Oman	I-Location
,	O
Red	B-Location
Sea	I-Location
,	O
parts	O
of	O
the	O
Indian	B-Location
Ocean	I-Location
and	O
three	O
critical	O
choke	O
points	O
at	O
the	O
Strait	B-Location
of	I-Location
Hormuz	I-Location
,	O
Suez	B-Location
Canal	I-Location
and	O
Strait	B-Location
of	I-Location
Bab	I-Location
al	I-Location
Mandeb	I-Location
.	O

U.S.	B-Organisation
5th	I-Organisation
Fleet	I-Organisation
is	O
working	O
with	O
regional	O
allies	O
and	O
partners	O
to	O
increase	O
the	O
rotation	O
of	O
ships	O
and	O
aircraft	O
patrolling	O
in	O
and	O
around	O
the	O
Strait	B-Location
of	I-Location
Hormuz	I-Location
following	O
Iran’s	O
recent	O
unlawful	O
merchant	O
vessel	O
seizures	O
.	O

The	O
increased	O
force	O
presence	O
supports	O
multinational	O
efforts	O
to	O
deter	O
threats	O
to	O
commercial	O
shipping	O
and	O
reassure	O
regional	O
mariners.	O
In	O
addition	O
to	O
heightened	O
patrols	O
,	O
U.S.	B-Organisation
5th	I-Organisation
Fleet	I-Organisation
is	O
bolstering	O
international	O
maritime	O
security	O
collaboration	O
among	O
the	O
International	O
Maritime	O
Security	O
Construct	O
and	O
European	O
Maritime	O
Awareness	O
in	O
the	O
Strait	B-Location
of	I-Location
Hormuz	I-Location
.	O

“Iran’s	B-Location
unwarranted	O
,	O
irresponsible	O
and	O
unlawful	O
seizure	O
and	O
harassment	O
of	O
merchant	O
vessels	O
must	O
stop	O
,	O
”	O
said	O
Vice	B-Person
Adm.	I-Person
Brad	I-Person
Cooper	I-Person
,	I-Person
commander	I-Person
of	I-Person
U.S.	I-Person
Naval	I-Person
Forces	I-Person
Central	I-Person
Command	I-Person
,	I-Person
U.S.	I-Person
5th	I-Person
Fleet	I-Person
and	I-Person
Combined	I-Person
Maritime	I-Person
Forces.	I-Person
“U.S.	B-Organisation
5th	I-Organisation
Fleet	I-Organisation
and	O
our	O
partners	O
are	O
committed	O
to	O
protecting	O
navigational	O
rights	O
in	O
these	O
critical	O
waters.”	O

Iran	B-Location
has	O
harassed	O
,	O
attacked	O
or	O
interfered	O
with	O
the	O
navigational	O
rights	O
of	O
15	O
internationally	O
flagged	O
merchant	O
vessels	O
over	O
the	O
past	O
two	O
years.	O
This	O
pattern	O
of	O
destabilizing	O
behavior	O
is	O
contrary	O
to	O
international	O
law	O
and	O
disruptive	O
to	O
regional	O
security	O
.	O

Forces	O
from	O
U.S.	B-Organisation
5th	I-Organisation
Fleet	I-Organisation
completed	O
a	O
four-day	O
exercise	O
with	O
Israel	B-Location
in	O
the	O
Gulf	B-Location
of	I-Location
Aqaba	I-Location
,	O
May	B-Temporal
11	I-Temporal
,	O
that	O
focused	O
on	O
unmanned	O
systems	O
and	O
artificial	O
intelligence	O
integration	O
into	O
maritime	O
operations	O
.	O

The	O
exercise	O
,	O
called	O
Digital	O
Shield	O
,	O
included	O
members	O
of	O
U.S.	B-Organisation
5th	I-Organisation
Fleet	I-Organisation
's	I-Organisation
unmanned	O
systems	O
and	O
artificial	O
intelligence	O
task	B-MilitaryPlatform
force	I-MilitaryPlatform
,	O
Task	B-Organisation
Force	I-Organisation
59	I-Organisation
,	O
as	O
well	O
as	O
a	O
MANTAS	B-MilitaryPlatform
Devil	I-MilitaryPlatform
Ray	I-MilitaryPlatform
T-38	I-MilitaryPlatform
unmanned	O
surface	O
vessel.	O
U.S.	B-Location
forces	O
trained	O
alongside	O
Israeli	O
counterparts	O
during	O
maritime	O
awareness	O
and	O
vessel	O
boarding	O
drills	O
.	O

“By	O
working	O
together	O
to	O
advance	O
unmanned	O
systems	O
innovation	O
we	O
can	O
enhance	O
regional	O
security	O
and	O
strengthen	O
our	O
collective	O
ability	O
to	O
address	O
emerging	O
threats	O
,	O
”	O
said	O
Capt.	B-Person
Colin	I-Person
Corridan	I-Person
,	I-Person
Task	I-Person
Force	I-Person
59’s	I-Person
commander	I-Person
.	O

NAVCENT	B-Organisation
established	O
Task	B-Organisation
Force	I-Organisation
59	I-Organisation
in	O
September	B-Temporal
2021	I-Temporal
to	O
integrate	O
new	O
unmanned	O
systems	O
and	O
artificial	O
intelligence	O
into	O
U.S.	O
naval	O
operations	O
across	O
the	O
Middle	B-Location
East.	I-Location
Since	O
its	O
launch	O
,	O
the	O
task	O
force	O
has	O
operated	O
a	O
suite	O
of	O
new	O
unmanned	O
systems	O
from	O
regional	O
hubs	O
in	O
Bahrain	B-Location
and	O
Aqaba	B-Location
,	I-Location
Jordan	I-Location
.	O

Task	B-Organisation
Force	I-Organisation
59	I-Organisation
also	O
conducted	O
a	O
Digital	O
Shield	O
exercise	O
last	O
September	B-Temporal
with	O
Israeli	B-MilitaryPlatform
naval	I-MilitaryPlatform
forces.	I-MilitaryPlatform
The	B-MilitaryPlatform
task	I-MilitaryPlatform
force	I-MilitaryPlatform
regularly	O
trains	O
and	O
operates	O
with	O
maritime	O
partners	O
in	O
the	O
Middle	B-Location
East	I-Location
to	O
accelerate	O
the	O
integration	O
of	O
cutting-edge	O
unmanned	O
technology	O
into	O
daily	O
operations	O
.	O

U.S.	B-Organisation
5th	I-Organisation
Fleet’s	I-Organisation
area	O
of	O
operations	O
encompasses	O
approximately	O
2.5	O
million	O
square	O
miles	O
of	O
water	O
area	O
and	O
includes	O
the	O
Arabian	B-Location
Gulf	I-Location
,	O
Gulf	B-Location
of	I-Location
Oman	I-Location
,	O
Red	B-Location
Sea	I-Location
,	O
parts	O
of	O
the	O
Indian	B-Location
Ocean	I-Location
and	O
three	O
critical	O
choke	O
points	O
at	O
the	O
Strait	B-Location
of	I-Location
Hormuz	I-Location
,	O
Suez	B-Location
Canal	I-Location
and	O
Strait	B-Location
of	I-Location
Bab	I-Location
al	I-Location
Mandeb	I-Location
.	O

U.S.	B-Organisation
naval	I-Organisation
forces	I-Organisation
completed	O
participation	O
in	O
a	O
weeklong	O
Oman-led	O
naval	O
exercise	O
in	O
and	O
off	O
the	O
coast	O
of	O
Oman	B-Location
,	O
May	B-Temporal
11	I-Temporal
,	O
with	O
forces	O
from	O
France	B-Location
and	O
the	B-Location
United	I-Location
Kingdom	I-Location
.	O

The	O
five-day	O
exercise	O
,	O
called	O
Khunjar	O
Hadd	O
,	O
focused	O
on	O
mine	O
countermeasures	O
,	O
explosive	O
ordnance	O
disposal	O
,	O
maritime	O
interdiction	O
and	O
other	O
combined	O
naval	O
operations.	O
Personnel	O
from	O
a	O
U.S.	B-Organisation
5th	I-Organisation
Fleet	I-Organisation
expeditionary	O
mine	O
countermeasures	O
unit	O
participated	O
with	O
crewmembers	O
from	O
mine	O
countermeasures	O
ship	O
USS	B-MilitaryPlatform
Dextrous	I-MilitaryPlatform
(	I-MilitaryPlatform
MCM	I-MilitaryPlatform
13	I-MilitaryPlatform
)	I-MilitaryPlatform
and	O
a	O
U.S.	B-Organisation
Navy	I-Organisation
P-8A	B-MilitaryPlatform
Poseidon	I-MilitaryPlatform
maritime	I-MilitaryPlatform
patrol	I-MilitaryPlatform
aircraft	I-MilitaryPlatform
.	O

“Training	O
alongside	O
the	O
incredible	O
forces	B-MilitaryPlatform
of	O
Oman’s	B-Organisation
Royal	I-Organisation
Navy	I-Organisation
has	O
been	O
an	O
invaluable	O
experience	O
for	O
our	O
aircraft	O
,	O
ships	O
and	O
divers	O
,	O
”	O
said	O
United	B-Person
Kingdom	I-Person
Royal	I-Person
Navy	I-Person
Capt.	I-Person
Derek	I-Person
McKnight	I-Person
,	I-Person
deputy	I-Person
commander	I-Person
for	I-Person
Task	I-Person
Force	I-Person
52	I-Person
,	O
which	O
oversees	O
U.S.	B-Organisation
5th	I-Organisation
Fleet’s	I-Organisation
mine	O
countermeasures	O
mission	O
in	O
the	O
Middle	B-Location
East.	I-Location
“I	O
have	O
no	O
doubt	O
that	O
opportunities	O
such	O
as	O
this	O
increase	O
our	O
effectiveness	O
and	O
enable	O
us	O
to	O
achieve	O
shared	O
objectives.”	O

The	O
exercise	O
aimed	O
to	O
strengthen	O
relationships	O
and	O
enhance	O
interoperability	O
among	O
participating	O
military	B-MilitaryPlatform
forces.	I-MilitaryPlatform
It	O
began	O
May	B-Temporal
7	I-Temporal
,	O
the	O
same	O
day	O
U.S.	B-Organisation
5th	I-Organisation
Fleet	I-Organisation
hosted	O
Oman’s	B-Location
top	O
naval	O
commander	O
at	O
the	O
U.S.	B-MilitaryPlatform
Navy	I-MilitaryPlatform
base	I-MilitaryPlatform
in	O
Bahrain	B-Location
.	O

Vice	B-Organisation
Adm.	I-Organisation
Brad	I-Organisation
Cooper	I-Organisation
,	I-Organisation
commander	I-Organisation
of	I-Organisation
U.S.	I-Organisation
Naval	I-Organisation
Forces	I-Organisation
Central	I-Organisation
Command	I-Organisation
,	I-Organisation
U.S.	I-Organisation
5th	I-Organisation
Fleet	I-Organisation
and	I-Organisation
Combined	I-Organisation
Maritime	I-Organisation
Forces	I-Organisation
,	O
hosted	B-Person
Commander	I-Person
of	I-Person
the	I-Person
Royal	I-Person
Navy	I-Person
of	I-Person
Oman	I-Person
Rear	I-Person
Adm.	I-Person
Saif	I-Person
bin	I-Person
Nasser	I-Person
bin	I-Person
Mohsin	I-Person
Al	I-Person
Rahbi	I-Person
and	O
other	O
senior	O
Omani	O
officials	O
for	O
discussions	O
on	O
strengthening	O
regional	O
maritime	O
security	O
cooperation.	O
Cooper	B-Person
later	O
traveled	O
to	O
Oman	B-Location
and	O
embarked	O
Royal	B-Organisation
Navy	I-Organisation
of	I-Organisation
Oman	I-Organisation
patrol	O
vessel	O
RNOV	B-MilitaryPlatform
Al	I-MilitaryPlatform
Rahmani	I-MilitaryPlatform
(	I-MilitaryPlatform
Q41	I-MilitaryPlatform
)	I-MilitaryPlatform
to	O
observe	O
the	O
exercise	O
.	O

A	B-MilitaryPlatform
U.S.	I-MilitaryPlatform
Coast	I-MilitaryPlatform
Guard	I-MilitaryPlatform
fast	I-MilitaryPlatform
response	I-MilitaryPlatform
cutter	I-MilitaryPlatform
seized	O
$	B-Money
80	I-Money
million	I-Money
worth	O
of	O
heroin	O
from	O
a	O
fishing	O
vessel	O
transiting	O
the	O
Gulf	B-Location
of	I-Location
Oman	I-Location
,	O
May	B-Temporal
10	I-Temporal
,	O
during	O
the	O
ship’s	O
second	O
drug	O
bust	O
this	O
week	O
.	O

USCGC	B-MilitaryPlatform
Glen	I-MilitaryPlatform
Harris	I-MilitaryPlatform
(	I-MilitaryPlatform
WPC	I-MilitaryPlatform
1144	I-MilitaryPlatform
)	I-MilitaryPlatform
was	O
operating	O
in	O
support	O
of	O
Combined	B-Organisation
Task	I-Organisation
Force	I-Organisation
(	I-Organisation
CTF	I-Organisation
)	I-Organisation
150	I-Organisation
when	O
a	O
boarding	O
team	O
discovered	O
1,964	O
kilograms	O
of	O
heroin	O
on	O
a	O
vessel	O
transiting	O
international	O
waters	O
after	O
departing	O
Chah	B-Location
Bahar	I-Location
,	I-Location
Iran.	I-Location
Glen	B-MilitaryPlatform
Harris	I-MilitaryPlatform
also	O
seized	O
$	B-Money
30	I-Money
million	I-Money
worth	O
of	O
methamphetamine	O
and	O
heroin	O
two	O
days	O
ago	O
from	O
another	O
fishing	O
vessel	O
that	O
departed	O
the	O
same	O
port	O
.	O

“I’m	O
very	O
proud	O
of	O
my	O
crew	O
and	O
all	O
we’ve	O
been	O
able	O
to	O
accomplish	O
as	O
a	O
team	O
this	O
week	O
,	O
”	O
said	O
Lt.	B-Person
Nick	I-Person
Jabs	I-Person
,	I-Person
Glen	I-Person
Harris’s	I-Person
commanding	I-Person
officer.	I-Person
“We’re	O
out	O
here	O
to	O
work	O
with	O
regional	O
partners	O
and	O
disrupt	O
any	O
destabilizing	O
maritime	O
activity	O
at	O
sea.	O
We	O
will	O
continue	O
getting	O
after	O
it.”	O

Glen	B-MilitaryPlatform
Harris’s	I-MilitaryPlatform
previous	O
seizure	O
on	O
May	B-Temporal
8	I-Temporal
included	O
580	O
kilograms	O
of	O
methamphetamine	O
and	O
35	O
kilograms	O
of	O
heroin	O
.	O

The	O
ship	O
arrived	O
in	O
the	O
Middle	B-Location
East	I-Location
last	O
year	O
as	O
part	O
of	O
a	O
contingent	O
of	O
U.S.	B-MilitaryPlatform
Coast	I-MilitaryPlatform
Guard	I-MilitaryPlatform
cutters	I-MilitaryPlatform
that	O
are	O
forward-deployed	O
to	O
the	O
region	O
under	O
Patrol	B-Organisation
Forces	I-Organisation
Southwest	I-Organisation
Asia	I-Organisation
.	I-Organisation

CTF	B-Organisation
150	I-Organisation
is	O
one	O
of	O
four	O
task	B-MilitaryPlatform
forces	I-MilitaryPlatform
that	O
form	O
the	O
world’s	O
largest	O
multinational	O
naval	O
partnership	O
,	O
Combined	B-Organisation
Maritime	I-Organisation
Forces.	I-Organisation
Naval	B-MilitaryPlatform
forces	I-MilitaryPlatform
supporting	O
CTF	B-Organisation
150	I-Organisation
have	O
now	O
seized	O
illegal	O
drugs	O
worth	O
a	O
combined	O
estimated	O
U.S.	O
street	O
value	O
of	O
more	O
than	O
$	B-Money
250	I-Money
million	I-Money
in	O
2023.	B-Temporal
These	O
efforts	O
help	O
ensure	O
legitimate	O
commercial	O
shipping	O
transits	O
the	O
region	O
free	O
from	O
non-state	O
threats	O
.	O

U.	B-Organisation
S.	I-Organisation
Central	I-Organisation
Command	I-Organisation
(	I-Organisation
CENTCOM	I-Organisation
)	I-Organisation
hosted	O
a	O
Medical	O
Security	O
Cooperation	O
Exchange	O
(	O
MSCE	O
)	O
30	B-Temporal
April	I-Temporal
-	O
4	B-Temporal
May	I-Temporal
,	I-Temporal
2023.	I-Temporal
The	O
event	O
brought	O
together	O
healthcare	O
leaders	O
from	O
the	B-Location
U.	I-Location
S.	I-Location
and	O
its	O
regional	O
partners	O
over	O
five	O
days	O
to	O
share	O
best	O
practices	O
and	O
strengthen	O
relationships.	O
This	O
event’s	O
theme	O
was	O
“Partnership	O
and	O
Innovation	O
to	O
Enhance	O
Military	O
Medicine.”	O

The	O
bi-annual	O
MSCE	O
provides	O
an	O
opportunity	O
for	O
medical	O
professionals	O
to	O
discuss	O
current	O
challenges	O
,	O
to	O
share	O
experiences	O
and	O
practices	O
to	O
provide	O
care	O
,	O
and	O
to	O
identify	O
opportunities	O
to	O
partner	O
to	O
address	O
current	O
health	O
challenges.	O
People	O
,	O
partners	O
,	O
and	O
innovation	O
make	O
up	O
CENTCOM’s	B-Organisation
Strategic	O
Approach.	O
Each	O
element	O
was	O
prominent	O
within	O
the	O
context	O
of	O
the	O
MSCE	O
.	O

"	O
The	O
MSCE	O
is	O
a	O
testament	O
to	O
our	O
commitment	O
to	O
working	O
with	O
our	O
partners	O
to	O
build	O
strong	O
,	O
lasting	O
relationships	O
that	O
enhance	O
our	O
collective	O
medical	O
capabilities	O
,	O
"	O
said	O
Colonel	B-Person
Larry	I-Person
McCord	I-Person
,	I-Person
CENTCOM’s	I-Person
Command	I-Person
Surgeon.	I-Person
"	O
Through	O
events	O
like	O
these	O
,	O
we	O
can	O
share	O
knowledge	O
and	O
expertise	O
,	O
improve	O
our	O
medical	O
practices	O
,	O
and	O
enhance	O
our	O
ability	O
to	O
work	O
together	O
in	O
the	O
face	O
of	O
any	O
medical	O
challenge	O
.	O
"	O

Of	O
particular	O
focus	O
was	O
the	O
identification	O
of	O
opportunities	O
to	O
partner	O
and	O
innovate	O
to	O
address	O
common	O
health	O
challenges.	O
This	O
was	O
pursued	O
through	O
presentations	O
from	O
senior	O
health	O
leaders	O
and	O
supporting	O
organizations	O
,	O
through	O
tours	O
of	O
local	O
facilities	O
to	O
highlight	O
current	O
education	O
and	O
practice	O
methodologies	O
,	O
and	O
informal	O
discussion	O
throughout	O
.	O

Attendees	O
toured	O
the	O
University	B-Location
of	I-Location
South	I-Location
Florida’s	I-Location
Center	I-Location
for	I-Location
Advanced	I-Location
Medical	I-Location
Learning	I-Location
and	I-Location
Simulation	I-Location
(	O
CAMLS	O
)	O
and	O
the	O
James	B-Location
H.	I-Location
Haley	I-Location
VA	I-Location
Hospital.	I-Location
CAMLS	O
is	O
one	O
of	O
the	O
world’s	O
largest	O
medical	O
simulation	O
facilities	O
exclusively	O
dedicated	O
to	O
training	O
healthcare	O
professionals	O
.	O

“CENTCOM	B-Organisation
and	O
the	O
partner	O
nations	O
provided	O
beneficial	O
lectures	O
and	O
tours	O
during	O
the	O
conference	O
,	O
”	O
said	O
Brig.	B-Person
Gen.	I-Person
Dr.	I-Person
Mohamed	I-Person
Al-Khawalde	I-Person
,	O
of	O
the	B-Organisation
Jordanian	I-Organisation
Armed	I-Organisation
Forces.	I-Organisation
“We	O
all	O
benefited	O
from	O
many	O
of	O
the	O
topics	O
raised	O
,	O
in	O
addition	O
to	O
providing	O
much	O
of	O
our	O
own	O
expertise	O
in	O
military	O
medicine	O
and	O
healing	O
injuries	O
during	O
wartime.”	O

The	O
MSCE	O
underscores	O
CENTCOM	B-Organisation
's	I-Organisation
ongoing	O
efforts	O
to	O
improve	O
medical	O
capabilities	O
and	O
foster	O
relationships	O
with	O
partner	O
nations.	O
By	O
working	O
together	O
to	O
improve	O
medical	O
capabilities	O
,	O
CENTCOM	B-Organisation
continues	O
to	O
build	O
strong	O
and	O
effective	O
partnerships	O
with	O
countries	O
in	O
the	O
region	O
.	O

“Such	O
medical	O
conferences	O
are	O
essential	O
to	O
our	O
region’s	O
partnership	O
efforts	O
as	O
they	O
explore	O
collaboration	O
possibilities	O
with	O
the	O
attending	O
countries	O
and	O
come	O
together	O
with	O
a	O
global	O
health	O
plan	O
,	O
”	O
said	O
Maj.	B-Person
Gen	I-Person
Dr.	I-Person
Yasser	I-Person
Hussain	I-Person
Mandourah	I-Person
,	O
of	O
the	B-Organisation
Royal	I-Organisation
Saudi	I-Organisation
Armed	I-Organisation
Forces	I-Organisation
.	O

Operating	O
in	O
support	O
of	O
Combined	B-Organisation
Task	I-Organisation
Force	I-Organisation
(	I-Organisation
CTF	I-Organisation
)	I-Organisation
150	I-Organisation
,	O
USCGC	B-MilitaryPlatform
Glen	I-MilitaryPlatform
Harris	I-MilitaryPlatform
(	O
WPC	O
1144	O
)	O
seized	O
580	O
kilograms	O
of	O
methamphetamine	O
and	O
35	O
kilograms	O
of	O
heroin	O
from	O
a	O
vessel	O
transiting	O
international	O
waters	O
after	O
departing	O
Chah	B-Location
Bahar	I-Location
,	I-Location
Iran	I-Location
.	O

CTF	B-Organisation
150	I-Organisation
is	O
one	O
of	O
four	O
task	B-MilitaryPlatform
forces	I-MilitaryPlatform
that	O
form	O
the	O
world’s	O
largest	O
multinational	O
naval	O
partnership	O
,	O
Combined	B-Organisation
Maritime	I-Organisation
Forces.	I-Organisation
Naval	B-MilitaryPlatform
forces	I-MilitaryPlatform
supporting	O
CTF	B-Organisation
150	I-Organisation
have	O
seized	O
illegal	O
drugs	O
worth	O
a	O
combined	O
estimated	O
U.S.	O
street	O
value	O
of	O
nearly	O
$	B-Money
200	I-Money
million	I-Money
in	O
2023	B-Temporal
.	O

Glen	B-MilitaryPlatform
Harris	I-MilitaryPlatform
arrived	O
in	O
the	O
Middle	B-Location
East	I-Location
last	O
year	O
and	O
operates	O
from	O
the	B-Location
U.S.	I-Location
Navy	I-Location
base	I-Location
in	I-Location
Bahrain	I-Location
where	O
CMF	B-Organisation
is	O
headquartered	O
with	O
U.S.	B-Organisation
Naval	I-Organisation
Forces	I-Organisation
Central	I-Organisation
Command	I-Organisation
and	O
U.S.	B-Organisation
5th	I-Organisation
Fleet	I-Organisation
.	O

The	B-MilitaryPlatform
fast	I-MilitaryPlatform
response	I-MilitaryPlatform
cutter	I-MilitaryPlatform
is	O
part	O
of	O
a	O
contingent	O
of	O
U.S.	B-MilitaryPlatform
Coast	I-MilitaryPlatform
Guard	I-MilitaryPlatform
ships	I-MilitaryPlatform
forward-deployed	O
to	O
the	O
region	O
under	O
Patrol	B-Organisation
Forces	I-Organisation
Southwest	I-Organisation
Asia	I-Organisation
(	I-Organisation
PATFORSWA	I-Organisation
)	I-Organisation
.	I-Organisation
PATFORSWA	B-Organisation
deploys	O
Coast	O
Guard	O
personnel	O
and	O
ships	O
alongside	O
U.S.	O
and	O
regional	O
naval	O
forces	O
throughout	O
the	O
Middle	B-Location
East	I-Location
.	O

“The	O
dedication	O
and	O
expertise	O
of	O
Glen	B-MilitaryPlatform
Harris’s	I-MilitaryPlatform
leadership	O
and	O
crew	O
embody	O
our	O
commitment	O
to	O
interdict	O
and	O
remove	O
illicit	O
narcotics	O
from	O
the	O
sea	O
,	O
denying	O
malign	O
actors	O
the	O
ability	O
to	O
destabilize	O
the	O
region	O
,	O
”	O
said	O
Capt.	B-Person
Eric	I-Person
A.	I-Person
Helgen	I-Person
,	O
PATFORSWA’s	B-Organisation
commander.	O
“I	O
could	O
not	O
be	O
more	O
proud	O
of	O
our	O
fast	B-MilitaryPlatform
response	I-MilitaryPlatform
cutter	I-MilitaryPlatform
crews.”	O

Currently	O
led	O
by	O
the	O
United	B-Location
Kingdom	I-Location
,	O
CTF	B-Organisation
150	I-Organisation
conducts	O
maritime	O
security	O
and	O
counter-terrorism	O
operations	O
in	O
the	O
Gulf	B-Location
of	I-Location
Oman	I-Location
and	O
Indian	B-Location
Ocean	I-Location
to	O
disrupt	O
criminal	O
and	O
terrorist	O
organizations	O
and	O
their	O
related	O
illicit	O
activities	O
,	O
including	O
the	O
movement	O
of	O
personnel	O
,	O
weapons	O
,	O
narcotics	O
and	O
charcoal.	O
These	O
efforts	O
help	O
ensure	O
legitimate	O
commercial	O
shipping	O
transits	O
the	O
region	O
free	O
from	O
non-state	O
threats	O
.	O

U.S.	O
and	O
international	O
naval	B-MilitaryPlatform
units	I-MilitaryPlatform
in	O
the	O
Middle	B-Location
East	I-Location
seized	O
illegal	O
drugs	O
totaling	O
$	B-Money
1	I-Money
billion	I-Money
in	O
value	O
from	O
2021	B-Temporal
to	O
2022	B-Temporal
.	O

U.S.	B-Organisation
Naval	I-Organisation
Forces	I-Organisation
Central	I-Organisation
Command	I-Organisation
(	I-Organisation
NAVCENT	I-Organisation
)	I-Organisation
welcomed	O
Oman’s	B-Location
top	O
naval	O
commander	O
to	O
the	O
U.S.	B-Location
Navy	I-Location
base	I-Location
in	I-Location
Bahrain	I-Location
,	O
May	B-Temporal
7	I-Temporal
,	O
coinciding	O
with	O
the	O
start	O
of	O
an	O
Oman-led	B-Location
maritime	O
exercise	O
in	O
the	O
Gulf	B-Location
of	I-Location
Oman	I-Location
.	O

“Oman	B-Location
is	O
an	O
important	O
regional	O
maritime	O
partner	O
and	O
it	O
was	O
a	O
pleasure	O
hosting	O
discussions	O
on	O
our	O
shared	O
vision	O
for	O
advancing	O
cooperation	O
among	O
our	O
forces	O
at	O
sea	O
,	O
”	O
said	O
Cooper.	B-Person
“We	O
look	O
forward	O
to	O
strengthening	O
our	O
collaboration	O
in	O
the	O
days	O
ahead.”	O

The	O
visit	O
to	O
Bahrain	B-Location
fell	O
on	O
the	O
first	O
day	O
of	O
an	O
annual	O
Oman-led	B-Location
naval	O
exercise	O
called	O
Khunjar	O
Hadd	O
,	O
in	O
and	O
off	O
the	O
coast	O
of	O
Oman.	B-Location
This	O
year	O
,	O
mine	O
countermeasures	O
ship	O
USS	B-MilitaryPlatform
Dextrous	I-MilitaryPlatform
(	I-MilitaryPlatform
MCM	I-MilitaryPlatform
13	I-MilitaryPlatform
)	I-MilitaryPlatform
,	I-MilitaryPlatform
personnel	O
from	O
a	O
U.S.	B-Organisation
5th	I-Organisation
Fleet	I-Organisation
expeditionary	O
mine	O
countermeasures	O
unit	O
and	O
a	O
U.S.	B-MilitaryPlatform
Navy	I-MilitaryPlatform
P-8A	I-MilitaryPlatform
Poseidon	I-MilitaryPlatform
maritime	O
patrol	O
aircraft	O
are	O
slated	O
to	O
participate	O
.	O

In	O
addition	O
to	O
the	O
Oman	B-Location
and	O
the	O
United	B-Location
States	I-Location
,	O
the	O
weeklong	O
exercise	O
will	O
include	O
forces	O
from	O
France	B-Location
,	O
Japan	B-Location
and	O
the	O
United	B-Location
Kingdom.	I-Location
Training	O
will	O
focus	O
on	O
mine	O
countermeasures	O
,	O
explosive	O
ordnance	O
disposal	O
,	O
maritime	O
interdiction	O
and	O
other	O
combined	O
naval	O
operations	O

While	O
at	O
the	O
U.S.	B-Location
Navy	I-Location
base	I-Location
in	I-Location
Bahrain	I-Location
,	O
senior	O
Omani	O
officials	O
met	O
with	O
leaders	O
from	O
U.S.	B-Organisation
5th	I-Organisation
Fleet	I-Organisation
,	O
Combined	B-Organisation
Maritimes	I-Organisation
Forces	I-Organisation
and	O
the	O
International	B-Organisation
Maritime	I-Organisation
Security	I-Organisation
Construct.	I-Organisation
They	O
also	O
received	O
briefings	O
and	O
toured	O
facilities	O
showcasing	O
unmanned	O
systems	O
the	O
U.S.	B-Organisation
Navy	I-Organisation
has	O
integrated	O
into	O
regional	O
maritime	O
operations	O
.	O

On	O
May	B-Temporal
3	I-Temporal
,	O
Lt.	B-Person
Gen.	I-Person
Alexus	I-Person
Grynkewich	I-Person
,	O
9th	B-Organisation
Air	I-Organisation
Force	I-Organisation
(	O
Air	O
Forces	O
Central	O
)	O
commander	O
,	O
conducted	O
an	O
immersion	O
with	O
the	O
380th	O
Air	O
Expeditionary	O
Wing	O
at	O
Al	B-Location
Dhafra	I-Location
Air	I-Location
Base	I-Location
,	I-Location
United	I-Location
Arab	I-Location
Emirates	I-Location
.	O

Grynkewich	B-Person
met	O
with	O
Airmen	B-MilitaryPlatform
and	O
Marines	B-MilitaryPlatform
from	O
across	O
the	O
base	O
to	O
discuss	O
regional	O
threats	O
,	O
watch	O
operations	O
unfold	O
at	O
the	O
tactical	O
level	O
and	O
enhance	O
his	O
understanding	O
of	O
the	O
opportunities	O
and	O
challenges	O
facing	O
380th	B-Organisation
AEW	I-Organisation
members	I-Organisation
.	O

Grynkewich	B-MilitaryPlatform
also	O
had	O
the	O
opportunity	O
to	O
tour	O
the	O
beddown	O
location	O
of	O
the	O
A-10	B-MilitaryPlatform
Thunderbolt	I-MilitaryPlatform
IIs	I-MilitaryPlatform
that	O
recently	O
arrived	O
in	O
theater	O
and	O
engage	O
with	O
75th	O
Expeditionary	O
Fighter	O
Squadron	O
pilots	O
and	O
maintainers	O
.	O

“I	O
look	O
forward	O
to	O
seeing	O
how	O
our	O
A-10	O
experts	O
adjust	O
their	O
tactics	O
and	O
operations	O
to	O
employ	O
this	O
capability	O
,	O
”	O
said	O
Grynkewich.	B-MilitaryPlatform
“Deployments	O
like	O
this	O
provide	O
valuable	O
experience	O
to	O
our	O
pilots	O
,	O
maintainers	O
and	O
weapons	O
teams.	O
It’s	O
experience	O
like	O
this	O
they’ll	O
need	O
in	O
the	O
future	O
as	O
they	O
transition	O
to	O
new	O
platforms	O
capable	O
of	O
flying	O
in	O
all	O
operational	O
environments.	O
In	O
the	O
meantime	O
,	O
we	O
have	O
a	O
responsibility	O
to	O
the	O
taxpayer	O
,	O
while	O
the	O
A-10	B-MilitaryPlatform
is	O
still	O
flying	O
,	O
to	O
wring	O
from	O
it	O
every	O
possible	O
ounce	O
of	O
combat	O
capability.	O
The	O
75th	B-MilitaryPlatform
EFS	I-MilitaryPlatform
is	O
well	O
on	O
the	O
way	O
to	O
showing	O
us	O
how	O
that	O
can	O
be	O
done	O
here	O
in	O
USCENTCOM.”	B-Organisation

As	O
the	O
service	O
modernizes	O
its	O
fighter	O
fleet	O
,	O
the	O
first	O
of	O
21	O
A-10s	B-MilitaryPlatform
in	O
the	O
Air	O
Force’s	O
fleet	O
arrived	O
at	O
the	B-Location
Boneyard	I-Location
last	O
month	O
.	O

“With	O
the	O
380th	B-Organisation
AEW	I-Organisation
team	I-Organisation
preparing	O
the	O
A-10	B-MilitaryPlatform
to	O
carry	O
small	O
diameter	O
bombs	O
in	O
combat	O
,	O
we	O
are	O
eager	O
to	O
leverage	O
the	O
capability	O
this	O
brings	O
to	O
the	O
U.S.	B-Organisation
Central	I-Organisation
Command	I-Organisation
area	O
of	O
responsibility	O
,	O
”	O
added	O
Grynkewich	B-Person
.	O

The	O
A-10’s	B-MilitaryPlatform
ability	O
to	O
carry	O
SDBs	B-Weapon
will	O
increase	O
the	O
platform’s	O
stand-off	O
range	O
;	O
whereas	O
previous	O
munitions	O
could	O
be	O
employed	O
only	O
within	O
ranges	O
in	O
single-digit	O
nautical	B-MilitaryPlatform
miles	I-MilitaryPlatform
,	O
SDBs	B-Weapon
can	O
travel	O
dozens	O
prior	O
to	O
detonation	O
.	O

Manama	B-Location
,	I-Location
Bahrain	I-Location
–	O
Late	O
last	O
week	O
Naval	B-Location
Amphibious	I-Location
Task	I-Location
Force	I-Location
51	I-Location
/	I-Location
5th	I-Location
Marine	O
Expeditionary	O
Bridge	O
(	O
TF	O
51	O
/	O
5	O
)	O
Joint	O
Terminal	O
Attack	O
Controllers	O
(	O
JTAC	O
)	O
embarked	O
on	O
Bahrain-based	B-Location
U.S.	B-MilitaryPlatform
Coast	I-MilitaryPlatform
Guard	I-MilitaryPlatform
fast-response	I-MilitaryPlatform
cutters	I-MilitaryPlatform
to	O
conduct	O
joint	O
training	O
with	O
both	O
U.S.	B-Organisation
Navy	I-Organisation
and	O
U.S.	B-Organisation
Air	I-Organisation
Force	I-Organisation
aircraft	O
in	O
the	O
Northern	B-Location
Arabian	I-Location
Gulf.	I-Location
The	O
training	O
involved	O
five	O
U.S.	B-Organisation
Coast	I-Organisation
Guard	I-Organisation
vessels	O
and	O
a	O
group	O
of	O
Marine	O
JTACs	O
who	O
sharpened	O
their	O
tactical	O
skills	O
by	O
controlling	O
U.S.	B-Organisation
Air	I-Organisation
Force	I-Organisation
A-10	B-MilitaryPlatform
Thunderbolt	I-MilitaryPlatform
II	I-MilitaryPlatform
and	O
U.S.	B-MilitaryPlatform
Navy	I-MilitaryPlatform
P-8	I-MilitaryPlatform
Poseidon	I-MilitaryPlatform
aircraft	I-MilitaryPlatform
.	O

“This	O
was	O
an	O
excellent	O
opportunity	O
for	O
all	O
five	O
crews	O
to	O
be	O
shown	O
the	O
potential	O
of	O
joint	O
maritime	O
and	O
air	O
operations”	O
said	O
U.S.	B-Organisation
Coast	I-Organisation
Guard	I-Organisation
LT	B-Person
Sehng	I-Person
Hwang	I-Person
,	O
Commanding	O
Officer	O
of	O
U.S.	B-Organisation
Coast	I-Organisation
Guard	I-Organisation
Cutter	B-Person
Clarence	I-Person
Sutphin	I-Person
,	I-Person
Jr.	I-Person
“It	O
really	O
allowed	O
us	O
all	O
to	O
see	O
the	O
specific	O
lethal	O
capability	O
that	O
something	O
like	O
the	O
A-10	B-MilitaryPlatform
has	O
,	O
in	O
tandem	O
with	O
capable	O
and	O
competent	O
Marines	B-MilitaryPlatform
and	O
Sailors	O
when	O
deployed	O
to	O
the	O
region”	O
.	O

In	O
addition	O
to	O
its	O
steady-state	O
mission	O
of	O
maintaining	O
readiness	O
as	O
a	O
crisis-response	O
task	B-MilitaryPlatform
force	I-MilitaryPlatform
,	O
Task	B-Organisation
Force	I-Organisation
51	I-Organisation
/	I-Organisation
5	I-Organisation
advances	O
naval	O
integration	O
in	O
support	O
of	O
the	O
Tri-Service	O
Maritime	O
Strategy.	O
Published	O
jointly	O
in	O
2020	B-Temporal
by	O
the	O
Commandant	O
of	O
the	O
Marine	O
Corps	O
,	O
Chief	O
of	O
Naval	O
Operations	O
,	O
and	O
Commandant	O
of	O
the	O
Coast	O
Guard	O
,	O
the	O
Tri-Service	O
Maritime	O
Strategy	O
outlines	O
an	O
integrated	O
U.S.	B-Organisation
Marine	I-Organisation
Corps	I-Organisation
,	O
U.S.	B-Organisation
Navy	I-Organisation
,	O
U.S.	B-Organisation
Coast	I-Organisation
Guard	I-Organisation
approach	O
towards	O
supporting	O
Department	B-Organisation
of	I-Organisation
Defense	I-Organisation
maritime	O
prerogatives	O
.	O

“Joint	O
training	O
like	O
this	O
only	O
delivers	O
greater	O
flexibility	O
and	O
options	O
for	O
crisis	O
response	O
in	O
this	O
theater”	O
said	O
Brig.	B-Person
Gen.	I-Person
Matthew	I-Person
Reid	I-Person
,	O
TF	B-Organisation
51	I-Organisation
/	I-Organisation
5’s	I-Organisation
Commanding	O
General.	O
“As	O
Marines	B-MilitaryPlatform
,	O
we	O
are	O
always	O
looking	O
for	O
ways	O
to	O
support	O
joint	O
maritime	O
efforts	O
and	O
,	O
in	O
this	O
case	O
,	O
we	O
were	O
able	O
to	O
take	O
things	O
a	O
step	O
further	O
by	O
working	O
with	O
our	O
Air	B-Organisation
Force	I-Organisation
partners.	O
Altogether	O
,	O
this	O
helps	O
the	O
Marine	B-Organisation
Corps	I-Organisation
better	O
support	O
regional	O
security	O
and	O
demonstrates	O
that	O
we’re	O
able	O
to	O
work	O
together	O
with	O
joint	O
partners	O
to	O
deter	O
external	O
threats”	O
.	O

The	O
training	O
culminated	O
on	O
Friday	O
with	O
a	O
live	O
fire	O
attack	O
by	O
U.S.	B-Organisation
Air	I-Organisation
Force	I-Organisation
A-10s	B-MilitaryPlatform
onto	O
sea	O
targets	O
,	O
in	O
conjunction	O
with	O
high-value	O
target	O
seizure	O
,	O
fast	O
intruder	O
attack	O
craft	O
,	O
and	O
visit	O
,	O
board	O
search	O
and	O
seizure	O
(	O
VBSS	O
)	O
exercises	O
conducted	O
by	O
embarked	O
U.S.	B-Organisation
Coast	I-Organisation
Guard	I-Organisation
and	O
Navy	B-Organisation
forces	I-Organisation
.	O

TF	B-Organisation
51	I-Organisation
/	I-Organisation
5	I-Organisation
is	O
a	O
Bahrain-based	B-Location
Joint	O
Task	O
Force-Capable	O
(	O
JTF-C	O
)	O
Headquarters	O
that	O
responds	O
to	O
crises	O
and	O
contingencies	O
;	O
coordinates	O
,	O
plans	O
,	O
and	O
executes	O
operations	O
;	O
conducts	O
theater	O
security	O
cooperation	O
;	O
and	O
advances	O
emerging	O
Naval	O
concepts	O
at	O
sea	O
,	O
from	O
the	O
sea	O
,	O
and	O
ashore	O
in	O
support	O
of	O
U.S.	B-Organisation
Central	I-Organisation
Command	I-Organisation
,	O
Fifth	B-Organisation
Fleet	I-Organisation
and	O
Marine	B-Organisation
Forces	I-Organisation
Central	I-Organisation
Command	I-Organisation
theater	O
objectives	O
.	O

On	O
May	B-Temporal
3	I-Temporal
at	O
approximately	O
6:20	O
a.m.	O
local	O
time	O
,	O
Panama-flagged	B-Location
oil	O
tanker	O
Niovi	O
was	O
seized	O
by	O
Iran’s	B-Location
Islamic	B-Organisation
Revolutionary	I-Organisation
Guard	I-Organisation
Corps	I-Organisation
Navy	I-Organisation
(	O
IRGCN	O
)	O
while	O
transiting	O
the	O
Strait	B-Location
of	I-Location
Hormuz	I-Location
.	O

The	O
oil	O
tanker	O
departed	O
Dubai	B-Location
and	O
was	O
transiting	O
from	O
the	O
Arabian	B-Location
Gulf	I-Location
toward	O
the	O
port	O
of	O
Fujairah	B-Location
in	O
the	O
United	B-Location
Arab	I-Location
Emirates	I-Location
when	O
a	O
dozen	O
IRGCN	B-Organisation
fast-attack	O
craft	O
swarmed	O
the	O
vessel	O
in	O
the	O
middle	O
of	O
the	O
strait.	O
The	O
IRGCN	B-Organisation
subsequently	O
forced	O
the	O
oil	O
tanker	O
to	O
reverse	O
course	O
and	O
head	O
toward	O
Iranian	O
territorial	O
waters	O
off	O
the	B-Location
coast	I-Location
of	I-Location
Bandar	I-Location
‘Abbas	I-Location
,	I-Location
Iran	I-Location
.	O

A	O
previous	O
incident	O
occurred	O
six	O
days	O
ago	O
when	O
the	O
Islamic	B-Organisation
Republic	I-Organisation
of	I-Organisation
Iran	I-Organisation
Navy	I-Organisation
seized	O
Marshall	O
Islands-flagged	O
oil	O
tanker	O
Advantage	O
Sweet	O
while	O
it	O
transited	O
international	O
waters	O
in	O
the	O
Gulf	B-Location
of	I-Location
Oman	I-Location
.	O

Iran’s	B-Location
actions	O
are	O
contrary	O
to	O
international	O
law	O
and	O
disruptive	O
to	O
regional	O
security	O
and	O
stability.	O
Over	O
the	O
past	O
two	O
years	O
,	O
Iran	B-Location
has	O
harassed	O
,	O
attacked	O
or	O
interfered	O
with	O
the	O
navigational	O
rights	O
of	O
15	O
internationally	O
flagged	O
merchant	O
vessels	O
.	O

Iran’s	B-Location
continued	O
harassment	O
of	O
vessels	O
and	O
interference	O
with	O
navigational	O
rights	O
in	O
regional	O
waters	O
are	O
unwarranted	O
,	O
irresponsible	O
and	O
a	O
present	O
threat	O
to	O
maritime	O
security	O
and	O
the	O
global	O
economy	O
.	O

U.S.	B-Organisation
5th	I-Organisation
Fleet	I-Organisation
hosted	O
Qatar’s	B-Location
top	O
naval	O
leader	O
May	B-Temporal
2	I-Temporal
at	O
the	O
U.S.	B-Location
Navy	I-Location
base	I-Location
in	I-Location
Bahrain	I-Location
,	O
marking	O
strengthening	O
ties	O
between	O
U.S.	O
and	O
Qatari	B-Organisation
maritime	I-Organisation
forces	I-Organisation
.	O

Vice	B-Person
Adm.	I-Person
Brad	I-Person
Cooper	I-Person
,	O
commander	O
of	O
U.S.	B-Organisation
Naval	I-Organisation
Central	I-Organisation
Forces	I-Organisation
Command	I-Organisation
,	O
U.S.	B-Organisation
5th	I-Organisation
Fleet	I-Organisation
and	O
Combined	B-Organisation
Maritime	I-Organisation
Forces	I-Organisation
(	I-Organisation
CMF	I-Organisation
)	I-Organisation
,	I-Organisation
welcomed	O
Commander	O
of	O
the	O
Qatari	B-Organisation
Emiri	I-Organisation
Navy	I-Organisation
Maj.	B-Person
Gen.	I-Person
Abdullah	I-Person
Hassan	I-Person
Al-Sulaiti	I-Person
and	O
other	O
senior	O
Qatari	O
officers	O
for	O
discussions	O
on	O
regional	O
maritime	O
security	O
cooperation	O
.	O

“We	O
were	O
deeply	O
grateful	O
for	O
this	O
opportunity	O
to	O
host	O
our	O
Qatari	O
partners	O
at	O
U.S.	B-Location
5th	I-Location
Fleet	I-Location
headquarters	I-Location
here	O
in	O
Bahrain	B-Location
,	O
”	O
said	O
Cooper.	B-Person
“Strengthening	O
and	O
expanding	O
maritime	O
collaboration	O
with	O
the	O
Qatari	B-Organisation
Emiri	I-Organisation
Navy	I-Organisation
is	O
essential	O
for	O
regional	O
security	O
and	O
stability.”	O

Qatar	B-Location
is	O
one	O
of	O
38	O
nations	O
that	O
make	O
up	O
CMF	B-Organisation
,	O
the	O
world’s	O
largest	O
multinational	O
naval	O
partnership.	O
The	O
organization	O
is	O
co-located	O
at	O
U.S.	B-Location
5th	I-Location
Fleet	I-Location
headquarters	I-Location
.	O

During	O
the	O
visit	O
,	O
the	O
senior	O
Qatari	O
military	O
officials	O
met	O
with	O
U.S.	B-Organisation
5th	I-Organisation
Fleet	I-Organisation
staff	O
and	O
attended	O
a	O
briefing	O
on	O
new	O
unmanned	O
systems	O
the	O
U.S.	B-Organisation
Navy	I-Organisation
has	O
recently	O
integrated	O
into	O
regional	O
operations	O
.	O

The	O
meeting	O
in	O
Bahrain	B-Location
came	O
on	O
the	O
heels	O
of	O
Cooper’s	B-Person
daylong	O
trip	O
to	O
Qatar	B-Location
where	O
he	O
met	O
with	O
Qatar	B-Organisation
Armed	I-Organisation
Forces	I-Organisation
Chief	B-Person
of	I-Person
Staff	I-Person
Lt.	I-Person
Gen.	I-Person
(	I-Person
Pilot	I-Person
)	I-Person
Salem	I-Person
bin	I-Person
Hamad	I-Person
bin	I-Person
Aqeel	I-Person
al-Nabit	I-Person
near	O
Doha	B-Location
.	O

RICHMOND	B-Location
,	I-Location
Va.	I-Location
–	O
The	B-Organisation
Virginia	I-Organisation
National	I-Organisation
Guard	I-Organisation
began	O
recognizing	O
its	O
20th	O
year	O
of	O
partnership	O
with	O
the	O
Republic	O
of	O
Tajikistan	B-Location
March	B-Temporal
27	I-Temporal
,	I-Temporal
2023	I-Temporal
,	O
as	O
VNG	O
senior	O
leaders	O
visited	O
with	O
the	O
Tajikistan	B-Location
Ministry	I-Location
of	I-Location
Defense	I-Location
in	O
Dushanbe	B-Location
,	I-Location
Tajikistan	I-Location
.	O

During	O
the	O
visit	O
,	O
the	O
VNG	O
team	O
,	O
led	O
by	O
Brig.	B-Person
Gen.	I-Person
James	I-Person
W.	I-Person
Ring	I-Person
,	O
the	O
VNG	O
Director	O
of	O
the	O
Joint	O
Staff	O
,	O
participated	O
in	O
bilateral	O
talks	O
on	O
military	O
to	O
military	O
engagements.	O
The	B-Organisation
Ministry	I-Organisation
of	I-Organisation
Defense	I-Organisation
also	O
hosted	O
a	O
20th	O
anniversary	O
celebration	O
,	O
commemorating	O
two	O
decades	O
of	O
partnership	O
supporting	O
the	O
State	O
Partnership	O
Program	O
.	O

"	O
The	B-Organisation
Virginia	I-Organisation
National	I-Organisation
Guard	I-Organisation
has	O
enjoyed	O
great	O
camaraderie	O
with	O
military	O
forces	O
of	O
Tajikistan	B-Location
over	O
the	O
two	O
decades	O
of	O
our	O
partnership	O
,	O
and	O
through	O
various	O
military	O
exchanges	O
have	O
helped	O
promote	O
regional	O
and	O
global	O
security	O
and	O
prosperity	O
,	O
"	O
said	O
Maj.	B-Person
Gen.	I-Person
Timothy	I-Person
P.	I-Person
Williams	I-Person
,	O
the	O
Adjutant	O
General	O
of	O
Virginia.	B-Location
"	O
We	O
have	O
dramatically	O
increased	O
the	O
pace	O
of	O
our	O
exchanges	O
,	O
and	O
we	O
look	O
forward	O
to	O
further	O
growing	O
the	O
partnership	O
to	O
help	O
build	O
the	O
capability	O
and	O
capacity	O
of	O
the	O
Tajikistan	B-Organisation
military	I-Organisation
force	I-Organisation
.	O
"	O

"	O
The	B-Organisation
Virginia	I-Organisation
National	I-Organisation
Guard	I-Organisation
values	O
the	O
continued	O
partnership	O
with	O
Tajikistan	B-Location
in	O
support	O
of	O
our	O
shared	O
security	O
cooperation	O
objectives	O
,	O
”	O
said	O
Ring.	B-Person
“Each	O
partnership	O
exchange	O
between	O
the	O
Virginia	B-Organisation
National	I-Organisation
Guard	I-Organisation
and	O
the	O
Tajikistan	B-Organisation
military	I-Organisation
forces	I-Organisation
supports	O
our	O
nation’s	O
mutual	O
interest	O
in	O
peace	O
and	O
regional	O
stability.”	O

During	O
the	O
visit	O
to	O
Tajikistan	B-Location
,	O
Tajik	O
leaders	O
expressed	O
their	O
gratitude	O
for	O
the	O
partnership	O
,	O
according	O
to	O
Maj.	B-Person
Isaac	I-Person
Rivera	I-Person
,	O
the	O
State	O
Partnership	O
Program	O
director	O
.	O

“Col.	B-Person
Husein	I-Person
Shokirzoda	I-Person
,	O
Commander	O
of	O
Tajikistan	B-Organisation
Mobile	I-Organisation
Forces	I-Organisation
,	O
was	O
grateful	O
for	O
all	O
the	O
training	O
that	O
the	O
Virginia	B-Organisation
National	I-Organisation
Guard	I-Organisation
has	O
provide	O
to	O
his	O
forces	O
over	O
the	O
past	O
years	O
,	O
”	O
said	O
Rivera	B-Person
.	O

The	B-Organisation
VNG	I-Organisation
and	O
Tajikistan	B-Location
began	O
their	O
formal	O
partnership	O
in	O
July	B-Temporal
2003.	I-Temporal
The	O
relationship	O
has	O
benefitted	O
from	O
sharing	O
subject	O
matter	O
expertise	O
during	O
over	O
200	O
military-to-military	O
engagements	O
that	O
help	O
counter	O
terrorism	O
,	O
deter	O
violent	O
extremism	O
,	O
expand	O
emergency	O
response	O
capabilities	O
,	O
develop	O
professionalism	O
among	O
leaders	O
and	O
staffs	O
and	O
promote	O
shared	O
values	O
in	O
national	O
sovereignty	O
and	O
security	O
.	O

The	O
two	O
organizations	O
have	O
made	O
vital	O
contributions	O
to	O
regional	O
stability	O
and	O
security	O
across	O
Central	B-Location
and	I-Location
South	I-Location
Asia	I-Location
,	O
executing	O
bi-lateral	O
and	O
multi-lateral	O
engagements	O
with	O
international	O
partners	O
;	O
enhancing	O
multinational	O
understanding	O
and	O
shared	O
values	O
of	O
peace	O
,	O
national	O
sovereignty	O
and	O
global	O
security	O
.	O

Most	O
recently	O
,	O
a	B-MilitaryPlatform
team	I-MilitaryPlatform
of	I-MilitaryPlatform
four	I-MilitaryPlatform
Tajik	I-MilitaryPlatform
officers	I-MilitaryPlatform
traveled	O
to	O
Fort	B-Location
Barfoot	I-Location
where	O
they	O
conducted	O
an	O
Officer	O
Professional	O
Development	O
hosted	O
by	O
the	B-Organisation
Fort	I-Organisation
Barfoot-based	I-Organisation
183rd	I-Organisation
Regiment	I-Organisation
,	O
Regional	B-Organisation
Training	I-Organisation
Institute	I-Organisation
,	O
focused	O
on	O
weapons	O
qualification	O
.	O

“It	O
went	O
great	O
,	O
we	O
really	O
liked	O
it	O
,	O
”	O
said	O
Tajikistan	B-Person
Capt.	I-Person
Jaloliddin	I-Person
Qurbonzoda	I-Person
through	O
a	O
translator.	O
“The	O
instructors	O
are	O
great	O
,	O
we	O
can	O
tell	O
they’re	O
very	O
experienced.	O
We	O
really	O
liked	O
shooting	O
the	O
weapons	O
and	O
clearing	O
buildings	O
,	O
it	O
was	O
a	O
lot	O
of	O
fun.	O
Zeroing	O
the	O
weapons	O
was	O
very	O
important	O
and	O
what	O
we	O
were	O
looking	O
for.”	O

At	O
the	O
conclusion	O
of	O
the	O
training	O
,	O
Ring	B-Person
presented	O
certificates	O
to	O
the	O
four	O
Tajik	O
officers	O
and	O
their	O
translator	O
,	O
marking	O
their	O
successful	O
completion	O
of	O
the	O
program	O
.	O

“I	O
want	O
to	O
thank	O
each	O
you	O
individually	O
for	O
your	O
service	O
to	O
your	O
country	O
,	O
”	O
said	O
Ring.	B-Person
“We	O
recognize	O
that	O
freedom	O
does	O
not	O
come	O
free.	O
It	O
is	O
the	O
direct	O
result	O
of	O
citizens	O
such	O
as	O
you	O
who	O
stand	O
for	O
the	O
freedom	O
of	O
your	O
people.	O
We’re	O
glad	O
,	O
as	O
the	B-Organisation
Virginia	I-Organisation
National	I-Organisation
Guard	I-Organisation
,	O
to	O
be	O
part	O
of	O
that	O
for	O
Tajikistan.”	B-Location

Read	O
more	O
about	O
the	O
State	O
Partnership	O
Program	O
and	O
the	O
VNG’s	B-Organisation
relationship	O
with	O
the	O
Republic	B-Location
of	I-Location
Tajikistan	I-Location
.	O

